So here is where we left in the last module.
We finished our Angular 2 front end,
or most parts of it.
We're able to create messages here.
We're also able to click Edit,
though we only edit them in a static way.
And we can delete them.
But all of that is happening in the front end.
We're not really connecting to a server.
And this is the reason why if we create a message here
and we reload, the message is gone,
because it isn't saved anywhere.
Also, we get the authentication route here,
but even though we're able to fill out this form,
we're not really able to save the user on the back end,
or well, really create a user on our server.
So these are the two missing things in this application.
And these are the things which really make this
a course about Angular 2 and NodeJS,
because until now, we really only had to look at
the Angular 2 part here.
Now it's time to make the next step
and also implement our back end with NodeJS.
We already set up our back end basics in the NodeJS
and the MongoDB sections in this course, though.
We already have our models,
and we got our app.js file, which controls our request flow,
and we got our app.js file here in the routes folder,
which renders our root route, this index page here,
which starts our Angular 2 application.
Now it's time to add more routes to allow Angular 2
to reach out to our back end and then do something there.
Remember this slide from the very beginning?
It shows how we connect Angular 2 and NodeJS.
We get our Angular 2 application and then we reach out
to the server whenever we need something.
We request data, that could also be that we request
to store some data, but in the end we reach out
to the server because we want something to happen.
And then on the server, it's NodeJS and ExpressJS
and MongoDB's job to do something with the data
we sent there, or give us the data we're requesting,
but in the end, to send us back a response
and tell if the action was successful
and possibly the data we wanted.
So this separation is key to understand,
because that is what we're going to work on now.
We're going to work on this server part
and set up some routes to which Angular 2 can connect
so that Angular 2 knows how to, well, get data,
store data, and so on.
Let's start with the route for saving messages.