So, I want to start by adding
a route to which Angular 2 can connect,
which allows me to send a message I create
in my frontend, in my Angular 2 application,
to the server and store it in my Mongo database.
Now, for the rest of this course,
I'll create two new files in this
routes folder here, so on my backend.
A messages.js, which should hold all my
message-related routes, and a user.js route,
which I'll use later on once I add user-related routes.
Because I want to keep my app.js route here,
my app.js route's file here, clean,
I only want to render my root route here,
the one which loads the Angular 2 application.
In my messages.js file, I want to have all
message-related routes, to which Angular 2 can reach out.
And in the user-related file, I'll respectively have all my
user-related routes, to which Angular 2 can reach out.
So, in the messages.js file, I, of course,
want to use express, so I will require this
because I want to set up the express router,
just like I'm using it here in the app.js file.
You may actually make it quicker or use a shortcut here
and simply copy and paste all of that here.
Though, I will override this route,
or I will change this route here.
We also need to have access to our messaging model,
because I want to interact with it.
Remember? In this file, I want to store messages.
I will use mongoose or my mongoose models to do that.
Therefore, I need to import message from
models/message without the file extension.
Now, that's my messages routes file.
Though, the function here is route,
we'll get a well written.
Before doing that, I'll do something else, though,
in the app.js file in the root folder.
So, the file which handles all our requests.
I currently only reference my
appRoutes file, this one here.
Now, I'm going to duplicate this
and also create my messageRoutes,
just duplicate it once, though,
and import my message.js file,
which, remember this? Exports the router here.
So, I'm importing this router,
and down here were I use the routes,
I want to use the messageRoutes.
And now, this is important.
First, I want to use them whenever the user
navigates to a URL which contains
or which starts with /message,
so all the message-related routes
should have /message in the URL path.
The second important thing is the order here.
My messageRoutes need to come first.
Because, if I would have this order, then every request
would first be handled by the appRoutes.
But I don't want to do that.
I don't want to handle every request with that.
I want to handle requests which have /message
with the messageRoutes first, so with the routes
I set up in this messages.js folder.
So this is important that I have the more specific
routes first so that I can handle them before
more generic routes try to handle them.
With that, I can then head over to the messages.js file
to this route, and I will change it to a post route,
because I want to store messages on the server.
I don't want to get my messages with this function.
Here, I simply want to be able to store them.
To send them from the Angular 2
and store them in my backend.
Therefore, this will be a post request which gets sent.
Now, the pov will just be '/'
and the important thing to recognise here is,
in the end, of course, it is messages or message/
because I'm only getting to this file
if my request has /message as a URL,
or /message in front of or at the beginning of the URL.
This is when I reach the messages.js file
in the routes folder, so every route I set up here
invisibly has message in front of the pov here.
So, this is the /message post route therefore.
And then here, of course, I don't
want to render the index page.
Instead, here I want to save a message.
So let's first create a new one using
the mongoose model we created before.
So, a new message here.
And, as you learned in the MongoDB section,
we pass JavaScript object to this message object,
to this message model.
Here, we want to set up the message we want to store.
Now, let's have a look at the message model.
We're expecting the content and the user.
Now, I'll take care about the user in the
next section when we actually create users
and are able to work with them.
For now, all I wanna do here is
I want to store the content.
Now, how do I get the content I wanna store there?
I simply assume that my request will send me
the content in the body of the request.
So I can extract it from the request body,
this is normal express.js code to
access the body attached to a request.
And then the content field.
And of course, it will be my job to populate
this content field in the frontend in my Angular 2 code
when I send this request to the backend.
But it's an assumption I make here on the backend.
This kind of is the interface frontend
and backend are communicating with.
Now, what this message created,
I can take my message here and save it.
Now, in here, I wanna provide a callback
to check if we got an error
or the result of this operation.
And first, I'll have a look if error is not null,
so if we do have an error.
In this case, I want to return a response
with a status code of 500 for a server error.
And some json, which allows me to
handle this error on the frontend.
So this will send a JavaScript
object then convert it to json.
And here I simply wanna set up, let's say
a title for this error, 'An error occurred,'
and then the error itself.
I can simply set the error object here,
stored in the error variable the mongoose
package creates for me in case of an error.
This error object here happens to have a message field,
which I later on can access like this.
This will come in useful in the
error-handling section, of course.
So, this is handling the error case
and sending the error to the frontend.
And the other case, of course, is that we're successful.
In this case, so if the error is null,
we will reach this code, where
I also want to send a response.
I don't need the return keyword here, though,
because I'm not executing any code after this line.
And here, I want to set the status code to 201
for everything is okay and your resource was created,
and then send some json, too.
Now, here in the JavaScript object,
I'll send a message.
It's, of course, totally up to you
what you want to send here.
So here I'm just sending a message, 'Saved message,'
so the message the frontend sent me.
And then, the object will be the result,
which actually is the saved message,
as it now lives in the database.
So this will contain the ID and so on.
So, this is my response. And again,
just to highlight this, why don't I put
return in front of this statement?
I'm using it up here in the error
if statement, at least in the end.
Well, the reason I'm using it here is
if error is not null, we're getting
inside of this if block here.
In which case, if I don't have return, we send a response.
But then, we still execute this code.
Now, I could, of course, put that in an else block
and therefore prevent this from happening,
but if I don't want to write an else block,
I would execute this code.
So, I'm setting return here to
let the programme know that, in this case,
I not only want to send a response,
but I also want to return from this function.
So this code then doesn't get executed.
This is the reason why I don't use return here.
There is simply no code which would get executed after it.
The function here ends directly after this response here.
So with this, I'm handling error and success case,
and I set this up to now be able
to store messages in my database.
Now, of course, the important question is,
how do we get the messages from our Angular 2 frontend to
this route to this function here which then saves them?