How do we use HTTP in Angular 2?
Because we now need to use it.
We want to send data the user entered
in our Angular 2 application to the back end
to this route we just created.
Normally, we have this request response
workflow here, between server and client.
The client sends a request to the server,
and the server responds.
But how do we do this with Angular 2?
Remember, we only get one page which we render,
and then, Angular 2 handles the complete webpage.
Well, it turns out, Angular 2 is still able
to send requests behind the scenes.
So, it doesn't re-render the page,
but it is still able to send Ajax requests,
so, requests which are then handled
in the background by Angular 2 once we get a response.
Such a request is sent with a concept
or a object named Observables.
Angular 2 uses these Observables,
and Observables are basically objects
coming from a third-party library
which allow us to handle asynchronous tasks.
And such a HTTP request is an asynchronous task,
because we send it now, but we get back
the response in a couple of milliseconds or seconds.
So, the Angular 2 HTTP service,
a built-in service which allows us
to connect to the web, so, to connect
to any routes and handler responses in the background,
this service uses Observables.
So it basically sets up a request as an Observable,
which means it gives us this Observable thereafter,
so that we can listen to any responses
we get back from the request, which was sent
to the back end to our server.
So that's just a pattern to make sure
that we can still execute code whilst our request
is travelling through the web, handled by the server,
and eventually gives us back a response.
It would be pretty bad if we would have to wait for that.
And, it turns out, with Observables, it's really easy to do.
So, once we get this response, we can use
another method provided by this
Observables third-party library Angular 2 uses,
which allows us to map this response,
which basically means transform it,
so, for example, extract certain fields
from that response we're interested in,
and we can do all of that in a callback
of this subscribe function we used on this Observable
to send the request in the first place,
and to be informed about responses coming back.
Well, that's the theory.
It becomes more clear once we see this in action,
and you'll see it's pretty easy
to send HTTP requests with Angular 2.