Now how do we hook up our
Angular 2 front end to this back end?
The back end route here is prepared so
we have to do some work in our front end.
Now for this, make sure that your NPM run build
process is running so that any changes you
make instantly get re-compiled.
Now in my messages folder on the front end,
I get this message service and here we get
the @message method, now we should change
this method to no longer simply push this message
on our array of messages, but instead
actually send it to the server.
I'll leave the push method here for now.
But I want to do here is I want to use Angular 2's
http service instead of logging in to the console.
Now I need to inject this http service
into the message service here.
We already learned how to inject services
but we haven't done this inside of a service.
It's really easy though, I can do it the same
way I do it in components for example.
I set up my constructor and then I simply
give it a name or as I do here, immediately
bind it to a property in this class here.
Let's name it http with a lower case h.
And the name of the service I wanna use
it Http with an upper case H, imported from @angular http.
So this is the constructor which allows me
to use http in here, though there is one important
thing to memorise here or to be aware of.
Like this, this would give us an error.
Because here, we need to attach some metadata
or a decorator to this class.
It turns out that the Angular 2 injector
is only able to inject services into classes
which have some form of metadata attached to them.
Now this plain vanilla class here doesn't have any metadata.
A component on the other hand, like the input component, of
course does have the @component decorator which is why we
can inject a service without any issues.
Now which decorator should we attach
to this service class here though?
Should we attach @component, no that certainly
doesn't make any sense, it's no component.
We don't want to turn this into a component.
Instead for this, we got the @injectable decorator.
This has to be imported from @angular core.
And what it does behind the scenes is nothing,
but it adds some metadata so that the injector
is able to give us the service here.
So with this were able to inject the http service
in the message service class.
Another missing thing or another important thing
we have to do is, we have to go to the
app module and unlock this http module.
So the http service is built in, but to unlock
it, we have to import a built in
module Angular 2 ships with.
This module is named http module and this module
which also has to be imported of course,
from @angularhttp, this module unlocks the http service.
Which means if we don't add this module,
we're not able to inject http here.
But since I just added it, this will work fine.
Now with this setup, I can go to the @message method
and here I want to setup the request I wanna send.
So I access http and then we'll send a post request.
So post is the method I'll use.
Now here, I have to pass a couple of arguments.
The first one is the URL to which
I want to send this request and here this
will be localhost:3000, my local server of course.
This needs to be exchanged for the server
for the domain of your real server,
once you deploy this application.
And then /message, since /message, if you
remember this is the path in the @js file in the root folder
which sends requests to the message routes
which happens to have a reference to our
router in the messages file in the routes folder here.
So we wanna send it to /message to get our
request to the right address.
Though we still need to pass more arguments,
or one more argument at minimum.
The data we want to send, since it is a post request,
the data is not encoded in the URL with query
parameters, but instead the data is sent in the post body.
So we need to set up this post body.
I'll create a new constant, I'll name it body.
And here all I wanna do is I wanna take the message I'm
already passing to @message and turn it into JSON format.
For that I can use the JavaScript helper,
JSON stringify and pass message as an argument.
This will give me a body in JSON format
which I can attach to this post request.
So here, I'll attach body like this.
Now nothing would happen because this line here
now sets up a so called observable.
It doesn't send the request yet.
This is extremely important to understand.
This line does not send a request.
It only sets up an observable, this object
I was explaining on the slides which holds
the request which allows us to subscribe
to any data this request will give us back.
But which doesn't send the request yet.
The reason why the request isn't sent yet,
is because no one has subscribed to this observable.
Well, if no one is listening, why would you send a request?
You wouldn't right, and this is why it hasn't been sent.
I don't want to subscribe in the service here though.
I want to subscribe in the component which
calls the @message method, this is a pattern
you'll see a lot of the times that the subscription
happens in the component, which, well needs
the data or which issues the data.
So here, I will therefore return the observable
which was created by this post method here.
Though I will add another method or
chain another method here, the map method.
Which I also explained or introduced on the slides.
To be able to use map, we need to
add another import here though.
The import may look a bit strange.
It's rxjs/rx and rxjs is simply the observable
third party library, Angular 2 uses.
So it's not from Angular 2, this simply another library.
And with this import from this library
and then from the rx sub folder so to say,
we're basically unlocking all these operators
as they are called, like the map function.
There are a lot more operators and observables
can be a pretty advanced topic.
But the map function here is one which you
will often times use which is pretty powerful.
It allows you to transform the data
once it comes back from the server.
So I can already set up how data should
be transformed here so that later on
in another function when I use this data,
it already has this transformed format.
So in here what I can do is,
I can take the response I'm getting back,
which is of type response which needs to
be imported from @angular http.
And then in here I can do whatever I want,
I can extract certain fields.
Whatever I return in this call back function here
will be what, from there on, is treated
as the data I returned by this whole observable.
So I could return the response as it is
in which case this map function is pretty redundant.
Or I can call the JSON method on it.
The JSON method is simply a method offered
by this response object here which allows
me to extract data which was attached to the response.
So that means it froze away the status
code and all the headers and so on.
It only gives me the data which was attached
to the response and more than that, it automatically
kinda words it to a JavaScript
object so that I can work with it.
So if we have a look at our back end route
and the messages follow, we're attaching
this object here to a success response.
This object does have a message field
and then this object field which contains
the result of the database operation.
So it is this object which we then get in the front end,
simply by calling JSON on the response.
I know this is a lot, we'll see it in action soon though.
First, I wanna add another operator, the catch operator.
And like map for the success case,
this allows me to handle errors.
So an error, which of course, also is a response
because we always get back a response.
There is no success or error response like this.
It's always a response, it just
has a different status code.
But here, this response, well I could do whatever
I want with it, here I'll simply call observable.
Which I need to import from rxjs again, this
is the observable library and then throw to, well
basically return this response.
And here I can then also call error JSON to extract only
the data object attached to this error response.
So why observable throw, because the catch method
unlike the map method does not by default turn the
return statement of this callback function.
So this here if we wouldn't have observable throw,
it doesn't turn this into an observable automatically.
The map method does this, this data we're converting
here, behind the scenes gets converted to a new observable.
Because, remember we're returning observable here in
the end, so we can't start returning
anything else here in our call backs.
So for a map function it's automatically converted.
For the catch function it's not.
Which is why we do it manually by calling
observable and then throw will keep the error state.
And not all of a sudden turn
the error in a success response.
Why is this differentiation between
error and success important?
You'll see this now when I go to the the
when I actually call add message and where I will
subscribe and where I will handle the
actual data we're getting back.
Because even though we already talked about
this observable, we haven't sent it yet.
So time to finally do this in the input
component where we call add message.
Now this line won't work anymore because
calling add message isn't enough.
This will give us back an observable and as I said, I need
to subscribe to this observable to make anything happen.
So let me chain another method, subscribe.
Now this, will actually send the request.
And it would already send it like this.
But I also want to see the response we get back.
Now the takes three arguments.
And actually that will be three callback
functions which get executed in three different cases.
The first case is the success case.
So let's say we get back some data.
And I simply want to lock this data to the console.
The second argument, the second callback function.
And these are just of course fat arrow functions
using ES6 syntax here in case you didn't recognise.
So the second function will be the error function.
This is why this differentiation is important.
So here, I can console error, the error.
The third function which I won't pass,
would be the complete function.
So, this gets executed whenever the observable completes.
It differs from the first callback, the data callback.
As this callback will be called whenever we
receive new data through the observable.
So in this case, whenever we receive a response.
Where as the last callback here, would get called
whenever the observable finishes to exist.
So basically when it completed, when it knows
there won't be any more data to come in the future.
Now while this might be interesting to listen to,
I know there will be only one response sent
by the server and I'm only interested in this response data.
This is why the first two callbacks are enough for me.
Well with all that talking, let me save this.
Also, make sure to restart your server
since we made some changes there.
And thereafter, let's head over to the application
and actually save a message.
Well, we get an error, we get a 500 error.
The reason for this error can be a bit
hard to track down, because if we did into
the error, we get the validation error.
And specifically, that the content path here is missing.
Now if we have a look at our messages js file here in the
routes folder, we clearly are passing the content here.
Now, you could guess that the request doesn't send
the content though the body correctly.
So that in our message service where we attached
this body to the request, we got an issue with this body.
But the issue actually is another one,
we are sending this request as plain text.
We can't see this in the network tab.
If we click on the red request which
is the one throwing the error.
And then in here, we can see that in our request
headers, our content type is set to text plain.
Now as it is set to text plain, it doesn't have properties.
It doesn't have key value pairs which means once we try to
extract data like we do here, this will fail.
Now we have to change the content type for this
to work correctly, and for that I will attach
some headers to this request.
So time to create some new headers with the
headers object Angular 2 ships with.
Which is important from @angular http.
Now I can pass a JavaScript object to the constructor
of this object and here I can already
set up the headers I want to use.
So here, I want to set, content type to application JSON.
And with this headers created here, with this headers object
I can add a third argument to my post request setup here.
Which is a JavaScript object where
I can configure this request.
And the one thing I want to configure
are the headers of this request.
By setting headers to my headers constant here,
I pass my headers to this request.
I add the headers I set up here
so the content type in this case.
Now with this, if I save this and then I'll
let this re-compile, by the way, if this ever
should crash, simply restart it.
Sometimes it does this, so once it's
recompiled, I can reload this page.
Of course, the request didn't,
excuse me, the message didn't survive.
Now if I send another one, now this looks better.
No error, instead, the object I get back with
the message, safe message which clearly is the message I'm
sending in my routes file here in case of a success.
And my object which is the object stored in the database.
We can also see this if we go to the MongoDB
client here in the shell, start it with /Mongo
as you'll learn in the MongoDB section.
So, if I go to that and I already navigated
into my node angular database with use node angular.
So in here, I can run db messages to access my messages,
find to see all messages currently stored in the database.
Now here, we only see one message and this
happens to be the one with just saved here.
Now of course, once I reload this, it's still gone
because once I do save it to the database,
we right now have non way of retrieving it.
So this is what I'll work on next.