So while it is nice
to be able to save messages, to see them being locked here,
and to see them here in the mongdoDB shell client,
it would be great to also see them in our application here
once we reload the application.
But right now, this is not happening, so let's work on this.
I'll again start with the backend.
So in my messages.js file in the routes folder,
I'll add a new route, and you can add it below
or above the post route, I will add it above.
This will be a get route because now I want
to get my messages.
The path is all just slash because remember,
it has this invisible message at the beginning,
since this is our filter in the root app.js file.
I then have the well-known callback function,
which passes me the request, the response,
and this next callback I can execute.
And in here, I now want to find all my messages.
I can use my mongoose model to do so,
so I can directly use the model, the object I imported
here at the top, and call find on it.
Now it could pass arguments to control
which messages to find.
This would be a java script object where it could say
content should be, and then, well, whatever condition.
But if I don't pass anything, that means find all messages
and this indeed is what I want to do here.
Now, I could add the callback in here, function.
But I would do it differently, and you'll learn why
I set it up differently in the next section
when we add users.
I will use a style where I can chain multiple methods
to retrieve data, and then at the end, I call exec
to execute them all.
Now right now, I only have find chained, so this doesn't
make any sense right now, but again, I'll come back
to this in the next section of the course.
So this exec function then takes the callback,
which I could also pass to the find method directly,
which either gives me an error or any documents it fetched.
We can also name this messages, since we know it will be
a couple of messages.
So in here, I now want to check if we do have an error,
in which case, again, I will just copy the code
from down here, I will return status code 500,
an error occurred, and pass the error object.
But if we don't have an error, in this case,
I want to set the status code to 200 for successful,
and then I want to pass a j.son data,
where some j.son data, which is a java script object here
where I set some message, let's say, simply success,
whatever you like, of course, you don't have to pass
this message in the first place, if you don't want this.
And then, and this is important, my messages.
Now I could name it messages, I'll stick to object
since this was also the field name I chose down here
when we saved the message, but you're free to rename this.
Just make sure to also use this field on the front end then.
So here, I pass my messages.
This is all, this is my backend route and function
to fetch my messages from the database.
Now the next thing we gotta do is,
we need to connect our Angular 2 front-end to this function
and call this function or access this route
and then work with the data we get back.