As with sending the message,
of course we now have to work in our message service again,
where we get the messages.
Now, getMessages no longer works like this.
I will no longer simply get my messages array.
Instead, here, I want to reach out to my backend
and get the messages from there,
so let's override this and access http here again.
I will return it because, again,
we will just create an observable,
but here, of course, I need the get method,
since we will send a get request.
The URL is the same as above,
so you may just copy from there.
It's slash message at the end.
I don't need to send the body here,
because I'm not sending any data in the request body,
and I also don't need to setup headers,
because, again, I'm not sending any data,
so no need to set the content type.
I do want to transform the response, though,
so I do need the map method.
Here, I will get back my response, of course,
of type Response, as before,
but now, it's more than a one-liner,
so I'll add a function Body here.
First, I want to retrieve my messages, like this, messages.
I can retrieve them from the response with the json method,
and then access the object field.
Remember, this object field here,
is the field I'm setting up here,
when I'm getting my messages
and setting up the object and returning.
If I were to rename this to messages,
then I would have to use messages on the front end as well,
but here, it's object.
So these are the messages I got from the server.
The issue is the messages on the server
do have different fields
than the ones I need on the front end.
If we have a look at such a message object,
you see we get this underscore, underscore, v-thing,
the underscore id-thing and,
well, that's not really how
our front end message looks like.
Instead, our front end message should look like this,
content, username, and possibly a messageId and userId.
Now, in order to achieve this, I need to transform it here,
so first, I will create a new array,
name it transformedMessages,
which will hold my, well, transformed messages.
So this will basically be an array of messages,
so let's import messages,
on, of course, a type Message array,
and there will be an empty array at the beginning.
Next, I want to loop through my messages
in this messages constant here.
So here, I can simply say for let message of messages,
this for-of loop is ES6 syntax supported by TypeScript.
So here, it can loop through all the messages in the array,
and then, for each message,
I want to say transformedMessages,
push, so push it on this array of transformed messages,
and here, simply create a new message, like this.
This new message will then hold the content,
which I can extract from the message
I'm currently at in this iteration,
and here, the content field.
I also want to store the id,
so message.id is the next field I want to extract.
And for username and userid,
I'll pass dummy and null for now, because I don't have it.
I don't use users yet.
So with this loop, I'm looping through
all the messages I get from the server, I transform them,
and I push them onto the array, transformedMessages.
As a last step, I return this transformedMessages array,
because my map function here needs to get
something returned to it, kind of,
because again, behind the scenes,
it will automatically create a new observable
which holds these transformed messages.
Because always keep in mind,
we are subscribing to an observable in the end,
so map needs to give us an observable.
It does this behind the scenes,
but it needs to have something to work with,
and this is what we return here,
our transformed data.
Next, I will also add the catch method from above,
to handle any possible errors here.
Now, with this, I'm extracting my messages.
It's now, of course, time to also use them in my components.
So any message list component where I get my messages,
we no longer assign them like this.
Instead here, we need to subscribe to our messages service,
and what I want to do here is in the success callback,
where I get my messages,
and I know this will be of type, Message,
array, of course, because this is what we set it to
in the transformed messages array,
we created the map method.
So here, what I want to do is,
I want to set this.messages equal to messages here,
and this parentheses should be placed here.
Now, to keep this application in sync
back in the message service, what I will do is here
in the map method, for example,
I will also set this.messages, so in the service,
equal to the transformedMessages,
so that the array I'm returning here,
and I'm using the component, is all the same,
due to it being a reference type, as in this service.
This will become important later on,
when I start accessing messages from other methods,
like later on I will access them from the addMessage method,
or delete them, and so on.
So with this, if I rerun the build process,
since it quit due to some error here.
If I rerun this,
also make sure to restart your backend server,
since we made some changes there.
Thereafter, let's reload this application.
We already see the test you created before,
so fetching does work.
Now, the username is missing,
and that's just happening because I have a tiny mistake here
when I transformed my messages.
I'm assigning the message id to the username field,
and the username to the message id field.
So, I'll quickly reverse or switch these two fields here.
So with this now, if I save this,
let it rebuild, and then, reload the application,
we should see, Dummy, here,
and the part where we stored the actual user,
that will follow in the next section.
For now, we've got a working mechanism
to save and fetch messages.
The next step, of course, is to also be able to edit them.