Editing messages is something right now
we haven't really implemented.
I can click Edit, but this will only change the value here.
Well, now, I want to have the functionality
that once I click Edit,
I load the message here in the input field,
I can change it and then save it back to the database.
I also want to have a button which allows me to,
well, cancel the editing process,
and not only do I want to have this process,
which is 100% front-end only,
I also want to store whatever I enter here
as a new value to the database.
Of course, only if I save and not if I cancel.
So, let's implement this starting with the front-end.
If we have a look at the message list component,
which is the component rendering all our messages,
and then at the MessageComponent,
which is the individual message,
we see this onEdit method,
which executes or which emits this editClicked event here.
This event is then handled by the MessageListComponent here.
Here, where I list into this custom event.
Well, and then here, I simply changed the content.
I don't want to use the setup anymore.
I want to edit the actual message in the array
and then save it to the database.
So, I'll delete this in the MessageListComponent
where I list into my own event,
and in the MessageComponent,
I will delete this output in the EventEmitter.
I also no longer need to import EventEmitter
and output, therefore, since I don't use it.
Now, I want to do all of that in the Service,
in the Message Service.
So, I'll get rid of this line, which doesn't work right now,
and back in the Message Service,
it's time to work on that.
Here, I want to add a new method,
which I'll call editMessage.
To this method, I wanna pass the Message,
which should get edited,
and I will call this message from my message component.
Now all I want to do here, though, is
I want to inform the message input component
that it should now load this message
into this input here in the HTML template,
so that I'm able to, well, change it.
So, in order to do this,
I will add a new property here and EventEmitter,
and I will call it, messageIsEdit,
of course, you may choose whatever name you like.
This will be a new EventEmitter,
of course, therefore, you will need to import it
from "@angular/core",
and it will event a message object.
It will emit, excuse me, a message object in the end.
So, with this set up, I can go to my editMessage method,
where I called this.messageIsEdit,
and emit this event.
Here, I wanna pass the message which is sent
to this method.
Why do I set it up like this?
Because the Service will now act as a middle man
between the MessageComponent,
which we'll now, simply use this Service,
and call editMessage, and pass the message
off this component,
this.message, of course,
and the input component, when I wanna list into this.
So, here, I will implement OnInit lifecycle hook,
which also needs to be imported from "@angular/core"
to add the ngOnInit method, which is the perfect place
to now call this.messageService.messageIsEdit,
so this event, and subscribe to any events
which may get emitted,
so that this message input component gets informed
whenever in some other component,
I click the edit button.
Now, what do I want to do once the edit button is clicked?
I want to load this message into my input field.
Now, of course, if we have a look
at the message input component template,
right now, we're not really using
any pre-filled values, this is always empty.
We don't have a possibility to fill this input
with our own value.
Time to add this functionality.
In the time script file, in the class body,
I'll create a new property, called message,
which will present the message loaded into the input field.
This is of type Message,
and by default, that this of course, undefined
because by default, the field should be empty,
so there is no message pre-filled into this field
because the default is set we create a new message,
but I can hook up this input field
with this ngModel here, by adding square brackets.
Not square brackets and parentheses,
I don't want to set up two-way binding.
I don't want to ...
Update the message property
of this component on every key stroke,
but I want to pre-fill it.
If this message property we set up here,
if this is not a new find,
then I want to fill the value into this input field.
This is what ngModel, here, does.
Though, of course, I want to target
the content of this message,
and I pass a question mark to only do this
if it is not undefined,
in which case, of course,
there is no content field to access.
So, if the ...
Message property, here, is undefined as it is by default,
there will be no value in my input field,
but if we do have a value for message,
if it is set to something else, than undefined or null,
well then, we will see the content of this message.
So, here, back to the ngOnInit method,
where I subscribe to my messageIsEdit event.
Here, I can simply say,
well, for each ...
Message I get passed,
since I know I will get a message passed
to this call back, so it is of type message,
since that is what this event emitter is set up to emit.
In this case, if we receive such a data
if this event is fired, then I want to set this message
equal to the message I get passed
through the event emitter.
Now, let's save this and I already see this in action.
If I reload my application here,
and I click on Edit,
see this, we already load Test.
Though, right now, if I click Save,
I created a new object, as you will see once I reload.
So, this doesn't really work.
It doesn't really save it.
Also, I get no way of clearing this input,
and well, of course, I can clear it like this,
but then, I have the red button.
So, this needs some more fine-tuning.
The fine-tuning I wanna apply to this input field here is,
I want to have a clear button,
which allows me to reset the form,
and I want to, once I click the Save button,
not Save it as a new
message, but instead update the existing one.
I'll need a new method in my Service form disc.
Well, let's start with resetting the form.
Here, in the onSubmit method,
I already call Form, resetForm, when I clicked Save.
So, this is done, but I want to have this Cancel button.
Here, I want to add a new button
to my input component to this form.
So, I'll quickly do this.
I'll add a button, which is of type buttons,
so, that it doesn't submit this form,
and then, we'll get the bootstrap classes,
btn and btn-danger, to make it red,
and here, I'll simply say, "Clear",
and what this clear button does is, it will execute
the onClear method in my input component body here.
So, here, we have onClear,
and what do I wanna do here in onClear?
Well, let's call form.resetForm,
and in order to be able to do so,
I need to pass my form here, of course,
which I can do since I have access to it
with this f reference,
so I can pass it just like I passed it
to the onSubmit method.
Let's save this and see if it does what we want.
If I reload my application here, click Edit,
we see the Clear button.
If I click Clear, it clears the form
and I am not able to Submit this anymore.
So, this resets it, and just clears the value.
So, that does what I want it to do,
but still, we're not able to really
update an existing message
instead of saving a new one.
So, let's work on this now.
I have to work on the onSubmit method,
which is the place where I currently call the addMessage
method in the Service.
While I don't have a update Message method yet,
but I can already implement a logic here
to decide which method in the Service should get called.
So, here I will add a if statement,
where I simply check if this message
is not null or undefined
because if this message is null or undefined,
then I know we're creating a new message,
but if it is not null or undefined,
so in this case here, we're editing,
otherwise, we're creating.
So, if we're creating,
well then I wanna execute this code form.resetForm,
welds stay outside because I wanna execute this
in both cases,
but if we're editing, then I simply want to set
this.message.content
to the content of my form.value.content field here.
So, if the content field in my form,
the single input I have here,
and then I want to call a method in the MessageService,
which allows me to really update my message.
So, let's create such a method in the Service here.
I'll name it updateMessage,
so this is not the method loading the message.
It's the one which we changes it,
and it expects to get the message
which should get updated.
Now, what do I need to do here?
Right now, nothing.
I'll soon add the HDP methods
to reach out to the server and change it here,
but to change it on the front-end,
I don't need to do anything here.
We already got all the functionality we want.
We're already editing this.message.content
and set it equal to form.value.content.
Remember, this message here,
the message we use in this input component
comes from this global array where we message,
where we manage all the messages, we get it here,
when we list into the event,
and therefore if we change the message here,
the one in the array is changed,
since we're only using arrays and objects here,
so, only reference types.
We're not changing a copy,
we're changing the actual message.
So let's see this in action.
If I save this and let it recompile,
and I load my application here,
if I click Edit and I change it to Test 2
and save this, now you'll see no knew message was edited.
Instead, this one here was edited,
and if I reload, you will also see we didn't add a new one.
Of course, the edit didn't persist
because well, we're not storing it in the database,
but we're now in the edit mode here.
The strange thing is, the form is not reset.
So, let's see why this happens.
The form does not reset
because this message is changed here.
So, we're setting this message here,
and that means, it's not undefined or null.
So, we need to call this.message equals null here
to set this object back to null,
in which case, we will no longer output anything here
since message is now null
and we don't access to content,
and therefore, to make everything work correctly,
we also need to do the same here
in the onClear message, method.
So, here, we also need to set this to null.
What this will do is that if click on Edit,
and I clear and Edit again,
it now also sets this to null in between.
If I wouldn't reset this to null here, too,
then you will see that
if you click Edit and Clear, it clears it,
but if you click Edit again, it won't load it.
So, with this, we've got the form set up,
we're able to edit it and to really change it.
Now, it's time to work on the back-end,
and allow us to save these changes
we're making on the front-end
to our database on the back-end.