Now saving the message is actually
the most complicated method or thing to do here,
but no worries, it's not that complicated in the end.
I'll set up a new route here,
and this will be a patch route.
Patch is a HDP word you'll commonly use to
change existing data, put would be an alternative
if you want to simply override the existing one.
Here, we expect the slash route.
Again this has message in front of it automatically,
but here I also want to pass the id as a parameter,
the id of the message we want to work on,
or we want to update.
Then we have the well-known callback function here,
as we always do.
And now inside of here, the job is to use
the message object, the message model,
to find the message.
Now here, I can use the handy find by id method here,
and then pass the id, which gets passed as a parameter,
so let's access it on request params and then id.
The name I chose here in the path.
In this case, I'll execute another callback,
where I either get an error or my message if we do find it.
So, here first, let's handle the error that we have
problems fetching this.
In this case, I want to return the same error as always.
Let's return this one here.
We could also encounter the case
that we don't have an error,
but message is not found because we don't have that id.
In this case, I also want to return the status code of 500,
but let's give it a title of no message found,
something like this, and of course, all the pass the error,
though here, I don't pass the error object
because remember, error here is only set in the first
if block, not necessarily in this one,
because we don't have an error,
we just don't find the message.
So here, I will create my own one, and to be consistent
about these errors, I later on want to be able to retrieve
detailed errors messages.
The errors found by mongoose, these ones here,
will contain the message property,
therefore my custom object here will also get one.
This is a good practise to make sure that you're really
able to show your errors on the front-end,
and that your errors have a specific format
with it you can work on the front-end.
So here, you can enter any error text you want.
Here, I will simply say message not found, which of course,
also is the title, but you can make this more detailed.
Now the final step is to save or to update this message.
So here, I want to access message content,
since this is the field we're changing, and instead
of the call to request, and now where is the content
of the new message or of the updated message?
Well, this is send in the request body, so a patch request
typically has both:
some data in the path, like the id parameter,
and some date in the body.
So let's access request body content,
for the updated message content, and thereafter, I can call
message saved, like I did when creating a new message.
Here again, of course, with the callback
the error or the result, and now I can just copy the code
from the post route here where I created new message.
We either have an error or we are successful,
but I will change the status code to 200 here then,
and I'll rename it to updated message.
Now this is my backend function, far as getting the message,
checking for errors, and if I actually did get the message,
and then changing it, and lastly, saving the
well, changed message back to the database.
Mongoose will hear automatically not create a new one,
but simply override the old one,
or override the change fields in the old one to be precise.
With this set up, it's time to go back to the front-end
and hook it up to this backend.