Let's hook up our front end to the back end.
Here in the message.service, I get the updateMessage method,
which is called when we, well, actually do update a message
or which we want to call, in this case.
Well, right now, I'm not doing anything here,
so let's copy the code from the addMessage method,
since a lot of that is actually the same code.
We do want to create a body which contains the message,
the updated one that is,
and we do want to set these headers,
but the method is patch.
Of course, here in the path, we need to pass this ID,
so add a slash and then message.messageId.
This is why we're fetching it.
Now we're passing this message ID to the path,
because remember, on the back end,
we're expecting to get an ID in the path here.
So with this set up, we're sending this patch request.
The transformation I'm doing here is fine.
Now we can hook up our input component
to actually trigger this updateMessage method.
So here in the onSubmit method,
where I currently only set this message to null,
well, before I do this, I want to call
my messageService.updateMessage
and pass my updated message to it.
Thereafter, it's time to subscribe to it
to actually send the request.
Now, here, I will only print the result to the console,
so console.log .
You could also log the error if you want.
Now, in order to see this in action,
I need to make sure that the messageId
is actually stored in my message models
here on the front end.
I'm doing this here when I'm getting my messages,
here when I store messageId in the message.id field.
This is key.
Otherwise, this messageId field here won't be populated
and I'm not able to access it and pass it.
Now, to populate it correctly, though,
I need to change this to _id, small mistake,
because, of course, on the back end, in the server,
it has this _id name.
You can see this here in the Mongo DB Shell client.
The field name is _id.
So this allows me to retrieve it here when I fetch messages.
Of course, I also want to do this
when I add a new message, though.
Otherwise, a message which I added
won't have the messageId.
Therefore, if I edit it instantly
before reloading the application in-between,
I would get an error.
So let's do this, too, and I will do this here
in the map function, where I return my messages.
So I'll extend the function body here.
I'll store this in the result constant.
This is what I'll get back from the server.
Then, here, I want to return a new Message,
and here, the content should be my result.object.
Remember, on the back end here, Message is service,
on the post route, I do store the created message
in this object field.
So this will be the new message I retrieve.
And there, of course, the content field.
Now, for the username, I'll set this to Dummy for now.
The messageId should, again, be result.obj
and then _id, like we changed it down here.
Here, I want to set the user ID to null.
I'll add the real user ID
in the next section of this course.
Now, do you think this would work?
It wouldn't, because on the front end,
we still push a new message, like this here,
right before reaching out to the server.
The fact that I return a new message here
and store the ID doesn't influence
the message which actually gets stored in the array,
so if I don't reload the application,
we still have, well, no ID stored there.
So this.messages.push has to go away here.
Now, we could implement it in two ways.
I could implement the push method here somehow
in the input component or here in the map method, as well.
So here, where I return the new message,
I could instead store it here in, let's say, message
like this.
Then, in the next line, I can
push it on my messages array
like this before I then ...
Whoops, only one A.
Before I then return my message, like this.
Now, with this in place,
if I now save this, let it recompile,
and also restart the server,
since we changed something there,
if we now head over to the running application,
we can click edit on an existing message, save it here.
We get the Updated message message, which looks great.
If I reload, let's see if that persisted.
Yes, it did.
If I add a new message, without the W, let's say,
and I now want to change this without reloading the app,
if I now hit save, this all looks good.
I got the Updated message message here.
Once I reload, we see it was, indeed, updated.
Now we got the edit and update methods in place,
we're able to create new messages to fetch our messages
and to update them.
The missing piece, of course, is to delete them,
and you will see this is really easy to implement.