For deleting messages,
I'll again start in the backend here
in my messages.js file and routes folder.
And here, I will add a new route, which is a delete route
so it uses the delete method.
The path here again is slash and then the id
of the message I wanna delete.
So like the patch route, the delete route gets
some or all of the data it needs in the path.
I'll then add the callback function
you already are aware of,
and then in here, I will pretty much copy the code
from the patch function because I still want to get
my request or my message here, I still want to find it
by id, then I want to check
if we got an error, if I didn't find it,
and then of course, I won't change the content.
Instead here, I want to simply remove it.
Then I still have my callback where I either have an error
or I am successful, in which case I pass deleted message.
So this is basically all, this will remove my message.
Now with that, I'll instantly go back to the message service
and here in the delete message method,
of course, I want to call that, so what I'll do here is,
I will copy the code from the update message method here.
I will leave the splice method here though, I still want
to remove it from the array immediately on the front-end,
so that it is gone there too, but then I also want
to reach out to the backend, and of course,
I do remove it from the front and then right before this
backend method comes back to me,
before this request was sent,
because this is kind of an optimistic updating.
Here, I'm removing it before I know that it was deleted
on the server, but I'm pretty sure it will be deleted,
and otherwise, it will be back on the next Petri load.
But I will leave this splice method here, but then I called
my delete route on the backend where I pass my message id.
I don't pass headers or a body though.
I only executed or assess it like a get route.
And then here, I also mapped the response
and catched any errors, but with that I'm doing everything
I want to do, to delete a message in my database.
So where do I want to trigger this then?
Well, in my message component where I have my,
if you have a look in here, my delete button.
In the on delete method, I already execute
this message service delete message,
and if we have a look at the message service, this now
returns an observable, so what I'll do here is,
I will simply call subscribe,
and then here, log the result to the console,
just to see if this worked.
So, let's recompile this and I'll restart the server
a final time since we changed something there.
And then if I head over to reload the application,
if I click on delete here,
looks good, we get the deleted message, message here.
If I reload, it's indeed gone.
If I delete all messages and reload, well,
all messages should be gone, and we can double-check this
by running db messages find
in the mongo shell client,
and we don't find anything here.
So indeed, all messages were removed, and with that,
we set up our Angular 2 two-node js connexion.
We're now able to create messages and store them
on the database to fetch messages and display them
in our application to added messages and save these
changes to the database, and to delete messages,
and also delete them from the database.
With that, we made a huge step.
Our application is now really more than just a front-end
I-don't-care-about-your-changes application.
And in this module, you learned a key thing.
You learned how to connect your node js express backend
to your Angular 2 application,
how to let both communicate,
how to send data from one to the other,
and building up on this, in the next section,
we'll work on the authentication so that we're able
to actually create users and map users to messages,
sign users in, make sure that only authorised users
are able to create and delete message, and much more.
See you there.