The first thing I did was I created
a normal node express application,
and for that I used express generator.
Which you can find some instructions
on at expressjs.com and simply Google for
express generator, you will find this page.
This is a little tool which scaffolds out
a basic express, node express project,
and I'm using this to build up on it
and adjust it to my needs.
So you can basically follow these steps
on this page and first run
npm instal express-generator -G
to globally instal this express generator
on your machine.
And once you have done so, switch into the folder
where you want to create your project.
I'm in an empty folder here.
And then run express dot if you want to
use this folder, otherwise the name of the folder
you want to create for this project.
And then, minus minus hps here because
I want to set up hps handlebars as
the default view engine.
Now I'm getting a warning here because
I got some idIDEfiles in this folder already,
but with that it scaffolded out
this project folder or setup and you might
already recognise this from earlier.
It's really close to what you saw before.
Now in this project, the first thing
you gotta do is to navigate inside of it
to in the terminal, run nmp instal
because this didn't instal the dependencies,
it only gave us a package to chase
and follow with some basic dependencies
node and express need to work correctly.
After doing so, you may run npm start.
This script is also already set up,
which allows you to start this application.
And then you can already head over and view it
at localhost:3000.
That's all, this is how the node express app got started.
Of course there's no Angular part in there yet,
but we at least have the back end.
Though, I will fine-tune this a little bit too.
And I will work on the back end next.