I added a gitignore file chest
if your using get to ignore my id files
to node_modules folder,
which we can always recreate with npmInstall,
and a public js folder, which is
where I want to store my compiled Angular 2 app.
And I don't want to store it on git
because I can always recompile it.
That's a good thing, though.
In the public folder, it doesn't look like
an A2 Project.
Now, you may use this set up if you want to.
I'll get rid of the image folder,
and I'll rename JavaScript to just js.
Just a peripheral preference.
You don't have to do this.
More important than that,
I'll get rid of the users.js file
in the routes folder,
and I'll rename index.js to app.js,
but, of course, you may keep this named
to index.js.
I'm just renaming it because this was
what I used throughout the course.
In the views file folder here,
I can also get rid of the layout.
We're not going to use a general layout
for our views,
and I'll get rid of the err.hbx file.
We're not going to render an error file
because, remember that I always want
to send the Angular 2 application
in the case of a 404 error,
so no need to have a separate page for that.
The index.hbs file, I'll clean it,
I'll empty it for now.
We'll work on that later.
For now, to finish the service side code here,
let's have a look at the bin www file.
And here the default setup should be fine.
Nothing you need to change here.
We need to adjust the app.js file
in the root folder, though.
Generally, this setup is okay.
But the first thing I will change is here.
I will remove this users routes variable
because we deleted this file
in the routes folder.
And I will rename routes here to appRoutes
and require my app file in the routes folder.
Like this.
This is the first thing.
The next thing I want to do is
I want to change the way we handle errors.
I get rid of all the error handlers down there.
And in the case here, when we have an error,
I don't want to throw an error.
I don't want to show an error page.
Instead, I always want to render
the index.hbs file to let Angular 2 take over.
So, all I do here, if we reach this point,
is I render the index.hbs file
to always give me back
that Angular 2 application.
Well, and then here,
I will also get rid of this app.use
middleware here.
We no longer have the users variable
which stored this users routes file.
So let's delete it.
Right now I want to handle
all my incoming requests here
with the appRoute variable,
which points to this routes or this app.js file
in the routes folder.
There's one other thing I want to add here.
We don't need it for this course,
but you will need if your Angular 2 application
runs on a different server
than your backend is on.
In this case, you would get course errors,
which means you're trying to access
your backend from a different origin
because your front end is on a different server.
This is not allowed by default.
To allow it here, I'll add my own custom
middleware by using app.use.
Using the command here express gives me
to add a middleware being run on every request.
And I will pass the default express middleware
function here as a callback with request,
response, and this next function
I can execute to let
the request continue its journey.
And here I will set up some headers.
Now, I already prepared them,
and I will copy them in here
and quickly explain what they do.
The first one allows any other domain
to access this server.
You could restrict this to certain domains
or IP addresses.
Here, I'll allow every source
to access this server.
And just as a side note
so that you don't get this wrong,
we're not talking about sensible server access
in the sense of accessing it through SSH.
I'm talking about incoming requests
over HTTP here.
The second header sets up which headers
I want to allow on incoming requests.
You could leave this out.
But, yeah, here I added it.
And the third parameter specifies
which method, which HTTP methods
I want to allow.
Here, it's POST, GET, PATCH, and DELETE,
the four methods we will use
throughout this course.
And options,
since this will be sent automatically
on PATCH and DELETE requests
when sending HX requests.
Very importantly, I then need to call next
to let the request continue.
I'm not handling the request here.
I'm not sending a response.
I'm only setting some header,
so calling next is key
so that the request actually has
the chance of reaching our routes here
in the app/routes variable,
which again points to the app.js file
in the routes folder.
That is the basic backend setup
I want to use.
And with that, let's turn to our front end next.