Let's start pulling in Angular 2.
Here to the dependencies I'll add the Angular 2 package.
You may, of course, choose the latest version
at the point of time you're watching this video.
This is Angular 2, it's just split up
over multiple packages because we can
then pull in only the parts we need and so on.
So these are the Angular 2 specific dependencies,
but Angular 2 also needs polyfills and so on
to work correctly.
So I will add these polyfills too.
I exit out of my server here
so that I can instal some stuff again.
And I want to instal, as a production dependency
with --save zone.js.
I also want to instal rxjs.
I also want to instal core-js.
And that is it.
These are the three dependencies I need to instal
to have my application work correctly here.
Now with that being pulled down,
it will add to dependencies here
to the dependencies node,
and with that we've got everything we need
to run Angular 2.
I will later on add some dependencies
to set up my build process though.
Now with that added, we can soon start
working on the front end application.
What I will add first are some types.
Types are basically the bridge between
shallow script libraries
and type script code.
Angular 2 is written in type script word,
using type script,
but we're also using some commands
from Shallow Script libraries,
like from core-js.
So I need to instal these types
to have that bridge so that my Angular 2 code
correctly uses these Shallow Script packages
so to say.
I can instal ,
-save-dev as these types are development
dependencies, not required when deploying our
application, and here I want to instal
@types/node and @types/core-js.
Now since this probably looks strange,
I'm not installing the node types
because we would write node-js in
type script code.
We don't in this course.
I instal them, because in our front end,
processing our front end code,
we will use some node-js specific commands
or features and for this to work correctly,
we can do so because no js is installed of course.
But for this to work correctly without
any compilation errors, we need to make
types aware of it, and we do this by installing
these types.
So I can now hit enter to also instal these types
and add them as development dependencies here.
And with that I'd say let's start working
on our front end build process next.