I will use Webpack, Webpack 2 to be precise,
to build this project.
So the first step is to instal Webpack
and all the dependencies we need.
Now Webpack 2 is still in beta.
So I'm installing a specific version here.
You may choose the latest one
but of course that may introduce some bugs
where I least know that the version I instal here
doesn't have.
But definitely check out the latest version
to know if well maybe it's released
until you watch this video.
So to instal all these dependencies
that will be a bit more.
I'll again run npm instal minus minus save dev
to instal the mass development dependencies.
We need Webpack.
And here we need at
2.0 beta 21.
That's the version I know which works.
But of course feel free to just use Webpack at beta
to get the latest beta version.
Or if Webpack 2 is officially released,
until you watch this video,
you may try just Webpack without an at anything.
But make sure that you're not installing
Webpack 1 by accident.
So I'm using this version here.
Then I will instal Webpack merge.
Because this is needed to merge multiple configuration files
because we will create a different process for
the development and the protection workflow.
And then we also need to instal the Angular 2
template loader,
to be able to outsource our templates in separate files
and load them correctly.
We also need the awesome
TypeScript loader.
This is used to compile our TypeScript to JavaScript.
We also need to use del cli.
That is used to be able to delete some files
in the course of this whole process.
And we'll need the HTML loader
to load our templates correctly.
So we do both the Angular 2 template loader
to load this connexion correctly
and the HTML loader to load the files correctly.
We also need to instal TypeScript
since the awesome TypeScript loader
will need this locally installed
even if you should have that globally on your machine.
You don't need to as a side note
but here we always need to instal it locally
in this project.
I also need to instal the Angular 2 router loader
if we want to use lazy loading.
This will make sure that the syntax we use in our code
gets transformed correctly so that it actually works.
And this is all.
These are the packages we need.
We can now hit enter to download them and instal them all.
Again, ignore any warnings you might get
as long as it finishes without an error, that's good.
And we're done.
So with that the development dependencies list here
grew quite a bit.
And we can now set up our Webpack workflow.
For this,
I will first set up something else.
I will set up a tsconfig.json file.
This is required for the compilation of TypeScript
and will be used by this awesome TypeScript loader
we use in our Webpack workflow later on.
So in this tsconfig.json file,
I'm going to copy in this default setup here
where we set up some compiler options
that we want to compile to commonjs format,
that we want to target es5.
So the code, that JavaScript code which is created
uses es5 and not es6 or something like that.
Then we got noImplicitAny source maps.
You may switch this to your needs.
And very importantly we got these two options
which make sure that we are able to use Angular 2's
decorator and metadata features
or the usage it makes of them.
Then I include node modules and the public js folder
from compilation
because I certainly don't want to recompile
my third party packages or any code.
There shouldn't be types of code but nonetheless
any code in the public js folder.
This is the tsconfig.json file.
And with this, let's add a Webpack config file.
So I'll name it webpack.config
and now the name I'm going to choose is .common.js.
This will hold a general setup we will use in both
the development and the production workflow.
I will also create two other files.
The webpack.config.dev.js file
and the webpack.config.prod.js file.
You could probably guess what these files do.
Let's start with the general setup in the common file here.
We first need to instal or import Webpack here.
So let's require Webpack.
And then I will export the configuration of Webpack
in this file as a module.
Now I'm not going to dive super deep into Webpack here.
Webpack can be very complex
and there are a lot of tutorials on Webpack out there.
Here I will simply show how to create a setup
working nice with an Angular 2 project,
specifically with this setup structure
and also how to use Angular 2's ahead of time compilation.
So here, I can then set up a entry
which is where do I want to start.
Which is the first file I want to use?
That of course is in my assets folder in the app folder.
And then here we haven't created it yet.
We haven't even created the assets folder.
But here it will be the main.ts file.
The file which boostraps my Angular 2 application,
which starts it.
We will create the application soon.
Next, I'll add the resolve node here
to tell Webpack which file extensions to resolve.
By default, it knows that it can append .js.
I'll add it here nonetheless.
But I also want to make it aware that it is able .ts.
Because in our TypeScript code in our Angular 2 project,
we will always import something from something
without .ts at the end.
So I need to tell Webpack to
check if it finds a file if it attaches .ts.
Finally, in the module node,
I set up what Webpack should do with the files it finds.
I'll keep this simple.
I won't set up any CSS compilation or anything like that.
Instead here I will configure two simple loaders.
The first one, testing
for .ts files.
So for TypeScript code,
loaders.
And here I will use the awesome TypeScript loader
we installed to compile it.
I will also use the Angular 2 template loaders
since I know this will be temp Angular 2 files.
And I will use,
maybe let's split up over multiple lines
so that it's easier to read.
I will also use the Angular 2 router loader
to change any lazy loaded routes
into a format we can actually use
if we do have any.
So these are the three loaders I want to use
in TypeScript code.
Now if we have HTML as a file extension,
let's check it like this.
HTML dollar sign to also handle HTM files.
And we should add a dot at the beginning of course.
So here, I will use one loader, the HTML loader.
Now finally, one loader I forgot to instal,
we also need to add this,
is called save dev the raw loader
to be able to simply copy a file
without doing anything with it
but to simply copy it basically.
So here I will then test
for any
CSS files
and apply this raw loader to basically copy it over.
With that I set up my common workflow
or a common config file.
Now next, I want to set up the development config file
before we then create the Angular 2 application
before I then come back to these config files
and create the production workflow.