Thusfar, we already started
setting up this workflow.
I want to continue with the dev workflow,
but then we also need to build
our Angular 2 application
so that we can actually test this and see something.
Now, here in the corrupted config.dev file,
I will import webpackMerge
to be able to merge the config I'm creating here
with the common config.
I don't want to overwrite it.
I really want to merge the differences.
Therefore I will import the config configuration here.
It, of course, lives in this webpack.config.common file.
Here I'll add .js to find it.
And I will export the merged configuration here
So we'll call webpackMerge, which is a function
and here I pass the common configuration
and that has an object the things I want to override.
I will set up a devtool to get some source maps and so on.
And you can learn more about this
in the official documentation.
I'm going to use this one here
and then I will set up the output
where I want to store the bundled file.
Well, I want to store it
in ./public/js/app path here.
Then, the filename shall be bundle.js.
And I will set up the publicPath
to be /js/app.
This is important to let webpack know
where our bundle, our compiled code lives
Because if we use lazy loading
where we have multiple chunks,
we not only have one bundle,
we also have small other bundles
for our lazy-loaded modules,
it needs to know where to find them.
But default look at our root folder,
which is the wrong place.
It has to go to /js/app.
This is important.
And then here I will set up the chunkFilename
so how it will name such chunks used in lazy-loading.
It should assign a dynamic id, which I do with the id.
Woops, these commas should be after the string.
Which I do with the id in the square brackets.
And then add chunk.js.
So, what's wrong here?
Yeah, don't need a plus here.
So, like this.
This is my development setup.
With that, let's now create the Angular 2 application
so that we can actually see something.