To create the angular application
I will create a new folder first,
the assets folder.
In this folder I'll create a new subfolder app.
This will hold my Angular2 application.
And in here, I will create some basic files.
App Component for example.
Then I will also create some external files
so that we can see that this works.
App Component HTML for the template
and also App Component dot CSS file for the styles.
And then also my App module of course
to have this we need that.
And my main dot TS file to start everything.
I'll create another file too.
Polyfills.TS will hold the Polyfills
of my application, so these dependencies
Angular2 needs to run fine in all browsers.
So I'll fill this Polyfills file here first.
I prepared some code which I'll import
and what this does is it imports Core JS Polyfills we need
and then it also imports Zone JS.
We can ignore the arrows for now,
it will be able to figure this out in the end.
Let's go over to the app component
and quickly create it here.
Of course I'm not really explaining
what I'm doing here, we saw it as all over
through out the course
so add the component decorator here.
My ID unfortunately is not picking up on that yet
so I have to add the import manually
from AngularCore.
Oh it can't pick up because important,
we need to run NPM Instal to instal
all these angular dependencies I added
to my package adjacent.
I didn't add them with NPM Instal here in the command line.
Now my ID is picking up on that.
I'll set up a selector.
My app here, and the template URL
leading to App.Component.HTML
and of course the import here is wrong
because it should be @Angular.
Also let's add some style URLs here.
One to be precise leading to App Component dot CSS.
So in these files here I'll say "Hello World"
in the template and for testing reasons,
I will make it red so that we can see
if the styling gets applied correctly.
Last step here or almost the last step
is to create my app module here.
Let's add NG Module to it.
And also add this import NG Module
from @AngularCore.
And in this module we want to add
the app component to our declarations area.
Also add the import of course.
We also want to add some imports here,
specifically we need the browser module
Angular2 ships with.
This is imported.
Browser module from @Angular Platform Browser
and we want to add the Bootstrap array
to tell it to Bootstrap with this app component.
Missing piece now on the Angular 2 side here
is the Main dot TS file.
In here I will first import my Polyfills file
so that these get loaded first.
Then I will import platform browser dynamic here
to have just in time compilation in the browser.
I'll come to ahead of time compilation soon
from platform browser dynamic here
and with that I can call platform browser dynamic,
Bootstrap module, and Bootstrap my app module
which now also needs to be imported here.
This will start my application.
Of course right now the index HPS file is empty
so we're not reloading this.
So let's populate this file now.
I will create a general HTML five skeleton
with my ID here and let's name it Angular2 Messenger.
And in here this general set up
is great but I will need to add two links here.
One to Bootstrap and you may simply go
to GetBootstrap.com to fetch it there.
I will simply bring in this link here.
And the second link,
well this should lead to our own style sheets folder.
So to this folder you're in the public folder.
Where we then have a style.CSS file
where we can set up any styles we need.
And actually we got some default styles here.
I'll leave them as they are right now.
For the course project I created some different styles
but yeah, I'll stick to them for now
in this module here.
So these are the styles being imported.
One very important addition we have to make here
is set up the base ref to make routing work as intended.
And with that I can now add
the my app selector here,
add the loading text to display something
whilst we are loading,
and now very importantly add the script import here.
Now in the end the web peg workflow
will create this bundle.js file
in the public JS app path.
Now we don't need to add public to the import
because that is where our index page will be loaded at
so we have to see it from this path.
So we will need to add import to JS app bundle JS.
So let's do it here.
JS app bundle.js.
And with that we should have a working set up here.
A working Angular2 application
and loading it in the index HPS file.
The missing piece now is to add a script
to the package.json file to start
this development workflow, bundle everything,
and then be able to see this bundled code.