Let's add such a script therefore.
I'll add a script named "build" here
for the development workflow.
And first thing I wanna do here
is I want to use "del," this is
the command we have available due
to this 'del cli' to delete some files.
I want to delete all files in the public/js/app folder.
So basically the old bundle and all
the other files related to this.
Next, I wanna run webpack.
Pass the config option pointing
to webpack.config.dev.js file
to use this configuration file.
And then I'll add some other options
for a nicer output, how it should handle errors,
that it should file on errors, and so on.
Also very important at the end, dash dash watch.
We'll make sure that we add the watch mode
so that this process keeps running
and reboots the project whenever
we change something in a file.
With this set up, let's now test this
npm run build in the console to see if
it correctly bundles everything
builds everything gives us a running project.
While we get this warning.
So let's fix this warning.
In the common config file, I'll add something after module.
Some plugins.
Here I'll use a plugin webpack ships with,
so it can say "new webpack"
and now the ContextReplacementPlugin.
Which will fix this error for us.
Here I prepared some code.
I'll copy in here and of course you can find
this attached to this lecture.
And with this, let's try it again
and let's run npm run build again.
Now we don't have the error anymore.
If we had npm start now and reload the application,
it's still not working though.
And I found the reason why it doesn't work.
Let's quit both processes;
build process answer over here.
The problem is here in my app component.
I forgot the relative pathway importing the css file.
Therefore it doesn't find it on run time.
And the error has went out of source
in the common config file.
Yeah, this is not the right regular expression.
Now it's the right expression.
So restarting process again
now I need to because I changed the config file.
And now I'm confident that we're able
to load this css file correctly.
So if I now head over one final time
I reload we see 'Hello World!'
in red, so this is for working
and this developmental process is therefore finished.
Now the next videos, I will take care
of our de production workflow using
ahead of time so offline compilation.