So we finished the development workflow.
Let's work on the production one now.
I will use ahead-of-time, offline, compilation,
and for that I will create a new tsconfig file
to be able to set up a specific configuration
for the typescript compilation for that,
because we will use the Angular 2 compiler for that,
and this compiler needs some specific options,
and the defaults that I wouldn't do for that.
The first thing is the module will be changed to "es2015"
to use es6 modules here.
I'll leave the target at "es5" though.
No noImplicitAny and sourceMap, that can stay as it is,
the decorator options here should also stay as they are,
but now, I want to set up the outDir,
which means the directory
where we store the files we create.
Before, we managed this through Webpack,
now we will use the Angular CLI compiler,
so here I will need to configure this in the gsconfig file,
and I want to store it in the public folder,
and there in each Javascript folder.
This will only be temporarily,
I will clean this up,
but the compiler is a two-step process or runs in two steps,
and therefore it needs to write some temporary files
which I want to store there.
Now the exclude folders here are fine,
or the exclude files here are fine.
I will add one other file, though, or one other folder.
In the assets folder, I want
to ignore the polyfills.ts file.
I don't want to compile this with the Angular 2 compiler,
because it's not directly connected
to my Angular 2 application.
It's not using the Angular 2 framework.
Then I'll add the angularCompilerOptions.
These are some options specific to the Angular 2 compiler,
and here I need to add skipMetadataEmit
and set it to true.
With this setup, I can use the Angular 2 compiler,
we already installed it here,
in the package.json, you can see it.
So with that, we should set up our webpack.config file,
and then set up the bulk process script.
So let's go to the webpack.config.prod file now.
In here, I will first import Webpack again,
because I will need to access some of its plugins later on.
I will also need webpackMerge because I still want
to use the common config,
and therefore I will also copy the import here
from my dev config file, where I import the commonConfig.
I can then export...
the webpackMerge function,
but here, I will actually call the smart function,
webpackMerge.smart ,
which means it will not only merge it
and override anything in the commonConfig
with the config I set up here,
but especially for the loaders
which I will adjust a little bit,
it will merge them,
and not just take the loaders I set up here
and override all loaders in the other file,
but only override the differences.
So we'll pass the commonConfig and then my config here
as a Javascript object,
and the first thing which changes is the entry file.
The entry for my application is no longer,
./assets/app/main.ts,
it's now main.aot.ts, and I will create this file
in a second.
This file will import
or will bootstrap the Angular 2 application differently,
and we need this different bootstrap process.
Next, the output, while this is relatively comparable,
or relatively the same, I can copy it from there.
Only thing is, here, for the chunks, I also want
to add a hash value,
though it should work without that, too,
but that's the difference here.
And that now leads to the module and the loaders we use.
Now as I said, due to the smart option,
I'm not overriding all the loaders,
only the changes or the differences.
So here, my loaders, which is an array,
I only want to override the loader
testing my TypeScript code.
So my TypeScript files, like this.
Here, I want to set up the same loaders as before generally,
so I will copy this code here.
Oops, delete that.
But for the router loader, I need to pass some options,
because now we're in the ahead-of-time compilation mode,
and I need to tell this loader this.
So here I will say aot=true,
and the genDir option is set
to the temporary place where I store these files
during compilation.
Remember in my tsconfig.aot file, I set outDir to public/js,
so here I will then set genDir to public/js,
and now /app.
I also wanna adjust the plugins here a little bit,
so I will add some plugins.
The first one is the webpack.NoErrorsPlugin
for some error handling during the bulk process.
And the second one, very importantly,
is an optimization plugin,
the UglifyJsPlugin,
used to minify my code.
Here I will set sourceMap to false,
and you can, if you're familiar with the options,
of course, adjust this to your needs.
With that, I'm uglifying and minifying my Javascript code.
A missing thing, of course, is the main.aot.ts file
to which I'm referencing here.
So in the app folder, in my assets folder,
I will create this file.
I will copy the code from my main.ts file
into this file here, in the main.aot file,
but the bootstrap process now differs.
We're no longer importing something
from platform-browser-dynamic.
Instead, we're importing from @angular/platform-browser,
and the thing we're importing is the platformBrowser object
or function here.
I also want to call "enableProdMode " here,
and to be able to do so, I need to import this as well,
so I will import
from @angular, and here, it's "core".
This will disable debugging messages,
and do some other things we don't want
in a production application.
Well, down here, I now use platformBrowser ,
and call bootstrapModuleFactory ,
and I pass AppModuleFactory here.
Now that is a file, a module I don't actually have yet,
but it will be created during this bulk process.
It will be deleted thereafter,
because it's a temporary file,
which I don't need all the time,
but during the process,
at the point of time this file comes into play,
it will be there.
So based on this knowledge,
I can import AppModuleNgFactory,
as the name actually is,
so adjust it down there to AppModuleNgFactory,
and it can be imported from the app.module.ngfactory file.
Again, this file doesn't exist right now,
it doesn't exist before and after the bulk process,
but it will be created during the bulk process.
With this file being set up,
with the webpack.config being set up,
and with the tsconfig.aot file being set up,
we can now go to the package.json
and add the production script,
so that we are able to run this workload.
I'll name the production script "build:prod"
and the first thing is,
I will also clean my public.js app folder,
so I'm copying this.
Thereafter, I will run the Angular 2 compiler,
which I do by running ngc.
This is available because we installed it in this project.
"ngc" and I will point to with the -p option,
I will point to the tsconfig.aot.json file,
so that it uses this file to get its options.
And thereafter, and this might look strange,
but this is the setup I currently use,
I will run the same thing again.
Why do I do that?
Because the compiler is a two step,
or runs through a two step process.
First, it will create these factories,
the factory we're importing there, which isn't there yet,
and in the second step,
it will then take all these factories,
and basically strip out all the things we don't need.
Strip out the Angular 2 compiler, for example.
So give us an application, some Javascript files,
which we then can bundle with Webpack into one file,
which only has the things in it we need.
This is why I need to run this twice here.
You might use a different setup,
this is the one I chose here, and which works just fine.
Next, I will call webpack --config
to point to the webpack.config.aot.js file.
And then here, I'll again add --progress --profile,
and I don't add watch because I don't want to watch,
but I will add --bail so that it fails on errors.
And thereafter, it's time to do some cleanup.
With the del tool here again,
I will delete the public/js/ folder,
all the Javascript files in there,
so all these temporary files which were created.
I also want to delete all the .js.map files
which were created, all source map files,
and both options should be run on the app/ folder,
and then any sub-folder therein.
So let me add this js/app and then any sub-folder.
Now, rightfully, you would ask,
"Doesn't this lead our bundle as well?"
And yes, it will.
So I'll add another argument to this del command,
with an exclamation mark at the beginning, where I say,
"Don't delete this, though."
And here I'm pointing to public/js/app/bundle.js,
and also we don't want to delete any of our chunks,
if we use lazy loading,
so we'll also exclude any public/js/app/,
anything .chunk.js file,
so that our bundled application doesn't get deleted.
Finally, I want to do some cleanup in the assets folder.
There, the ngc command will create these factories,
so here I will delete all files in any sub-folder
which have ngfactory.ts as a file extension,
and as a last step, and then we're done,
I wanna delete all files in the app folder,
in the assets folder, or in any sub-folder therein,
which have shim.ts added.
All the file which will get created during the compilation.
So that's rather long, mostly due to the cleanup process,
but with that, we should have a clean process.
And if I now run npm run build:Prod,
like that,
we should hopefully get a successfully built application,
and as I say it, it fails.
The reason for this failing process can be found here,
in a tsconfig.aot file.
For one, I need to add /app here at the outDir,
and I also need to add one other option,
the "moduleResolution", so how modules are resolved,
should be set to "node".
And additionally, in the package.json file,
I recognised that here,
I'm trying to call webpack.confic.aot,
but it of course is prod.
And last but not least,
we need to adjust the css loader here
to also add a dollar sign.
These are the tiny things that add up,
once you go through such a workflow setup,
not too uncommon to find such tiny errors, though.
And with that, if we run np and run bulk prod, a final time,
now it should, hopefully,
work with all these little errors fixed.
So let's see, this will take a couple of seconds.
I'll be back once it is finished.
That looks good.
Set up finished successfully.
Let me start up my server with npm start,
and then let's head over there and reload.
You see the same as before, which is great,
because it means now it works too,
with our ahead-of-time compiled code,
which we can also see if we reload at the bundle size,
which is much smaller.
Keep in mind, this is not G-sieved,
so this is not optimised at all.
We can G-sieve this to get it down to even a smaller size.
And with that, we got our setup,
we got the seed project I use throughout this course,
both from scratch, on our own.
You also saw some errors,
which I think is not that bad to see,
because it are these tiny things you forget here and there,
and therefore not too bad to see them fixed, too.
Wish you fun with the setup,
and see you in the other videos.