That was the application as we know it, as we built it.
It works fine, there's nothing wrong with it,
but if we have a look at it here in the folder structure
we recognise that we get this auth
and this messages feature.
Angular2 has this concept called modules.
We have this App module here,
and we can use this module concept
to outsource the messages and the auth related parts
into different components.
Since we load the authentication part
when going to auth here,
which isn't the default, the default is messages.
We can also think about lazy loading this
so that it only gets loaded if we actually go there.
In the end of the section I wanna compile
this all using offline compilation.
You'll learn how to set this up in
the project module in this course.
Then we should be prepared to deploy this application.
Well, let's start with the messages module
and outsource this, or build it in its own module,
in the next video.