So I want to start with the messages part here
and create a new module there.
So I will create a new file, message dot nodule dot TS,
and in there I will export a class
which I'll name Message Module.
We already used such a module here,
the app module, which bundles our whole application.
We can do this, our application isn't that big
so there's nothing wrong with that,
but to show you how to bundle it into multiple modules
or how to split it into multiple modules,
I'll take this approach now.
So for the message module, I will now attach
the At NG Module decorator here.
So that we recognise or register this
as a module for Angular2.
And I have to import NG Module
from At Angular Core.
Now in this NG Module I want to declare
all the components which are only used
in this message part and nowhere else.
So let's have a look at our app module.
First of all we see both off service
and arrow service are global services
so we should not modularize them.
How about the message service.
Well the message service lives in this app component
but we only use it in the messages part
so we might also outsource that so I will remove this,
but I was talking about components.
Let's have a look at the app module.
So component wise we can strip out
all message related components here
since we will contain them in our message module.
They are all part of the message feature.
We know where you use one of the selectors
of one of the message components,
message related components, in our app component.
So no need to make it available there.
We do use the messages component in routing
but for that we don't need to declare it
in our app module.
We do have the import up here
and the router got everything it needs with that.
We would only need to declare one of
the message related components in our app module
if we were to use one of its selectors
and directly embed it in one
of our components templates here,
but that isn't the case.
So if data can go back to the message module,
and here I want to implement the messages component,
there after the message list component,
and the message component for the signal component here,
also add all the imports of course.
And the message input component.
These are the components of this message feature
which I can now contain or control
in this message module.
I also need to import some module here.
The modules I do need are basically
two built in modules.
One, the common module which has to be imported
from At Angular Common.
It includes directives like NG Four and so on
so we need that.
And then since in the message input component
we used a template driven approach,
I also need the forms module here.
So make sure to import forms module
from At Angular Forms.
With this set up I can now go to my app module here
and get rid of the forms module.
Get rid of all the unused imports up here of course.
That is the sense of splitting this up.
And then I need to add a new import
to my app module, the message module of course.
Otherwise we won't have that functionality available.
But before viewing it,
we still have to make sure that in our message model
or module, excuse me, here,
we also add the provider for the message service
because we removed it from our app component,
keep this in mind.
Now of that if we save one more time
and let it recompile again now we not only
get the components in the message module
but also the service, and with this
if I now reload the application,
we see the working application again.
But now with our code distributed
or our module split up and a feature module being created.
If you want to learn more about feature modules,
definitely have a look at a dedicated
Angular2 course like my complete guide for example.
There I dive deeper into this topic,
but basically with that we split up
our app module, making it a bit leaner,
and as you will see with the off module,
having some other advantages we can use.
So with that let's head on to that off module.