Now, the last lecture,
we created this message module to outsource
our message-related parts or code,
components in that module.
It makes our app module file leaner,
but, besides that, there aren't that many advantages
because we still import it.
So, it is a good approach.
It makes this file a bit easier to read,
but, performancewise, we don't gain anything.
This will change with the auth module, though.
The auth module is loaded via routing.
So is the message module,
but we always load the messages here
since we redirect to them, right?
But, for the auth module, we don't do that.
So, it would make sense
to only load the authentication parts if we need them.
So, for that, let's create a new module in the auth folder,
auth module ts,
and, as before, I will simply export
a class named AuthModule here,
and I will attach NgModule to it,
this NgModule decorator, which of course,
I need to import from at angular core.
With that imported, we can now add components
we only use in the auth part.
Let's head over the app module
and see what we can strip out.
Well, we could remove these Signin, Signup
and Logout components.
These are only used in the auth section,
and you might think that you can also remove
the authentication component.
This is not true, though.
We do use it in the routing here,
and while I will change the way we load our routes soon,
we still need to declare it.
We didn't need to do this for the messages component before
because we import the message module
right away at the beginning here,
when we start our app.
So, the message module, and therefore, the message component
is available to our root router.
Now, for the authentication component and the auth part,
I want to lazily load this module, which means
I want to only load it once we need it.
The authentication components here, though,
is needed all the time
because it's part of our root routes.
Therefore, we can't remove
the authentication component here.
What we can remove, though, are the ReactiveFormsModules
or this ReactiveFormsModule here
because this is not needed.
We will import this in the auth module,
where we use the reactive forms
to submit our Signup and Signin forms.
The AuthService definitely has to say here
because we use it application-wide,
so we'll let it stay in the app module.
With that, I can head over to the auth module
and add the Signin, SignUp
and Logout components here.
And, of course, we also need to import some things.
For example, the CommonModule and then
the ReactiveFormsModule.
I'll add the imports app here first.
At angular common, we add the CommonModule,
and from at angular forms,
we add the ReactiveFormsModule.
So, let's also add them here to the imports,
and then, that's it!
This is my app module.
Now, as I said, I want to lazily load it,
and, therefore, I need to change
the way we load the routes.
Right now, we load them right at the beginning.
Here, in the app routing file,
we import this auth routes constant,
which is set up in the auth routes file,
and here, we load all these components,
so that's no lazy load at all.
In order to change this, I need to set up
my own router module in this auth module.
I'll first rename this file to auth routing
to be in line with the app routing file
from a naming perspective.
Then, I will no longer export this constant here.
Instead, I want to export a new constant,
which I'll name authRouting,
which uses the RouterModule.
I have to import it from at angular router.
And then, the forChild method.
In the app routing file, we use forRoot
to restructure some route routes for the whole application.
Now, in the auth routing file here,
I want restructure some routes,
which are only valid for this auth section,
which is why I use forChild.
It's only a part of the application,
not the entire application.
And here, I pass by auth routes as an argument.
This, of course, means that
I now need to adjust my routing file.
First of all, I can remove this import,
it doesn't work any more.
And, second, this part here has to change.
Instead of directly importing children like this,
I now use loadChildren,
and this key tells Angular 2 to lazy load them.
Here, I therefore pass a string as a value,
and this is important, a string, not a type.
I don't import the auth routing.
Router here does RouterModule I created there,
that would, indeed, load them instantly again.
Instead, here, I create a string,
where I point to this module I want to load.
Now, that is, seen from this app routing file on,
in the slash auth folder,
and here in the auth dot module file
without the extension.
I also need to specify the name of the class
I want to import.
This is, of course, AuthModule.
So, therefore, here, I separate it with a hashtag
and then AuthModule.
I added a package to my webpack work flow,
which converts the string in, actually, a function,
which Angular 2 can use at run time
to dynamically load this module when it needs it.
Now, since I point to the module here,
and we created the RouterModule in the auth routing file,
we now need to import this auth routing file
or this authRouting router module in the auth module here.
So make sure to add this import, auth the router,
the router we just created.
With that, if we save all that,
and we let it recompile, it should work,
and if we now reload the application,
we see, it works.
The interesting part is,
if you open up the developer tools
and go to the Network tab, disable cache here,
and then reload the app on the messages route here.
You'll see a couple of files get downloaded
among them, the bundle.
No worries, it's that large
because we're in development mode.
If I now click on Authentication,
watch this part down here,
where we see Network, incoming network responses.
You see that, we downloaded this chunk js file,
and this is just lazy loading.
It only downloaded this file,
which keeps the code responsible for what we see here
and what we use here.
It downloaded this file here
right here when we needed it,
when I clicked on Authentication
and not before doing so.
This is lazy loading in action.