With the application optimised like this,
using multiple modules to lazy loading,
we can now build it for production by running
mpm run build:prod
This is the script I set up in the package.json
which now also uses offline compilation.
What does offline compilation mean?
I'll start with the opposite, the default way,
the Angular 2 compiler works,
with compiler, I mean the template compiler
rendering our templates,
is that it does this at runtime in the browser,
so the compiler is part of the code we ship
as are our templates.
Now, Angular 2 offers a second mode of preparing
our application, and that is using the offline compiler.
As the name implies, we use data compiler
during development, so right now, after finishing everything
when building for production,
and this now parses and compiles all the templates
on our machine here.
This has a huge advantage.
First, the templates and some code is optimised,
unnecessary code is stripped out,
and second, we don't need to ship the Angular 2 compiler,
which actually makes up around 50%
of the whole Angular 2 framework, so our bundle
gets much, much smaller, and I can show that to you.
Compilation finished, this now creates a bundle,
and it should still work as before.
If we reload, you'll see it works.
Now let's go to the network tab again.
Remember before, we saw eight megabytes of a bundle there.
Now if I reload again, you see this shrank down
to 836 kilobytes, still pretty big, but keep in mind,
it's not gzipped.
So once it's gzipped this, it will shrink even more.
This is offline compilation in place.
As you see, a huge improvement
really helping your application at load time
and also at runtime, since some unnecessary stuff
is stripped out.
In the Build Your Own C-Project Module in this course,
you'll learn how to set up the work flow to implement
this offline compilation.
Here, you just see the result, and with that I'd say,
we got a very well optimised application,
which we now can deploy.