In the next videos I will deploy the application
we built with offline compilations.
So, whenever you see me rebuild the application
I use the command NPM run build production.
This has changed since I recorded the videos,
now simply NPM run build:prod like this.
So not production, just prod.
Besides that, all the other steps you see
should be the very same.
The messages you see here are changed a little bit,
and the folder structure on the left,
since I'm now using you built process,
but generally it's the same.
Also my assertion about which files to deploy is the same.
You need to deploy all the folders
you see here, including app js.
This file, not the assets folder.
Especially of course make sure
that you've got your bundled application here,
which should be done automatically though
when you run NPM run build:prod.
Also important, you don't need to import
enableProdMode anymore.
It's already done here in the MainAOT.ts,
which happens to be the file being used
when we run NPM build:prod.
So this will be enabled by default.
With that I wish you fun with the next videos
where we actually deploy our application.