The first thing I want to do is,
I will outsource my MongoDB.
Now of course, you can instal your own MongoDB server,
on, for example, an EC2 instance on Amazon Web Services,
but that really would be beyond the scope of this course.
This is no AWS course, right?
And the great thing is we have certain providers
where we can easily outsource this.
Specifically I'm talking about MongoLab.
So just search for MongoLab and you'll find mlab.com.
This is a provider where you can host your own
MongoDB databases or actually, it's hosted on other services
but they set it up for you and you can conveniently
manage it and access it.
Generally, there is a free plan, the sandbox account,
but for production usage, it probably will cost something.
So check out their plans and features,
and make sure you're not paying for something
you don't want or you're not paying too much.
I'll, for this video, use the sandbox account,
which is free.
So sign up if you haven't already,
and I will just log in since I already have an account.
I will see you once I'm done.
Once signed up, you should be in this dashboard here,
and there you can create a new Mongo database.
So click on this, and this might take a couple of seconds
to load.
Once it has loaded, you can choose which cloud provider
should actually host the database,
and you may choose whatever you like.
I'm going with AWS here.
And since I'm in Germany, I'll just pick the EU region here,
but choose whatever region suits your needs.
And then click on Single-node.
And here on Sandbox.
Now as I said, this is a free testing environment mainly,
but as you can see, there are of course, also paid plans
for your needs.
So I'll choose the sandbox,
and just make sure that here at the bottom you see this
zero dollars per month thing, or well,
whatever you want to pay, but make sure you're not paying
for something you don't want.
You should then give this database a name.
I'll name mine angular2-deployment.
And then you can create this new MongoDB deployment,
which will also take a couple of seconds.
Now as you can see it's now in progress,
and being prepared, and now it's done.
Once it's done, click on it.
And on this page, click on users.
Now here, you wanna create a new database user.
Pick whichever name suits your needs.
I'll name mine test-user,
and just give it a password of test_pw.
Of course, maybe you want to pick a more secure one
for real production or when you're actually putting
a real app into production.
So with this user setup, I'm pretty much done.
The next step is to copy this link here,
without the mongodb at the beginning,
and go back to your application.
Now that's the link you will have to enter into
the app.js file here, when connecting to MongoDB
with Mongoose.
Currently we're connecting with localhost,
and of course, that won't work when we're running this
on a real server.
So I'm going to replace this with the link I just copied,
and here, for dbuser, I enter test-user,
which is the user I just created,
and then test_pw, which is the password I just created.
Now as a side note, hard coding it like this will work,
but you probably might choose other methods,
like setting an environment variable with these fields,
which then are accessed through your code
to make this a little bit more secure and also configurable.
For here, I'll go with the hard coding approach.
So with that, I'm connecting to this database.
The next step is to actually deploy the application.