I want to start with Heroku,
so I'll head over to Heroku
.com,
and then either create an account
or if you already have one, just log in of course.
So I'll quickly do that.
On your dashboard, click create new app,
and then choose whichever name you want,
angular2-deployment in my case here which is available.
Runtime, I'll choose Europe here,
and then I'll create the application.
Now I don't have to specify which kind of app this is,
if it's Node.js or PHP,
since Heroku will automatically detect this,
or I could set it in some kind of off environment variables,
but I'll go with the automatic detection.
Now as you can see, you got various options of deploying.
You could just use Dropbox to sync it,
but I'll use Heroku Git, and of course for this,
you will need Git on your computer.
If you're not aware what Git is or you don't have it,
I strongly recommend googling it and looking it up.
And basically it's a version control system
which basically allows you to keep different versions
of your source code.
And you want to make sure that this is installed
for this to work.
So with the Heroku Git approach,
you have to instal the Heroku Toolbelt here,
so make sure you're doing this,
just download it here and follow the instructions
you see here.
And once this is done, you get a new command
you can use in your terminal or command line window.
So I'm going to do this.
Back in my project, I'll open up my terminal here.
Let me clear this.
And first I have to log in, so I'm quickly doing that.
Once you're successfully logged in,
you see on the Heroku page that the next step is
to put your project under a Git's version control.
I already did this.
And then you have to run this command here
to basically add Heroku as a remote repository
for your project where you can stores your files then.
So I'll do that.
The next step is to stage all your files
which means make them ready to be committed
to your Git repository and then actually commit them.
But before I do this, I have to make some changes.
Remember that in the Angular 2 code,
I'm still using these references
to my local host server here.
I have to exchange this with the link to Heroku.
So in order to do this, I'll go to settings here,
and here you can find your domain
where you'll find your application once it's running.
So copy this link and then over in the service,
I'm just going to replace all my localhost:3000
links here or addresses with this new address.
Now would it be better to store this in one central variable
which I could just change and have it change everywhere?
It definitely would, but I will just go with this
as I don't want to make this about refactoring here,
but it's certainly a good idea to do that.
I'll also do the same in the off service of course
so that everywhere we're connecting
to the Heroku server and not to local host anymore.
Now with that being done, I can head back
to the deploy page here and follow along.
So the next step is I'll add type git add .
to stage all files.
And then I can commit them with a message
like ready for deployment.
This commits my files, however this is not exactly
what I need to do.
I need to do one extra step.
I also have to make the production ready,
so I will run npm run build:production
which is the script setup in the workflow module
which will prepare my app for production
which will bundle everything and so on
because I don't need to commit my TypeScript files here.
Remember that.
I need to commit and provide my finished
app here in the Chalice script folder
so that is what I just did.
I bundled everything and prepared it.
Now I can again add everything,
and now I'm really ready for deployment.
So now that this is committed,
I can continue with the next step, to push it to Heroku
with this command.
But since I'm on a different branch here
and this might not be the case on your project,
but I have different branches for different steps
in this overall project.
I have to change this a little bit,
and I will actually push from,
I conveniently named ron-cheer.
So I'll run this.
And now you can see it's uploading it here,
writing all these objects.
Now it's uploaded and then you should soon see
Heroku kick in.
Yeah, here you go.
It detected a Node.js application,
and now it's installing all the node modules detected
in the package.json.
And we'll wait for this to finish.
I'll be back once it's done.
So it's done.
It successfully launched and you shouldn't see
an error here.
Here is the link where you will find your application.
So let's see if this works.
The title at least works.
This looks pretty good.
So if we now sign up here, create a new user.
Test, test, sign up.
You see that it doesn't seem to run,
and if we have a look at the console
we see that we get this error that we got mixed content.
We loaded this page over HTTPS, so as using SSL,
but we are requesting now with the Angular 2 services
a resource on HHTP without SSL.
That won't work, so I'll go back to my application.
Shrink this a bit.
And in my services here, I have to make
all these calls using HTTPS, so using SSL.
So we'll just add an S for HHTP here in all these links.
Now with this, I'll just repeat the last steps.
I'll build it again,
then I will add everything or stage everything
for committing,
then I will commit it, and then I can push it again.
And the cool thing about Heroku is now I'm pushing it again
and it will automatically restart this app then,
or it will detect this and everything will work like this.
I don't have to delete the old app first.
It will just work like that.
As you see it was done pretty fast
as it didn't reinstall everything,
it just detected your changes.
And now it's working again,
so let's first navigate back to the root of our application.
It might take a couple of seconds here, but now it is done.
And now if I click signup and I try this again.
Let's see if this worked by logging in here.
No thank you.
That looks good, and if I add a message,
we see it here.
Now let's see if this message stays here
if I reload the application,
if it really was stored on the server.
Looks great, so let's edit it.
Save this.
Go back to authentication, go back here,
reload the application.
Well that looks all very great,
and as you can see with these easy steps,
we deployed our application on Heroku.
Now of course you can also play around
with different settings and so on,
but this is how easy it is to get your application
to run on Heroku.