Time to deploy the application on AWS.
To do so I'll of course also need to make some changes
to my app later on but first let's start on AWS.
Of course I will still use Mongo Lab as my Mongo database
so make sure to watch this lecture
to know how to set this all up.
I'll then head over to AWS.
Just go there and I will click the login
and I'll switch this to English here maybe.
That just sounds like a good idea,
and so I'll login here to the management console.
I am already logged in but of course you may
just create a new account with AWS if you don't have that.
Be aware that there is a free tier available
which means that many services as long as you stay
in certain volumes are free to use for your one year.
Read the documentation AWS provides to learn more about this
to make sure you're not running
into any costs you do not want.
I'm not responsible for your bill
you are getting in the end.
So what's definitely included in the free here is what
I'm showing you here, as long as your app matches my app
and you're not getting tonnes of traffic, 'cause again,
if you pass certain volumes in terms of traffic
and so on, you will run into problems.
I would use Elastic Beanstalk which is a service
AWS offers which will automatically set up everything
we need for our app.
We could also do this manually by launching an EC2 instance
and then an S3 instance and connecting everything
and then adding auto scaling, and if you're interested
in that check out some courses and tutorials on using AWS.
But this course is not really a hardcore AWS deployment
and administration course.
So I'll go with Elastic Beanstalk
which is kind of similar to Hiroku.
It makes deploying applications very easy.
Now here on the Elastic Beanstalk site click on create
new application and enter an application name.
Angular two deployment for me.
You can add a description if you want and then click next.
Choose create web server then, then choose node JS
and then next and then just leave sample application
checked here to start with a default application.
We'll change this later on.
This is all fine, click next again.
This is fine too, and here you'll see
your URL you will get at the end.
Click next.
You can also click next here.
Make sure you have the micro instance here selected
because this is part of the free tier
and won't cost you anything, as long as
you stay in certain limits, as I said.
All of that here is fine.
Just leave it.
Click next.
Don't need that here.
And of course you can configure this more detailed
but as I said this is not really about AWS in depth course.
It's not.
So that's the review and what I'm going to do
is I'll copy my URL here which is the URL of the server.
I'll then click launch to launch the instance
since this will take a couple of seconds or even minutes
and well, as I said, just leave this launch here,
and I'll head over to my application entity assets folder.
So to the Angular Two code, and then our messages.
I'll go to the message service and I want to make sure
to replace this URL here local host 3000 and http,
with the URL address copied from the AWS service,
because this is the URL of my server
and of course I have to connect to this URL
and not to my local host which won't work.
So I'll do this and then here in auth service
I'll also replace all of these URLs,
and there's one other thing I have to do,
which is not obvious.
I have to rename my app.js file.
I have to do this because later when I upload it
Elastic Beanstalk will automatically launch my node JS app,
and it follows a certain pattern to launch it.
It tries to run node server.js.
So if I would have file server.js it would launch that.
Then it tries node app JS and then it tries NPM start.
I want it to use NPM start because this is the script
which actually launches the server.
However as I said it would first try node app JS
which I certainly don't want to happen
since this file doesn't do anything if it runs that alone.
Therefore I will rename this file to just application.js.
Of course another approach possible if you adjust every path
there after is to put this www file in the root folder
and you would name it to server.js.
But I'll go with the renaming of application JS,
and I have to adjust one other file then, the www file.
Here I am importing my app from the app.js file
and I of course have to change this to application now.
With that I am good to go and I will open up the command
line here and I'll rebuild my app to bundle it
and reflect all the changes I made and as this is done
it's time to prepare a folder which you can upload to AWS.
Now of course there are also other ways of deploying.
You can use the Elastic Beanstalk command line interface.
You can use more advanced techniques but here I want to show
you the basic technique of quickly getting your app to run.
This is still starting the instance or the, well,
the application, that's fine, and I will head over
to my Finder.
Here I opened my project and now I want to show you how
you can quickly create a zip file which you can upload
to your Elastic Beanstalk application
and AWS will automatically unpack this and start your app.
What do we need in the zip file?
I need the application.js.
I don't need the assets folder
because that's the uncompiled type script code.
We don't need that.
I need the bin folder which holds my server.
I don't need the gulp file.
That's for deployment, or development, excuse me,
for development only.
I need the models.
I don't need the node modules.
Node, AWS will instal that for me.
I do need the package.json file, that's important.
I need public and routes.
I don't need the builder here.
I don't need TS config.
I don't need typings, and while all of that is not needed,
I need the views though.
So these are the files I need and on Mac I can simply
right click and compress them, or zip them.
On Windows you might have an app installed
or a programme installed to do the same.
Otherwise just launch your zipping programme
and make sure to add these files into a zip folder.
So you can then compress them and you get well a zip file.
Name it whatever you want.
I'll name mine, name mine deploy zip.
So this is the file we'll actually upload
as soon as I'm allowed to do so.
So I'll wait for this to finish.
That was good timing.
I'm ready to do it now.
So I'll choose upload and then I'll choose my file,
the deploy.zip file here.
Open it, deploy it, and this will upload it,
and now it's again going back into work mode here,
because of course now it's basically installing
all the node modules and starting up your app.
I'll be back once this is running.
So the deployment just finished.
Now let's open a new tab and enter the link I added before.
We should see our application.
This looks great.
Now since I'm using the same Mongo app with,
as with the Hiroku video I already have a user account,
but I'll create a new one as well.
Just name is test two here.
Give it an email address of test two.
Sign up.
Let's see if this worked.
Looks good.
As you can see, I already see a message
I created in the Hiroku deployment video.
I'll add a new message here,
and then I can see this was created by another user.
Therefore I can't change it.
I can change this one here and yeah, looks good.
We got our application on AWS.
This is how easy you can deploy.
Now of course, you can then also add other services.
You can use route 53 to add your own domain,
cloud front to increase performance if you were hosting it
on a CDN or a cloud distribution network,
and turning on automatic compression, and so on.
But yeah, these are really details which
would be far beyond the scope of this course.
This is how you can actually get your application to run
there and for all the other things I strongly recommend
checking out the AWS documentation
or separate tutorials on how to do this.
With that I hope this is helpful to you and I'll see you
in all the other videos and hopefully courses, bye.