So welcome back
to another section in this course.
We left with a working Messenger part,
so we're able to save messages to our database,
to edit them, like this,
to save this and have these changes persist in our database.
Of course, we're also able to delete them.
That is great,
but there is a missing piece in this application.
The Authentication part here is not working,
so we're not able to sign up users, to sign in users,
and therefore we're also not able
to map our messages to users.
This is why,
if I create a new message here,
we always see Dummy here.
We just don't have a user
to whom we could attach this message.
So this is something we'll have to change,
and in this module,
I will show you how to implement user features,
and that of course, not only includes creating a user,
but also signing in a user,
and learning what the signing in a user
in a Angular 2, NodeJS application actually mean.
Because, as you will learn, it's different
from your normal NodeJS and Express only application.
So let's dive into this.