How does authentication in Angular 2
and NodeJS application work?
In a normal application, which means the front end
are basically just views rendered by our back end,
while we have this request response flow,
and the authentication would be managed by a session,
which means we keep a session on the server,
and a cookie on the client to know if the client
is logged in and delete or invalidate the session
once the client logs out.
Now for Angular 2 application, we shouldn't use a session
since our client, the Angular 2 application,
only reaches out behind the scenes to fetch or put data.
More than that, we could build a back end which works
with multiple devices, or multiple clients,
like also mobile phones.
In such a case, if we have a native app using our back end,
for example, we couldn't use a session.
So sessions are not the solution for authenticating
users in a single page application,
because we only render one page,
and we don't continuously re-render pages.
So there is a different approach you will commonly see
being used in single page applications.
We authenticate with the server,
which means we log our user in, which we created,
and upon logging in, we check on the server
if this is a valid data, but then instead of basically
saving this in our session, we instead send back
a token to the client.
This token basically contains the, well,
kind of encrypted user information and some other data.
Now this token can be stored on the client,
so in the browser, and if we want to fetch data
which is protected, for example, if we want to
create a new message and we only want to allow this
for authenticated users, we would attach this token
to our request and then on the server, we could validate
this token, so see if the token is valid if it matches
the data we have on the server.
Since the server is the one who created the token,
it is able to validate it.
We can extract any encrypted data, like, for example,
some user data we put into the token,
and if all that works, if all that is valid,
we send back data to the client, or we create
the resource the client wanted to create.
So we have this token-focused approach when working
with a single page application.
Now that's the theory.
Throughout this section, you will see how to create a user,
how then sign the user in,
how to create this token,
how to store the token,
and how to attach the token to future requests.
So let's dive into this.