As before I want to start on the back end.
Now in the user JS file here in the routes folder
because I'm going to create a user related route.
Which route?
Well, the one which allows me to sign up a user
because signing up a user is the basis for all the rest.
I can't log in a user if I don't have one, right?
So, in this user JS file the goal is to first export
the router like we do in the messages or in the app JS file.
So I'm just going to copy all the code from the app JS file
and put it in here because I want to set up the same router.
Of course I will work on this route here though.
It's not a get route.
It will be a post route because
creating a user will be a post request.
We're creating a resource on the server in the end.
Here of course this general function is right,
but I don't want to render a response.
Instead I want to use my mongoose user model I created
here in the models folder in the user JS file.
This specifies how a user should look like,
how we create a user.
So to do this I will first import this here.
So we'll store it in the user variable,
and require it from the models folder
and then the user JS file, and then in my router post
method here in this post route I want to create
a new user like I before created
a new method using this model.
But here the user model, of course.
I'll pass JavaScript object which contains the data
with which I want to create the user.
Now, the data we need can again
be seen here in the user model.
A first name, a last name, the password and an email,
and the messages, well, that's something I'll come back to.
Let's first stick to the four fields we start with.
So here I want to pass the first name,
and I can't retrieve this from the body of my request.
As before, when I created a new message here,
I simply assume that I get this data.
Since I'm the one creating this application
I can make this assumption.
So here I get the first name and then I can simply duplicate
this three times to also get my last name there after
to get the password and then finally the email.
Now this will generally create a new all user object
but it does have one big security flaw.
Do you seen which one?
It's the password.
The password is stored in plain text here.
I'm not encrypting my password,
and this is something you never ever wanna do.
Now as a side note, you also want to submit it via SSL.
I'm not doing this here in the local development environment
but on the real server you might really think
about using SSL to encrypt the data
you send over your network.
So using SSL makes your app more secure,
but one thing you definitely have to do either way
is encrypt the password you store in the database.
Now how do we encrypt the password here?
Thankfully there are third party
packages we can use for this.
So I will cancel my build process here
and instal such a package.
The package I'll use for this is, can be installed via
npm instal --save to instal it as protection dependency,
and then the name is becryptjs which is a package allowing
us to easily implement this hashing
or the encryption of this password.
So after installing this we can now import it here.
Let's name it becrypt and of course we need
to require it from becryptjs here
and there after hashing is very, very simple.
For the password here, for the value I want to assign
to this password I use my becrypt variable here,
and then I can call hash sync
which means basically hash it synchronously.
So here I then pass my plain text as the first argument.
So this password I wanna encrypt,
and the second argument are the number of salting rounds.
Now salting is basically the algorithm
or the strength of this algorithm.
It defines how strong this encryption is.
So let's put this cue 10 for example,
and with this set up we're storing an encrypted password.
Be aware, this encrypted password is a one way encryption.
You can't decrypt it.
If you wonder how we then later on can check if the password
the user uses for logging in is the same as the one stored
in the database I'll come back to this
question in the login section.
For now be aware that we're storing
a saved password at this point.
So with this user set up in safe way
I can now call the save method on this user
and here I'll add the default call back you already know.
Now I first wanna check for errors
and I can use my error check code
from the messages JS file here.
It's the same checking if error exists,
and then in which case I would pass the error here
and return from this function.
But if we don't get an error I will set the status code
to 201 for resource was created
and I will pass them JSON data with the response.
In this object I'm passing here I'll set a message
of let's say user created and then I will pass my result
as the object that had cued this object here.
So the result of this operation, the user who was created,
and this is my back end function.
This is all I wanna do here.
This is the route which allows me to create a new user.
Now the missing piece is to use this user JS file
in the routes folder in the app JS file in the route folder.
Here we right now only handle slash message routes
and then all other routes.
But we're not importing the routes in our user JS file.
Therefore I will duplicate this import up here,
and set up the user routes variable importing my user JS
file in the routes folder, and then down here I will
duplicate the message route,
and now it's up to you which path you wanna have in the URL.
I will manage or I will store all
of that in the user path here.
Make sure it should not interfere with any paths
you might have configured in your angular two
application in this set up here.
So here I can then set up my user routes.
With that the back end is prepared.
The next step is to connect the front end to the back end.