In order to connect the backend,
the user creation route which has created to the frontend,
I'll go to the auth folder.
Here we've got a couple of files
but what we haven't got right now is a service
for our authentication components here
for our authentication feature.
So I will create a new file
and name it "auth_service.ts".
Here I will create a new service which I'll use
to sign up a user, sign in a user, and do all these things.
So here it's time to export
a class "AuthService", like this.
And in here what I want to do is
I want to create a signup method which allows me to,
guess what, sign up a user.
Therefore here I will pass a user object
of type User to this method.
Of course you need to import
the user from "./user.model"
from this file where we define how our user
should look like on our frontend.
So in here I get this user passed into my AuthService.
I want to reach out to my backend thereafter.
Therefore I need to inject the Http service.
And as you learned in the
messages section of this course here
for this to work I need to add "Injectable"
to this service here.
This makes sure I can inject a service into a service.
You need to import Injectable
from "@angular/core", like this.
This now allows me to add a constructor to this service.
And in the constructor I want to store
the Http service of angular in this http property.
So make sure to import Http here
from "@angular/http".
And with this injected, of course,
you also need to add the Http module to the app module
but we already did this in the
messages section of the course,
so no need to do it right now.
So with that set up, in my signup method here
I can return the observable I create.
Remember, we are creating an observable
when using Angular 2's Http service.
And here I want to send a post request, of course,
because I want to create a user
and we created a post route here in this user.js file.
Now remember the route we created here
has a path of "/",
but invisibly it has this "/user" in front of it
since this is the only way how we can
get into this user.js file here.
So therefore the path to our URL
I want to use here is "localhost:3000/user".
Now with that I'm connecting to
this post route I just created.
Of course, I also need to send some data
to this request, or with this request,
so I need to add a body to this post request.
So let me create a new body
and I will use the stringify function to stringify
the user we're passing to this function.
So then it's time to pass this body.
And as before I need to attach some headers
to let my backend know that we're getting JSON data.
So time to also create new headers here.
This is all the same I did in the
messages section of this course.
Of course Headers needs to be
imported from "@angular/http".
And here we pass a JavaScript object
where we set the content type to
"application/json", like this.
And then as a third argument set up our headers here
by adding the "headers" key
and then our headers' constant as a value.
So with this we're preparing this observable
which holds the request who can send to the backend.
But since no one has subscribed yet
we aren't sending it yet.
So make sure to subscribe to it,
though in this AuthService method here
I won't subscribe yet.
I will first add the "map" operator here
to transform the data we get back.
Remember to make map work we need to
unlock these operators by importing "rxjs/Rx"
here at the top.
This gives me access to map
and all of the other operators.
And here I can then use the Response
which needs to be imported from "@angular/http".
And all I want to do here is
I want to call response.json to retrieve the data
which is sent with this request or with this response.
And then I'll copy something
from the message service, this catch block here,
which allows me to catch any errors we might have.
So just like this.
This is the setup I want to use.
Of course Observable here then also
needs to be imported from "rxjs".
With this we set up our signup method in this service.
Of course now we also need to use it
in our signup component to really trigger this method
whenever the user hits the signup button.
So let's head over to the signup component here.
In the onSubmit method I want to
reach out to my AuthService.
For this to work I first need to inject my AuthService here.
So "private authService" of type AuthService
needs to be added here to get access to my AuthService.
Now for this injection to work I also need
to provide the AuthService though.
You learned this in an earlier module in this course.
The question of course is
where do you want to provide the AuthService?
I could provide it in this component
but then I would get a separate instance for this component.
This might be what I want,
but is it what I want in this case?
The AuthService will be a service
I want to use in other parts of the application too.
Now I could create a single instance
for this component since signing up
is not dependent on some data in the AuthService.
But I want to inject a single instance
for my whole application.
As I will later on also use the AuthService
in the messages feature for example.
Therefore the place to inject this or provide this
AuthService is in the app module.
Here I want to provide my service application-wide
which means I can use my AuthService,
the same instance of this AuthService,
in all components and all services
everywhere I want in my whole application.
To provide a service application-wide
I set up the providers area here in my app module.
This means whatever I provide here
is a available in the whole app module here.
And since I only have one app module
this means in the whole application.
So here I will provide my AuthService.
Of course you also need to import
the AuthService from "./auth/auth.service".
By the way, you also need to import it here
in the signup component.
So make sure to add these two imports.
And with that this injection
and the signup component here will now work.
And I will be able to inject this AuthService
in any other class and any other service
or component in my whole application
and I will always get the same instance.
Now with that injected time to
not log what the user submitted,
but instead to create a new user.
So let's create a new user here.
For this we also need to import user from "./user.model"
from our own user model.
And then we need to pass some data here.
Now what data does out user model expect?
It expects the email and then of course
also password, first name, and so on.
So to get the email I can simply
access myForm here and then the value of the form
and here the email field
since we set up an email field in our form value.
So there's this neat convenient thing about this.
Same is true for the password
and basically for all other fields as well.
We do have all these fields available.
And I'm just restructuring this
to make it easier to read,
so to have it over multiple lines
since we have a couple of fields here.
So here we also will have as a third argument
this.myForm, value, firstName.
And then as a last argument this.myForm, value, lastName.
So the names we're accessing here
are the names of our controls we set up
in the ngOnInit method down here.
So this allows us to easily extract the data
and create a new user using this data.
The next step is to reach out to he AuthService.
And here I will call signup
and pass my user to the signup method.
Now since the signup method returns an observable
I also need to subscribe to it
which will now send the request
and allows me to listen to the data I get back.
Now the data I do get back,
I only want to log it the console to see if it works.
And in case of an error I will also
simply error that to the console.
With this setup we should have a working setup
which allows us to create new users.
So let's have a look at the running application
and see if this works.
I will rebuilt this application by running
"npm run build" again.
Also, will restart my server, my node.js server,
because I made some changes there.
And with that setup let's now head over to the application.
Reload this page and open up the console
to see if this works or if we get any errors.
And then I can basically fill this out with any data
you'll want to put in there and hit submit.
This looks great.
A new user was created.
And we can check this in the Mongo Shell client.
Simply run "db.users.find "
and we see this user down here which
happens to have data we entered.
And also notice the password certainly
is not what I entered.
Instead it's this encrypted value.
Great.
So this works as intended.
With that we are able to sign up users.
Now the next step of course is to use
this new user to be able to sign him in
in the signin form here.