In the last lecture,
we wired up our sign-up form with the backend,
so we're able to create users.
Now, I want to make sure that I'm able to sign in users.
As before, I'll start with the backend before I then
wire it up on the front end.
So, in the user.js file in the routes folder,
where I currently have my signup route,
I will add a new route, which will be a post route,
and here the path should be /signin.
So, in the end, of course, it will be user/signin.
Here again, we get the callback you already know and love.
And, in here, how do we sign a user in?
Well, the goal will be to find the user first,
to identify the user by the email the user
who wants to log in to the browser provided here
in our sign in form.
And, once we've found a user who fits this email
in our database, we need to compare the password
of that user in our database
with the password the user entered in our sign in form.
So, let's start by retrieving a user by email.
I can use my Mongoose model for this.
And, here we get the findOne method,
which does what the name implies.
It finds all fitting entries,
but then it only takes the first one.
And, this is fine, since I know that for each email address,
I will only have one record,
since email is configured to be unique here.
And, therefore, there is no need to fetch an array of users,
which I then have to, well, extract,
or where I then have to extract the first and only element,
if I know it will only be one.
This is why I use findOne.
What I want to do here then is
I pass a javascript object as an argument.
Here, I define the criteria by which I want to find a entry.
The criteria, of course, is the email field in the database.
And, here I want to find all entries, or the single entry,
where the email is the same email
as passed in my request body here.
So, I will pass the email from the form in the request body,
since it is a post request,
and then I retrieve it here to match any email address
in my database.
Now, here in the callback, we'll see if we were successful
in retrieving a user.
Let's first check if we get an error,
in which case, I use my standard error function
or if statement here.
But, thereafter, I want to check if we, well,
didn't have an error, but maybe we didn't find a user.
So, here I will check if user is, well, not existent,
so if it basically is null,
in which case, I also want to return a response
where the status is also 500,
but I will issue another error message.
I will say, "title: 'No user found'"
and then issue an error, which is an object
where I have a message which says,"User could not be found".
Now, here's an important thing.
If you do it like this, this might create a security issue
because people are able to simply try out email addresses
and you tell them no user found
if the email address is wrong,
whereas in the case of invalid password,
you would probably, well,
give a message like password invalid.
This way, people are able to figure out
if they have the right email, but wrong password, or not.
Now, to prevent this, a better message here is login failed.
Something like this, a generic message
where you can't tell if the email or the password,
or both, was wrong.
So, you can here issue invalid login credentials
as a message, for example.
So, after checking for errors, and if we don't have a user,
we're now at the point
where we know we do have a user fitting this email address.
Now, we have to make sure, or to check,
if this user actually
has the password the user on the client, on the browser,
entered into the sign in form.
For that, we need to compare passwords,
and that is where we face a problem
because we do encrypt the password here
when we create a new user.
As you saw in the Mongo shell,
it's a really complicated string,
and as I mentioned in the user signup video,
we can't decrypt this password.
We can't get the plain text password
from this encrypted string.
This, on one hand, makes it secure.
But, on the other hand,
how can we figure out if the correct password was entered?
Well, the bcrypt package we used for encrypting,
also is able to check if the password entered here,
in the login form, would give us a hash,
not similar to the other one, but comparable
to the one in the signup method.
Since it is the same algorithm,
we can basically see if the hash,
while it is not the exact same,
does have the same similarities, kind of.
So, if we do have a valid password.
And, while this might sound strange,
it basically comes down to this encryption algorithm,
where we can check if the same algorithm,
on the same password,
whilst not giving us the same encrypted string,
would lead to a comparable result.
So, this package, bcrypt, can check this for us.
The usage is to, again, use bcrypt here,
and then call the compareSync method.
Here, as a first argument,
we pass the string we want to compare.
So, this password entered into the login form,
which we can retrieve from our request,
so req.body.password,
and then the hash to which you want to compare it.
That, of course, is the password stored in the database,
so on the user we retrieved here, the password field.
Now, this will return true or false,
and then we can go from there.
So, here I will check if this is true,
so if it is valid, or if it is not valid.
I will first check if it is not valid,
so if not bcrypt.comparSync, so if this returns false,
if the password is not the same as in the database.
In this case, I want to return the same status as up here,
though I just recognised we should return 401
as a status code for an authorised here,
and I will return the same error message
for the reason I just explained,
to not give a clue on whether the email was wrong
or the password, or both.
So this is the case that we're not
passing the right password, we're returning this error.
Now, if we made it to this point,
we know that the user does exist
and that the right password was entered,
so now we should create this token I was talking about
in one of the first lectures in this section.
This token, which our client
then can use for future requests to tell us,
"Hey, I already logged in, I am authenticated.
Please, let me in."
So, this token needs to be created.
And, as with creating the password and comparing it,
we won't do this on our own
since we need a kind of complex algorithm behind that.
There are packages to do this.
The question in the first place is,
how does such a token look like?
And, I will use a JSON web token, short form: JWT.
You can learn more about JWT, about JSON web tokens,
by, as dumb as it sounds, simply googling it.
There are plenty of resources diving deeper into it.
Basically, the first link here is a great resource,
it is a token which looks like this, for example,
which encodes a couple of information pieces in this token.
Some header date, then the payload.
Here, for example, we can store the locked in user
and then a signature we need to verify this token,
including this secret you see down here.
We will set this on our own.
This verification signature here allows us to, later on,
verify if the token passed by the client,
is a valid token, or is an arbitrary token
passed by malicious code, for example.
So, this is how that token looks like
and again, we will use a package to create this token.
So, which package do I want to user here?
I'll quit out of my build process
and then I will instal a new package
by running npm instal --save,
to store it as a protection dependency,
and then the name of the package I will use
is jsonwebtoken, like this.
This will pull down the package
and instal it in my project.
And, once it is installed,
I can pull it into my user.js file here.
I'll store it in a variable named jwt.
Require jsonwebtoken here,
and then down here at the bottom, I can create a new token,
store it in a variable by running jwt.sign.
This creates a new token, it signs it for us.
Generates it and signs it.
Now, the arguments we pass here
is the payload we want to store in the token,
then the secret we need for verifying the token,
and then some possible options.
Now, let's start with the payload.
The payload is a javascript object
that allows us to store any data we want.
Here, I want to store the user in the token
so that I'm later able to retrieve the locked in user
from the token being sent to the server.
So, here I will set up user field.
This name is totally up to you,
but you will need to use this same field name later
when accessing data in the token.
And, then the value I want to store here
is the user object I retrieved here
which I found in the database of which I now know
that it is valid, that the password is right, and so on.
The second argument is your secret key
and this should probably be a bit
of a more complicated string,
but I will simply use secret here for simplicity reasons.
And, then you can configure this token.
Now, I will configure the expiresIn key,
which allows me to specify
how long this token will be valid.
I will set this 7200, which means two hours,
since this is measured in seconds.
With this, the token is created.
The final step is to now pass this token to the client.
So, I will set up a response with this status 200 here
and then some data to be passed with the response.
And, in this javascript object, I do pass a message,
like successfully logged in, whatever you want.
Then, I will pass the token in a field named token.
And, I will also pass the ID of the user, the userId, why?
Well, you will see this in a second
when I hook this up to the front end.
Well, this will basically allow me
to find out the ID of the current logged in user
and therefore, on the front end,
to show if a user should be able to delete and edit a post
because I want to restrict this to posts
of the user who is logged in.
But, you will see this in action soon.
So, here I will pass user._id.
With this, we're set to go.
We're ready to wire this up to the front end.
The back end is prepared.
Time to now, also, go to the front end
and submit our login form there.