Now for hooking up the sign-in form
with the backend with the route I created
in the last lecture, I'll start the auth service again.
I will copy my signup method,
now call it, of course, sign-in.
But I will still expect to get the user being passed to it.
Now, of course, the user will miss the first and last name,
but it will have the password and email, which is the
important data for me.
Here in my URL, I then want to reach out to user/signin
since this is the path I set up here in my user.js file.
With this created, I'm passing the data,
and this is really all the setup I need.
Returning the observable allows me to subscribe to it
to send this sign-in request.
The other work I need to do, of course,
is in the sign-in component here.
Here, I, as in the signup component, want to override
this behaviour here in the on submit method.
Instead here, I will also create a new user, like this,
and you need to import user from user.model here of course.
And now I need to populate this.
Now, I will only pass the first two arguments,
the my form value email field,
and then the my form value password field, since I only need
to pass email and password.
With this, I can then reach out to the auth service,
but for this, of course, I also need to inject it.
So let's inject the auth service here, and remember,
I set up the provider in the app module, so no need
to add providers here, you do need to add the import
at the top, though.
With this set up, I can now reach out to my auth service,
to the sign-in method, and pass my user,
before I then subscribe to the observable
created in this method.
Here, I do get some data,
and this data is data I actually want to use,
so I will do a couple of things with that
in the function body here.
Also, I will possibly get an error, which is simply
one two error out to the console.
But let's go back to this first callback where I do get data
from the server.
Here, you know, I get the token and to user id
because this is what I passed down here
with the success response.
So, in order to use this, my sign-in component,
I want to store it.
Now, where do you store such a token?
You basically do have two options.
Your browser does come with some storage, local storage
and session storage to be precise,
and you can store it in a cookie.
There are arguments for both.
Basically, the local storage and session storage
is accessible only while a java script,
but doesn't the overhead means it's vulnerable
to cross-side scripting attacks.
If you can rule out such a text, if your application
is very secure regarding this, which it should be anyways,
then there is no way this token can be accessed
from anyone else but you.
On the other hand, cookies are not accessible
by java script, so they are protected against this,
but they are more complicated to submit,
and they are vulnerable to other kinds of security issues
against what you would have to protect.
So both have their advantages and disadvantages.
Of course, you are free to dive deeper into this
and choose your favourite approach by, again,
as dumb as it might sound, by simply Googling for either
Angular 2 and cookies or Angular 2 and local storage.
You will find examples for both and should be able
to set this up in the way you need it.
I will use the local storage here,
which is the storage in the browser,
which I assess like this.
This is not an Angular 2 specific object,
it's an object, one that like java script ships with.
The local storage here allows me to store that in my browser
and it will persist even if I close
the existing browser window.
That's, by the way, the difference to session storage
where this will then be cleared.
You may, of course, also choose session storage.
Keep in mind that the token will invalidate
after two hours anyways, though.
So here, I can store something by using set item,
and I want to set a token here and I want to store the token
in the data I return, keep in mind, this data I return
has this token field here.
It also has the user id field,
and I also want to store this user id,
so I will also store user id, and x is my user id here.
With that, I'm storing my data.
The last thing I wanna do is, after doing so,
I wanna navigate away, so I wanna leave this component here.
To do this, I need to uncheck my router here,
so here I will inject the Angular 2 router.
Of course, it needs to be imported from @angular/router then
and this allows me to hear also in this callback
because I want to do this after all this data
has been received and set.
Here, I can access this router, and then navigate,
or simply navigate by URL to go back to the root route
off my application here since I want to go to the root page,
which is the messages page.
With this setup, if I now run mpm run build,
we should be able to successfully log in,
and receive such a token, and then navigate away.
All to make sure to restart your node server,
since we made some changes on the backend,
and with that, let's head over to the application
and sign a user in, make sure to use the same credentials
as before when you created the user.
This looks good, I'm redirected, now let's see
if we do have the token.
You can see it if we go in Chrome and the develop,
and choose the application here,
and then here you got your storages.
Let's have a look at the local storage.
Here, for our running application, we see the token
and the user id field, both are populated,
this looks great.
So with this, we do have the token
in our front-end application.
The next step, of course, is to make our application
more secure, and take advantage of this token
by restricting who's able to create messages,
and which messages you may delete or edit.