Now, before making the next steps
and securing the content of my application,
I want to do one other thing.
I want to make this Logout button work,
and I also want to make sure that I don't see the
Signin tab if I already am signed in,
and that I don't see the Logout tab
if I'm not logged in.
So, that these are only shown
depending on my login state.
Let's start by implementing the Logout button.
In the authService,
I'll add a new method here
to simply have all of my authentication-related
methods in one place.
And here, logout is simply a function or a method
which takes no argument.
And what will this function do?
It will simply take my local storage and clear it,
because I want to delete both
the user id and my token.
And with that, the only thing
which would give me access to restricted resources,
my token, is gone
and that basically means I am locked out.
There is no session to invalidate.
But without the token, I can't do anything.
So, I am locked out with that.
Now with this, I can go to my LogoutComponent.
I do have the onLogout method
which is triggered once I click this button.
And here I want to use my authService,
so let me add a constructor
and store the authService
in this AuthService property.
Of course, you need to add the import
to authService at the top.
And, I not only want to trigger this logout function
in the authService,
I also want to navigate away.
So I will also inject the Angular to Router here.
Of course, the Router therefore, also needs
to be imported from .@angular/router.
And then in the onLogout method here,
I can call this authService, logout,
the function I just created.
And I can call this router, navigate,
and then pass
an array of URL segments.
And here, let's say I want to go to auth,
and then
signin.
So, with this set up,
let's re-compile this.
We don't need to restart the server
because we didn't change anything there.
If it's false, let's try it again.
It should work.
Yeah.
Looks better.
So with that, let me reload this application,
and hit this Logout button.
I get re-directed to the Signin page.
Great.
And if we go to the application here,
we see that indeed, our local storage was cleared.
So this is the working Logout button.
The next step is to now, conditionally,
show or hide these tabs.