To show or hide these tabs,
I need to determine if the user is logged in or not.
Now, I could store a variable in my auth service,
which says is logged in and is true or false.
But keep in mind, our token persists
even if we refresh the browser page.
So in this case, we would then also need to
on each startup of our Angular 2 application,
check if we do have a token, and if we do have a token,
we need to set this to is logged in.
That's not really how I wanna do it.
So, I will do it differently, and then it is actually
really easy to find out if the user is logged in.
I will add a new method, is logged in,
which should return true or false,
and now how can I determine if the user is logged in?
Well, I can simply check if the token exists
because I do clear my local storage on logout.
If I don't have a token, I'm not logged in.
It's as simple as this.
So here, I can simply return local storage,
get item,
token,
not equal to null, so if it's not equal to null,
it means we have a token, in which case I would return true
which is what I wanna return for the question
is logged in, but if it is null, we will return false,
so we are not logged in.
With this set up, I can go to my authentication component
here, which holds my navigation,
and here I of course will inject my auth service
to get access to this newly created method,
so add auth service here, of course, make sure to add
the import at the top, and then here, I will also add
another method, which I will also simply name
is logged in, just to make this really clear
what's happening.
And here, we will reach out to the auth service
called is logged in,
and return the result of this call, is simply pass it along,
so that here, all I have to do is,
I have to add some ngIf directives.
Mainly, I will check on this list item
if ngIf will only attach it
if it is not, if the user is not logged in
because only if the user is not logged in
we'll want to show this sign-in page.
On the other hand, the logout button should only be shown
if the user is logged in, so here,
I don't have an exclamation mark at the beginning.
With this setup, I can save this
to recompile the application.
And I can then head over to the application and reload it.
And we see the logout ribbon is not available,
but as soon as I do log in, we are redirected,
and now we only got the logout tab and not the sign-in tab.
Signing up is always possible, of course, you could
disable this, but I'm find with this.
So now, we're only showing the options I wanna show.
And as soon as I click logout, we switch to sign in,
and the logout tab is gone.
So now we're showing these tabs depending
on the user log-in state, which is great.
The next step is to secure our content and use the token
we are issuing to make sure only authenticated users
are able to create posts and so on.