So with users signed up and signed in,
it's time to now map them to our messages.
We do have a check to avoid that unauthenticated users
are able to reach our post routes here,
but remember in our user model,
we do have these messages arrayed,
so each user may have multiple messages
and each message has a user.
So its time to now fill this connexion with some life.
Right now, we don't have that connexion in our database.
So the first thing I'll do is,
I will clear all existing messages in my database
by running db.messages.remove and pass
an empty javascript object because the existing messages
of course don't have a user mapped to them,
and from now on, I want to make sure
that I only create messages where this mapping exists.
So with the messages cleared, it's now time
to go the messages.js file in the routes folder
and make sure we do create this connexion
whenever we create a new message here.
So here where we save the message,
it would be great if we could also save this message
on our user, and on the other hand save the user
who sent this request in this message.
Well, to do so we need to fetch the user
who reached this route in the first place.
Now, we can do this since we, if your remember this,
stored our user in the payload of our token,
and this token needs to be sent with each request
in order to be able to create a new message.
Therefore, here we can retrieve our user from our token.
So let's create a new variable and name it decoded.
Here, I want to use the jwt package
to decode a token.
Now, a token is not one-way encrypted.
We can decrypt it. This is important,
otherwise we wouldn't have a chance of getting the data.
But here is the important thing
about the decode method I'm using here:
this method is not checking if the token is valid.
We do this up here with jwt.verify.
Here we pass the secret and see if the token is valid.
With jwt.decode, I don't check the validity,
I only decode the token.
This is fine here because I already do check the validity
before reaching this route.
If you don't have this check before reaching this,
don't use decode, always use verify.
Remember, you get to decode a token there too.
There's just no need to reuse verify here,
because again I do check it
before actually reaching this route.
So here all I pass is the token,
which is stored in a query parameter,
and that gives me the decoded token.
I can then
find this user
in my ID
by using User.findById here
and pass the decoded object,
where I stored the user in the user field.
Remember this here, it's stored in the user field.
And then _id.
I then have a callback
where I do either get an error or my user.
Now, I first of course, as always,
want to check if I do have an error,
and if I don't have an error,
I can now save my message.
So we'll take all of the code down here
and put that into my code here.
So with that, I'm now creating a new message.
When creating this message,
I can now finally populate the second field, the user field.
This will simply be the user I extracted
from the database here.
By extracting it from the database like this,
I make it easy for Mongoose to automatically setup
all the connexions in the background for me.
Now with that, the other step I want to do,
of course, is when I save this message,
and I know it was saved successfully here,
I also want to access my user,
the messages array of that user.
Remember, we do have this field, which is an array.
And here I want to push a new message on this array.
Of course, the message I want to push
is the result of this operation,
so the message we just created.
Of course, here we then need to call user.save
to save this updated user where we pushed
the new message on the stack of messages.
With this setup, I'm creating disconnection on the back end.
I'm adding the user to the message,
and the message to the array of messages on the user.
With this the connexion is setup on the back end.
Now for all of this to work, to be able
to find the user by ID, you, of course,
also need to import the user model here.
So make sure to add this import here,
where we import user from models/user.
This is extremely important, otherwise this will not work.
Now on the other route, let's have a look
when patching, when editing a message,
I don't need to update anything about this relation
because the message just changed.
The user relation didn't change.
It's a different thing here when I delete a message though.
If I delete a message, I need to remove it from the stack,
or from the array of messages a user has.
So this is something we should also take care of
when setting up this mapping,
that we don't leave leave the message ID
in the array of messages for a user
if the message was already deleted.
Now we could fetch the user here
and delete this message from the array of messages,
but Mongoose gives us another nice way of doing that.
In the message model here, we can create
some kind of Mongoose middleware,
so a method which will get executed
whenever something happens to a message.
I can define this directly on the schema,
and there I use the post method to say,
"do it after" a certain action happened.
Then as the first argument in a string,
I specify for which action I want to listen.
It's the remove action here.
I want to get active whenever a message was removed.
This now will then execute this callback,
which passes me the message which was removed,
but it still has a reference to this message
even though we did delete it.
That's the cool thing about it.
So I know this message was deleted.
Now with this, I can simply find a user
by ID; of course, I need to import the user
from my models for this,
so from this folder here,
the user file.
And then here I can simply pass message.user
since our message has a user field
and this user field actually only holds the ID of that user,
we can pass this without an issue here.
So there we then have a callback,
where I either get an error or the user.
Then here I could also check for an error,
but I'll leave this out here.
All I wanna do here is, I want to take my user
access its messages array and then
pull a message from this array.
The message I do want to pull, of course,
is the message I passed here to this callback
of my post middleware.
Thereafter, I save the user to reflect this update,
and with that, I make sure
that whenever a message is deleted,
the messages array on the user,
who created this message,
is updated so that I don't have any redundant connexions
in my database, and by the way,
this is why I cleared my database before starting with that,
so that I don't have any old data sitting there.
With these changes in place,
let's restart our back end server
to reflect this latest code.
And now we can continue working on the front end
to actually send the token with requests,
so that all of our valuable setup
on the back end is now actually used.