So, time to send a token
with each request we issued in Angular 2 application
to take advantage of the additional
security measures we set up on the backend.
Now I want to send the token
in my messages service here,
where I reach out to my message related routes,
which are the routes I'm protecting right now.
I want to add a token for sending, or for creating a message
and for updating and deleting it.
Not forgetting though, this route is not protected.
So how do I send a token?
Let's start with the add message method here.
I will create a new constant and name it token.
And here I want to first check
if I do have a token in my local storage.
So I can simply say localStorage.getItem
token and then check if this exists.
So by adding a question mark I will only reach
the following code if this is not null.
If it is not null, I want to set the token constant
equal to a string which says ?token=
and then the actual token I can now retrieve
since I just checked if it exists, like this.
So I will just restructure this
over multiple lines to make it easier to read.
Here we have the out statement
where it simply set as equal to an empty string.
So why do I use this set up?
Because now in the case of an existing token,
I automatically set up this query string
which I want to append to end of my URL.
So here where I set up my URL,
I will simply add + token
and this is even a empty string, so nothing.
Or it is my query string where I set up token equals
and then the actual token stored in my local storage.
And with that I'm sending my token with each request.
Now I can simply copy my token here
and go down to the update message method here,
where I also need to append it.
Here the important thing is to
append it after the messageId,
this is important because you don't want to overwrite this,
this parameter is expected in this position.
And of course also pass it for the delete route.
Also after messageId.
With this, let's recompile these changes here.
And then head over to the application.
And right now, I should be logged in.
So lets create a new method here.
This looks great, it seems to work.
If I reload, lets see if it persists, looks great.
Now lets also check it in our Mongo Shell.
If I, here, run db.messages.find
we see the new message and we see that
the user ID field is populated.
So this worked.
And now lets see if the message
was added to the array of messages on the user.
Looks great, the messages array does have a new ID.
And if we compare IDs, this ID matches
this ID off the message.
And, of course, the same is true
for the user ID and the user ID down here.
So we see that our mapping works.
That we're now able to create new messages.
And just to show this again, that if I log out here
and I create a new message now,
I get an error and the message is not created.
Now lets also see if deleting works.
Nope we get an error.
Of course it disappears here but as soon as we reload
it's back, because, well we don't check
on the frontend if the user is authenticated.
We will add this soon.
But on the backend we're making
sure we're not able to delete it.
But as soon as I do log in again,
and now I click delete, this looks better.
Now it's gone and now lets see if was also removed
from the array of messages on our user.
Looks great. The messages array is empty.
Which means we're not storing any reference
to any message which no longer exists.
With that we set up the basic route protection
on the backend. We're able to work with that.
But of course it would be nice if
we only see the options on the frontend
which we actually have.
So, for example, if we are authenticated
and create a new post, this is great.
But then as soon as I log out,
I shouldn't see the edit and delete buttons
because I'm not able to use them anyways.
So this is some fine-tuning we need to implement here.
Also, we want to replace this dummy
here with the actual user name.
Additionally, right now if we create multiple users;
let's say I create another one: Test22,
and then which has this other email address
so a new user was created.
And now I sign in with this user.
I am able to delete this.
So now we don't have protection at all.
I can delete the messages of other users.
So that's all the same thing we need to fix.
So still a couple of work left here.
Lets start by making our backend
protection a little bit stronger
and ensuring that only the user
who created a resource is able to delete or edit it.