In order to ensure that only users
who created a post are able to add it or delete it.
I need to work on the patch and delete routes here
on my back end. Specifically I need to fetch the user there
and check if this is the user,
who actually created the message.
Thankfully we know how to fetch the user.
I can extract it from the decoded token,
so let's just copy this code from the post route.
So with that we get access to the token,
or to the value stored in the token.
Again keep in mind we should only use this
after validating the token, which we do here.
So with this, we're able to access the user.
So what I want to do here is,
I want to check if we got an error.
If we don't find a message. But then I only want to check
if my message user
is the same,
or to be precise here is not the same.
As the user stored in my token.
So I want to compare the user ID's here,
since message.user is just the user ID.
It's not the complete user object, it's simply the ID.
So if they are not equal, I know that a different
user is trying to delete this message.
Then who created this message?
So in this case, I don't want to allow this.
I want to return,
let's say this error here.
The not authenticated error we set up here.
Here we are.
Let's return this in this case.
Of course without the error check here, just like this.
I want to implement the same check when deleting this.
So down here,
I will now
add this check
in here too,
before removing it. Let's check is users are equal.
If they are not, return with a status code of 401.
Of course, this shouldn't be error
since we don't have the error object here.
Here I will simply say
"users do not match"
and quickly copy this up here.
Here too.
So with that, we set this up to make sure
that unauthenticated users are not able to delete
other users posts and messages.
Let's see this in action, by restarting the server
and reloading our front end page.
Though that wouldn't have been necessary.
Let's create a new message here,
and then switch the user.
So now I'll log in with my other user
and I'll try to delete this. So let's clear the console.
It is deleted here, but again only because
we don't check it in the front end yet.
But as you see, I do get the error and if I reload
the message is back.
The same should be true for editing.
Which also, if I change it.
Shouldn't be stored on the server.
Looks great, so we get this additional route protection.
Of course we still need to polish our front end,
So that we don't see these buttons
if they give us an error anyways.
We also want to output the user name here of course.