In order to only conditionally
show these buttons and show the right user name here.
It's important for me that, when fetching
my messages on the back-end here in this
get route, I not only pass my message
but also the complete user object
because I need the user ID and the user first name.
So, this is some additional information
I need which right now I'm not getting.
I do get the user ID since it is stored
in this message model in the user field
but I don't get the whole user object
so that I don't have access to user first name
but I want this access to be able
to correctly display this username below the message.
Therefore, this get route here needs some adjustment.
I mentioned earlier that I want to chain
multiple methods here, which is why
I use this syntax using .exec here.
Now, the one method I want to chain is .populate.
Populate is a Mongoose method which allows me
to expand the data I am retrieving.
By default, it would only give me the message object
but now I can tell it, hey there is this reference
to the user model and it is aware of this reference
since, in the model, we set this up with the ref key here.
So it knows, well, this is not an ID, not just a string.
It really is a connexion to another object in my database.
So, I can tell Mongoose to now expand this object
so that this user field actually not only
holds the user ID but the complete
user object with these fields possibly.
Though, I'm not interested in all
these fields I will only need the first name.
To get this as a first argument,
I pass the name of the field which I want
to expand, which is user as a string.
So, this field here and then the second argument
is the
data I want to have.
So, here I'm only interested in the first name.
So, I will pass firstName to now get an object
which not only has the ID but also
the first name of the user and I don't want email
or password or anything like that.
So, with that I can leave the other code
as it is, but now each message will not only
have the user ID but instead the complete
user object or, at least, user ID plus first name.
This, of course, means that I can now work
on my front-end to fetch the complete user
or use this additional information.
I'll do this next.