So now that I'm populating
the user field in my message with the actual user,
or at least with id and first name,
I can use this on my front end,
where I fetch my messages in the message service
here, getMessages.
Right now, the new message I create has the Dummy username,
and I don't populate the userid,
though I could have done that before,
but well, now it's time to work on this anyways.
Here, I first want to get the actual first name,
so instead of Dummy, I can simply access my message,
then user, and now remember, this was expanded,
so here now, I can access the first name,
since this is the one field by which I expanded it.
I can also store the id here,
by accessing message, user, and then, underscore, id.
So with this setup, and I can bring this in multiple lines
to make it a bit easier to read.
And now, finally passing all the user data
to each of the messages I'm creating here.
So now, I do store this connexion on the front end as well.
Now of course, the same is true here,
when I add a new message.
Here, I also create a message,
and I also need to populate this with the right data.
Now, you could think that I should, therefore,
on the backend in my routes folder,
when creating a new message here,
I also need to kind of populate this,
but there is no need to do so, because the result,
which I'm sending back to the front end here,
actually already has the expanded user object inside of it,
since I already do fetch my user here, when I find it by id.
Then, I add it to my message here.
This, in this case then, is not only the id,
but the complete user object, and therefore,
I already have the complete user object available here.
This allows me, on the front end now,
here, in the case where I add a new message,
to now simply say, result.obj.user.firstName,
and here, of course, it's result.obj.user._id,
and with that, I'm saving all the user data
in the front end as well.
Let's use the additional data we're now fetching
in our message component
to now show the edit and delete buttons,
only if the user is allowed to edit or delete,
and to show the right username.
To do so, I will go to my message component,
and here, I already display, message.username,
so this should work automatically.
Let's restart the backend service,
since we changed something there,
and then go to our application and reload here,
and we see, indeed, the username of
the user who created this.
If I, now, I'm still logged in,
add a new message here,
we also see that username.
So this already works, but we need to make sure
that we only see the buttons we are allowed to press.
So that if I now log out,
and log in with the other user,
I only see the buttons on this first message,
but not on the second one, here.
To implement this method, I will add a new method
to my message component TypeScript code.
I'll name it belongsToUser,
because this is what I want to check here.
If this component, excuse me,
if this message belongs to the currently logged in user.
I can determine this by simply returning,
localStorage, getItem, userId.
Remember, we're also storing the userId in the local storage
when authenticating a user, here.
So if this item here,
if this userId stored in the local storage,
equals the userId of our message object.
Now of course, since we're in Javascript on the front end,
we can always modify this on our own,
so you might be able to hack this,
and see these buttons on a message you didn't create,
but guess what, it doesn't matter.
We're checking it on the backend anyways,
and this is important.
You always need to check on the backend
because on the front end,
people are able to change your code.
Javascript isn't secured against user changes,
so you need to make sure to always
do the important validation on the backend.
I only implement this check here on the front end
to provide a better user experience.
If the user wants to hack this,
and don't have the better experience, therefore,
be my guest, do it.
The important validation happens on the backend.
This is only to provide a better user experience.
So this belongsToUser method here,
can now be used in the message component html code
to check if this button, or if these buttons here,
should actually be shown.
So here, I can say, ngIf,
and I only want to show them if belongs to user,
returns True, so if this does equal.
Otherwise, I don't want to show these buttons.
So with this, let's recompile it and reload.
And now, you'll see I only see the buttons on this message,
which, if we open the console, I may delete,
but I don't see it on the other message,
which wasn't created by me.
So let me create a new message,
and now, I will login with the other user again,
and now, you see, it changed.
Now, I only see the buttons here,
and I am able to change it.
And of course, would also be able to delete it,
but I can't click it on the second message,
which is the behaviour I wanted to add.