In this module we achieved a lot.
We implemented our User Authentication Workflow.
We are now able to create users to sign them in
and, more than that, we're able to use them to see if
we are authenticated,
if we are allowed to create new messages,
if we are allowed to edit or delete messages.
We implemented these checks both on the front and,
very important, on the back end.
I want to highlight this again.
Checking it on the front end is not a protection.
Users are able to read and edit your JavaScript code
in the end.
You can make it hard but you can't prevent this.
So it's important to do the sensible validation,
the sensible checks on your back end.
And, we do do this.
We do check in the messages JS file if the token is valid.
We do check here if the user who wants to edit something
is the user who created this message.
So these checks are key.
But then we also added them to the front end, like here,
to make sure that we provide a nice user experience,
and we don't see buttons which we shouldn't see.
With that our application really evolved quite a bit
and I really like the state of it.
Now I wanna conclude it in the next section
by adding error handling.
So that in the case I'm not logged in, whoops like this,
and then I hit this Save button.
I not only see
this error message
but instead I get a nice popup
informing me that I'm not logged in.
I need to login.
So let's do this in the next module.