Hi, welcome.
As you might be aware, Angular Two went from beta
to release candidate status right now and it will probably
be released soon.
Now, from beta to release candidate, there weren't too many
changes but some happened.
In this video, I want to guide you through all these
changes so that you are able, for example,
to use all my lectures or videos on Angular Two and apply
the knowledge there with the new release candidate.
Because, as I said, it's really easy to do.
To say the important thing first, all the content
is very up to date.
There are only three changes I want to talk
about in this video.
Two of them, only very very minor, and one, the router,
being a little bit bigger.
Let's start with the minor ones.
Here, I got a little example project and the first important
change is something you see right here at the top.
The naming of the package has changed.
In the background, the structure of the package has also
changed a little bit.
But for us here, only the name we have to use
when importing changed.
So now it's no longer angular2/core, for example,
but it's @angular/core.
So here at the bottom you can see an old import
and here at the top you see a recent one.
But if you exchange angular two for @angular,
you're good to go.
Now on this page, you can already see the router
which is by far the biggest change, though not
that difficult to get from the old router to the new router.
But I want to begin with another change.
NgFor.
Here the syntax changed.
The old syntax is this one with the hashtag.
The new one is to use let item of items, for example.
This still creates this local variable you can use
and the usage is completely the same.
It's just that you exchange hashtag for let here.
Now with those two changes out of the way, let's talk
about the biggest change- the router.
Here is an example router.
The old one with RouteConfig three routes
with names and so on.
Now in the individual routes, I have a subroute
in route two, indicated by the three dots here
and I'm passing a parameter to route three.
Now in route two, I definitely have other routes,
but already you can see the new syntax that we'll come
back to in a second.
In route three, I'm getting this pass parameter by injecting
RouteParams and then fetching it here through, well,
the RouteParams and then the get method.
Here are a couple of things which will change.
In the up component where I define my routes,
routes are no longer defined using RouteConfig,
but instead, by using the route's metadata.
Introduced by the @angular/router package.
So again, just exchanging angular two with @angular here.
So with this routes, its a new metadata which should
be used to set up routes.
The old router is still available
at @angular/router_depricated with a dash between.
But you should use the new one, in my opinion.
So this is the new way to set up routes
but it's not the only thing that changed here.
Also, routes no longer have names.
They are identified by the path which is unique, anyway,
therefore, names are gone.
Use as default currently, at the moment we record
this video, doesn't work but will probably be reintroduced
to work again.
But right now, routes are set up with path and component.
Another thing that changed is we no longer need the three
dots when having subrouting.
We can define this like any other route and Angular Two
will figure out that this route has routes, well,
within it in the component where this route leads to.
So this is how the router would be set
up in the app component.
I can get rid of this old import here.
Now, let's go to the route child components
where this route leads to.
The first component is a normal component.
There is nothing to change here.
Now, before I go to route two, I'm gonna go to
the router component which has the links.
This is how links were set up in the past, right?
You had an array where the first element was the name
of the route and the second an object with parameters
if you were to pass any.
That also changed.
The new way to use it is to use the paths of the routes
and the paths here, in this case,
are just route one, route two, route three.
I can leave out the leading slash here.
And then parameters can simply pass as additional arguments
in this or elements in this array.
So by adding one here, I am passing this as an ID
to route three since route three expects to get an ID here,
as set up in this app component.
So with this, I am setting up these route links
in the new way with the new syntax which is very similar
to the old one but now no longer using the names,
but instead the paths.
Notice that if I have slash route one, this is an absolute
route from the domain of this page.
If I want to have a relative one, I might use
dot slash, for example.
You can see this in route two component
where I have subrouting.
These are the routes set up here.
And here you can see that with the very first subroute,
I'm using dot slash to indicate that I want to use
this first route which is set up here which means it has
no path here so it should be the kind of default route
in this subroute here.
Right.
But if I were to use this as a path,
just as an empty stream,
that will lead me to the app component.
The route component.
So to this first component I see in the app.
In order to use a relative route, I use dot slash
which means stay on the same URL you're currently at.
Of course, I can add other things here
like subroute two, for example.
This will also lead me to subroute two which just means
seen from the current path or the current URL.
I hope this is clear.
Simply just that you have absolute and relative paths
you can specify here.
And really, you can navigate here like if you were
in a folder structure.
So in this route two component here,
this is just as subfolder of the overall router component
because I have a subrouter in the overall router.
This is how you have to think about it and then figuring
out the right paths to specify here
is really straightforward.
And in the end, it's just the paths you set up here
in your route's metadata.
So that was a lot of talking about router links
and how to get there.
But in the end, it's the old syntax,
just use the paths and not the names.
Now fetching parameters also changed.
We're no longer using RouteParams but instead now,
the RouteSegment.
Because Angular Two no longer knows RouteParams,
it only knows segments of a URL.
Segments not only means parameters but, well,
all the same.
Ones you might have in a URL.
But parameters are part of these segments, therefore,
to get a parameter, I now use my RouteSegment here,
and then I access it here.
RouteSegment has a method called getParam
and then it works like before.
You just pass the name off to parameter you want to get.
So really, not that different, just a, well, different
way of going there.
Not having a separate module for the parameters,
but instead, having one for the whole URL.
All of the segments in the URL.
That was a lot of talking.
Let's see this in action.
This is a running app.
Here you have to list with let instead of hashtag.
And then you have the different routes.
As you can see, I'm passing to parameter if I'm manually
changing this in the URL.
This still works.
Now I'm passing eight and the subroutes all to work,
as you can see, if I click on them.
So these are the changes Angular Two introduced
from beta to release candidate.
As you hopefully saw, it's not that difficult
to adjust your code.
I hope this video was helpful in this process.
See you in all the other videos.
Bye.