I do like the state of our application
but there's one thing I don't like.
If I'm not logged in and I try to save a message
I do get the error here, which is correct,
I am not logged in.
I'm not authorised to do this.
But it would be nice to get like a model here
which basically tells me the same thing
but in a nicer way, so that I don't have to check
the console which users of the website typically don't do.
While the same is true for other parts
of this application here,
let's say that we wanna sign up here
with an e-mail address which was already used.
Well, in this case, it would be nice to also get
an error in form of a model and not just this error
here on the right.
So these are just some improvements I want to do.
I want to handle these errors in a better way.
So in this module, we'll implement a better way
of handling these errors.