The way I want to handle errors
is here in my front-end I will create
a new feature, a new directory which I'll name errors.
I will have an error component
which holds the modal I want to show
and I will use the error service
to control when this modal should appear and when not.
I will also create an error model.
So, a file which defines how our error
should look like in the front end.
So let me create these files first.
This is an error component dot ts file for,
well, the component, you guessed it.
The error service dot ts file for
the service I'm going to use.
And the error model dot ts file
for the error model.
Well let's have the model first
since this is a key part.
Here I will export a class named error, for example.
And then I will use the short and quick way
of setting it up by defining the properties
here in the constructor by prepending them
with this access modifier, public or private.
So what should an error look like?
Well let's have a look at our back end.
How do the errors look like with fro?
Our errors here always have a title,
and then the actual error object.
So it does the case here and here, and always.
Now this of course allows me to now
go to my error model and set this object up in the same way.
So here I want to have a public title,
which is a string, and then I want to have
well, let's say a error object
which could be of type any.
Or since I also do know that all these
error objects on the back end
do have a message, I could also call this message.
Of course I will need to make sure
to extract this message from the error object.
As a side note, why do I know that on the back end,
this error object fro by mongoose
does have a message property?
Well simply by inspecting it or
reading it in the documentation.
So this will have a message, and all my
custom errors like this one here
also do have this message property.
So I can extract the message,
and this is what I wanna use in my model here.
This is the basic setup I wanna use.
With this, I can next work on the component
to create a nice modal I wanna display
when a error occurs.