Let's create this modal
I want to show in case of an error.
Here in my component.ts file,
I will export a class named ErrorComponent.
Now this class here, of course, needs to get
the ComponentDecorator imported from @angular/core.
Now how should this look like?
It needs a selector, I'll name it app-error.
You, of course, can choose any selector you want.
It also needs a template,
and I will create a new file for this:
the error.component.html file
to outsource this template.
So let's reference this template here
by adding templateUrl,
which should point
to the error.component.html file like this.
Now how should the component
or the html code here look like?
Well, I need a backdrop in the back
which greys out the background, and then the actual modal,
and I will use the Bootstrap modal for this.
Now you can basically just copy that code
from the Bootstrap webpage, so let's head over
to getbootstrap.com, and under JavaScript here,
you will find the modal.
Now we won't use the JavaScript Bootstrap offers us,
I'm only interested in the HTML and CSS code here.
We will hook up the rest on our own.
So let's copy this in here.
This generally is all fine.
Though, I also need to add the backdrop,
so let's add a class named backdrop.
I will create this class on my own.
It's not a Bootstrap class.
This is the backdrop I conditionally want to show or hide,
as well as the modal, so that the background is grey.
Now this setup here is fine for now.
I will, of course, remove these data-dismiss things
because I won't let Bootstrap handle this.
I don't even have the Bootstrap JavaScript code
to handle this, so I will need to add
my own on-click listeners here.
And now let's think about
which data I want to output in this modal.
And I also want to delete the save changes button.
There are no changes to be saved.
But this is the general setup of this modal.
The two things I want to do now is,
I want to configure my own backdrop,
this custom class here, and then I want
to output some data here, which of course,
first I need to create as a property in my TypeScript file.
So let's do this here.
I will create a new property named error,
which is of type error, so my error
I created here from the error.model file.
This initially is undefined.
I also will setup another property,
which decides on whether this should be displayed or not.
So I will name it displayed, and set it
to a string named none, or the value of none.
I will then use this with the ng-style directive later on
to change the display of the modal
from block to none, and the other way around.
So now this gives me these two valuable properties.
As I just said, I also need to define the styles.
I could outsource them, but I will write them inline here
with back ticks,
I can write a multi-line string here, of course,
and then I already prepared this class,
which I'm copying in here.
So this class simply gives it a nice grey background,
a bit transparent, and then fixed position
and spans it over the full window width and height.
This will be the modal background.
With this setup here, we're not yet getting the error,
but we're able to finish this component.
We've got the style of the backdrop,
and we've got the displayed property,
which we can use together with ng-style
to change the display style of the modal,
and the error to output data.
So back in the html code, let's use this.
First, here on the backdrop,
I will add the ng-style directive with property binding,
like this.
And here, the style I want to change is display.
This is a normal CSS style, of course,
and I want to set it to display.
And let's change this property name to display
to be in line here, so to display.
I can now copy this and also add this to my modal,
which I also only want to show while it should be shown.
And with that in place,
I can now output the error title here
and the modal title with string interpolation.
So let's access error, and then ?.title
because I don't know if the error is set.
It is undefined at the beginning.
And since I will place this modal
in my code right from the start,
because remember I'm not attaching or detaching it
with ng-if, I'm showing or hiding it with ng-style,
so it will always be there.
Since this is the case, I need this question mark
because we might simply not have gotten an error yet,
in which case, I certainly want to get an error
from the error model because we don't have an error,
that is really kind of stupid.
So this the error title, and then here in the body,
of course, I want to output the error message
also with a question mark to avoid any nasty errors.
The last thing I want to configure here
is this close button,
so either the X, if that has been clicked,
or the close button itself.
Here I'll have a click-listener and execute onErrorHandled,
a method I have yet to create.
So let me copy it here and also add it to this button.
This sets up the template of my modal.
The last step for me is to,
for now, to add this
onErrorHandled method here,
and in here,
I simply want to switch display back to none.
We don't have code to switch to anything else right now.
This will follow soon, but with this I make sure
that the modal disappears once we close it.
Now to prepare this for usage,
I will add it to my app component,
because again, I will always have it here.
I will always have my error component around,
I just switch its display style.
So I will append it here:
app-error is the selector of my error component here,
and for this to work, I also need to add it
to my app module, the ErrorComponent.
Also make sure to add the import up here.
With this setup, the error component is added.
If I save it and recompile my code,
we can see this kind of, if I reload the application.
We can see it if we inspect the HTML code here,
that at the very end we get this app-error element,
though of course, we don't see it
because the display is set to none.
I can switch this to block though,
so now we see the backdrop, at least.
But this is not really how it should work, right?
So let's make sure to setup the error service next,
so that we're actually able to emit errors and handle them.