We created and added our error component.
Now it's time to also configure our error service
to make this work, and to allow us to actually pass errors,
emit them, and show this error model.
The error service will be really lean.
It's exported class name named error service, of course.
And in here, I will have a new property named
error occurred, for example.
You may choose any name you like, and this will be
at event emitter, which of course therefore
needs to be imported
from at angular core.
This will emit an error, which therefore also needs
to be imported from error model.
And I want to emitted whenever this handle error method
in this service is called.
So here,
I will get an error, I'll type any actually,
because it may have different formats.
But then I can say that, let's say I will create
a new error data constant here.
I will create a new error based on my own model
on this fronted model, and here, I then know
I will be able to extract a title from each error,
because this is how my errors are set up in the backend.
They always have a title.
And they always have an error object, which then in turn,
happens to always have a message object.
All indicates here of the mongoose error.
So therefore, as the message, I can extract error,
and then this looks strange, but error, and then message
to access this error object in the error object.
That allows me then to call this error occurred
emit, and pass my error data as an argument.
Now this emits this event, now I'm able to subscribe to it
in error places and call handle error in some components,
when an error appears, to now get this error
from the component where it appears to,
well, the app component where I want to display my error.
To make this work, I will go to app module,
and I need to provide the error service application
wide because I want to be able to admit and to subscribe
to errors from all over my application.
So time to add the error service here,
also add the import, of course, and with this,
I'm able to use it application wide.