The fist place where I wanna use
this error service is in the error component.
Here I want to listen to emitted events
and errors, therefore.
So, I will implement OnInit to set up this listener.
OnInit needs to be imported from @angular/core,
and it requires me, of course, to implement ngOnInit.
So, in here, what I want to do is I want to listen to this
error occurred event emitter in my error service.
So, I need to inject the error service for this.
I can do this since I provide it application-wide,
so this will work fine.
And then in here, I can simply call this error service
error occurred subscribe to any errors we might get.
So, let me just restructure this,
and then in here, we could get an error,
and we actually know that this will be of type error,
like this, and then I wanna do two things here.
First, of course, I want to set this error
in my component here equal to the error we get passed,
and second, I want to set this display equal to block
to now show the modal and the backdrop.
So, this will do that.
Now, of course, that I listen to it
I also need to submit the error, or emit it.
Now, I wanna do this in the services.
So, here in the message service,
where I get a couple of places
where that error could happen,
so basically, in each catch function,
I will also inject the error service.
I can do this since @Injectable was added.
So now, let's add the error service here,
and of course, also add the import up here.
And then, it's here in the catch functions
where I wanna work with that.
I want to write more than just one line.
I will still throw the observable,
because I still need to return an observable here.
This needs to have a return statement
in front of it, though.
I still need this,
because this is observable overall here,
still expects to return an observable.
I can't leave this away just because I handled my error.
But now, I not only want to throw those
which I can lock to the console or not,
depending on my choice,
but I also now want to handle it with my error service.
This is the main thing.
This is why I built this.
So, here I call handle error,
and I pass my error JSON,
so this extracted error data, into it.
So, this is the cool thing about this catch function.
It allows me to run my own code before then of course
continuing with the default error flow here.
So, this setup here, I can basically copy it,
will be used in every catch block here.
This allows me to now handle the errors in a different way
to show my own error to display my modal
through this error service.
The same is true for the auth service.
Let's also inject the error service here,
like this.
Make sure to add the import at the top here, too.
And then again, simply replace it with the catch code
from before to handle the errors,
like this.
And, we're done.
Now, let it recompile.
If it froze in error, basically you restart it.
Sometimes it has this,
not finding a newly treated file here.
So, once this runs, let's reload this application,
and let's try to create a new message
whilst not being logged in.
Well, we do get the backdrop, but the modal is missing.
Let's see what went wrong here.
Let's have a look at the error component.
It's one little issue here.
We need to remove this fade clause,
otherwise it tries to fade it in,
which will work with bootstraps code,
but not with mine.
So, remove this, and thereafter,
after reloading this,
and, I can close the console.
Let's try it again.
Now, we see our error and then the error message,
in this case thrown by the jwt package
that we must provided.
And of course, you can feel free to make these nicer,
but you see it works.
It can also close it.
Now, what happens if I try to sign up a user
with a email address which is already taken?
User validation failed.
Well, of course, you could also improve that.
So, it is true, of course, the validation failed,
because we have a email address we already use,
but you see, the general output is working just fine.
And here, if I enter some data which doesn't exist,
invalid login credentials.
Great.
So, this is error handling in place,
and it was the final step in this application.
We now really have a nice-looking, user-friendly application
using Angular 2 on the front end and Node.js and Express
and MongoDB on the back end.
With that, we achieved a lot.
You learned how to set up the front end part,
how to connect it to the back end,
how to connect it to Node.js,
how to add user sign up and sign in,
how to protect your routes on the back end,
how to show or hide things on the front,
and depending on the user login state,
and on how to display errors in a user-friendly format.
This is a lot, and I hope you thoroughly enjoyed the course.
Now, in the next sections I will show you how to set up
this seed project we used here on your own
and how to deploy this application.
So, happy to see you there.