So at this point of time
you got a refresher on Node.js.
You know how our general application works,
how our files are getting served,
and how we route in Node.js.
You also got a refresher in MongoDB
and learned how to store data
in the Mongo database.
We also, and that is important for
the rest of this course and this
application we're building here.
We also set up our models here in the models folder.
We're going to use them in later modules
in this course to save our messages and users
when we then create them Y Angular 2 to the database.
Speaking of Angular 2, we haven't
seen much of that, have we?
Now in this module it's finally time
to get to the point and use Angular 2.
Now this module here, we'll set up
the whole front end of our application
and I will use it to also repeat
some of the concepts we're using
throughout this module and some of
the core concepts of Angular 2, therefore.
If you feel like that's not enough
and you need more Angular 2 knowledge,
I definitely recommend diving in a dedicated course.
With that, let's get started and let's learn
how we can actually start our Angular 2 application
through our Node.js application
which you've built thus far.