The first thing I'm going to do
is, in the views folder, I'll
get rid of the node.hbs folder.
I don't need that anymore.
And in the route folder in the app.js file,
I also need to tune this, this set up here
is not the one I'll use throughout
the rest of the course.
Instead, what I want to do here
and this is an important part
because this explains how our Angular 2 application
gets started through express or through Node.js.
We will only return one view through Node.js,
because Angular 2 allows us to
create single page applications.
And as this says, a single page application
only uses a single page.
Therefore, the job our Node.js back end here
is first, to render this single page
and then Angular 2 takes over.
And second, it needs to provide certain hooks
or routes for Angular 2 to which Angular 2
later is able to reach out to store
messages, fetch messages, because all these
are tasks done by our back end.
Now in this module, we'll not
work on these routes, we'll not
work on the back end again.
Let's only render the Angular 2 application for now.
I'll do this here in my get method,
the router get method here, in the routes app.js file.
And I will get rid of everything besides
the res.render function here.
Here, I will still render something,
but I will render the index hbs file
and I won't pass any arguments to it.
Just like this.
This will be the single page I want to render.
Therefore I can also delete this post route here.
And we don't need the user model here anymore.
So this is how we'll set up the routes
on our back end for now.
Now with that route being rendered to our front end
or to our client, let's have a look
at the index hps file.
It's very lean as you can see.
It's a basic HTML5 skeleton.
I'm importing bootstrap here to get
some basic styling, and then here
my own style sheet which lives
in the public style sheets folder,
just to have some global styling for the application.
I prepared this before starting this course,
and it'll hold some styling which
we'll use throughout the course.
Besides that, all we have is this
strange my app thing here, and then
our script here where I import
a bundle.js file from js/app/bundle.
We can see this here.
This will be our bundle Angular 2 application,
and responsible for the bundling is webpack
which I'll use as a, well, builder here
to monitor changes and to rebuilt
our application and so on.
So this is what will, in the end,
hold our application, and my app here
this seems to be related to our application.
But I'll come back to this in the next video
when I explain how the Angular 2 application starts.
For now, I just wanted to highlight how it gets served,
and this is how it gets served.
This single file, which holds everything
our Angular 2 application needs to start,
and then take over on the front end.