Before having a look at how
the Angular 2 application starts, there is
one important thing to know.
Angular 2 uses components.
An Augular 2 application is created
from multiple components.
So, this would be a typical Angular 2 application.
We might have a header, a main section
with model items and and let's say a sidebar.
All of that will sit on a root component.
So, if you have a look at this picture
or this image here, I think it makes sense
that you can think of basically any
web page you know to consist of
mode components, and since this is
the case, Angular 2 uses this concept
to split up your code into multiple
pieces, modules, so called components,
of which you build your application.
The great thing is, you of course can,
you don't have to, but of course you can,
reuse your components.
And, why is this also useful?
Because each component is contain
piece of code which contains a template,
so, html code, which will be displayed
in the browser in the end.
But, also a class, which holds
the lodging of this component.
Let's say what should happen the user clicks a button,
if user enters a value into input field, and so on.
The class which holds the logic is hooked up to
the template which holds the html code via databinding.
Of course, you will see this in this course.
We also get a lifecycle each component follows through.
So, Angular 2 creates it, destroys it, updates it.
All of that makes components very powerful
and why Angular 2 uses this concept
to create your application.
We'll see this in action throughout the course.
Let's now first start by actually starting
our Angular 2 application and see how this works.