So in the last video, we had a look at this
in HBS file, and I explained that this is the single file
getting served through our server,
and which is responsible for loading
our Angular 2 application, and this is true.
However, what does this file do, how is the Angular 2
application getting started, now that we serve this file
to the client?
We have this my app loading thing, and below this
strange element here, which clearly is not
a built-in HTML file element,
we import our script, our bundle.js file here,
which I told you holds our application.
So since this is the only script we're importing,
it looks like this script holds everything we need.
It holds everything we develop in this assets app folder,
plus the Angular 2 framework itself and the one
where all the code off the framework we used at least,
not code we don't use.
In this folder, we see a couple of files,
some app component files, app module,
two main files, the main.aot file, will ignore that for now.
It is related to optimising our application later
when we're building it for production,
and a polyfills.ts file.
Now, let's start with the polyfills.ts file.
It simply imports some, well, polyfills we'll need
for our application to run, and, well, basically all of this
up here is that we do import the polyfills we need
so that later when the application runs, it runs fine
on multiple browsers.
The important file for us, though, is the main.ts file.
This is the file where not only import these polyfills,
it also is the file where I bootstrap the application,
which means where I start the Angular 2 application.
You don't see it in the index.hbs file,
but the main.ts file, or the code in the main.ts file,
is the code which actually gets executed first
when we import this bundle here in the index.hbs file.
So, in this main.ts file, what are we doing?
Well, I'm importing two things: the platform browser dynamic
package from Angular 2, and my app module,
which lives in this app module file,
which I'll come back in a second.
And then I bootstrap this application by passing the app
module as an argument.
This is how you start up an Angular 2 application,
you have to bootstrap it.
You basically have to tell the framework, "Hey, here you go.
"Here's the new application", and I'm doing it
with this line.
Again, remember this is the first code
which will get executed.
So we somehow now kickoff our Angular 2 application,
but what happens in this app module which we seem to pass
as an argument, or which we're passing as an argument,
which seems to be important?
In this app module, I tell Angular 2 what my application
consists of.
Angular 2 has this concept of using modules
to possibly split other applications,
though you don't have to do this, you can also use
only one module, and for a lot of smaller to medium
sized applications, you will, but no matter if you split
it up or not, in this module, I define
what am I going to use in my application?
Which built-in modules which I might use
and/or which I might state in my imports area here?
Which custom components or directives or pipes
which I build throughout the application?
Of course, you will see this in this course.
Which of them add to the declarations area here?
Right now, we only have one component,
but this will grow throughout the course.
And then, in the bootstrap area, we tell Angular 2,
of all the things my application consists of,
and right now, it's only the app component and the
browser module here, but of all these things,
which component should be my root component,
which is responsible for holding my application,
what should be my root component which will hold
all my other applications, so basically, what should be
the component which you are aware of when starting off
the application, and you is Angular 2?
And here, this is the app component.
Now if we have a look at the app.component.ts file
which seems to hold this component,
then we see it's very lean too.
We got a empty class with no content.
But this class has the @component selector attached to it.
And this creates a component, it makes this normal
typescript class a component now.
Angular 2 works with components a lot.
You create your whole application from multiple components
so you put your application together by using
multiple components, and here, we create such a component.
A component can be set up very easy and lean as you see.
Here, we only set it up by passing the object,
which holds a selector, my-app,
and the URL to the template.
Each component needs to have a template
because a component will be something which in the end,
gets placed on the DOM, which gets rendered to the client
in the browser, therefore it needs to have some HTML code.
As you might tell, the HTML code lives in this app component
HTML file, this file here.
But before having a look at this file, let's have a look
at the my-app selector first.
Do you recognise this selector?
We saw it here in the index.hbs file, here.
So as we told Angular 2 in the app module, that we want
to start our application, with this app component in mind.
Angular 2 went to this app component file, had a look
at the component declaration here, and saw that the
selector of this component is my-app,
and it recognised the selector in the index.hbs file.
And therefore, it was able to place our content
in the place of this my-app element, which leads to us
seeing the content of the HTML file here,
app.component.html when we visit our page.
Well, let's see this in action by running mpm start
and also starting our build process, mpm run build,
which starts webpeg, bundles everything, and keeps
watching for changes so that it recompiles
whenever we change something, and if we then head
over to the browser, we see Hello World,
which is the content of this app component HTML file.
So this is how the Angular 2 application gets started
using our component to display the content
off this component on our page,
and we will work with this and add new components
add-ons to this application, which then will all get placed
in our root component, or nested in other components,
but not in the index.hbs file.
We're not gonna work on this file anymore.
This is how it starts the application,
and this is all we do in this file, that's important.