Now all the things you are seeing here,
are contained in an object,
or are properties of an object,
which is passed as an argument to @NgModule thing here.
Now this thing is a decorator,
decorator is a types group feature,
which allows us to attach some additional information
to a class.
As you can see, the class is totally empty,
there are no properties or methods inside of it.
So this class becomes more than just an empty class,
by adding this decorator.
You'll see this same concept throughout angular2 ,
for example when we use components,
which you'll learn about in a second.
We pass arguments to this NgModule decorator,
and in the background angular2 will use these arguments,
to store it, you could think of,
and then know that whenever we use the AppModule class,
it is more than an empty class.
It is configured with the info we set up here
in the @NgModule decorator.