If we have a look at our application,
it's clearly nice;
it displays Hello World,
but, it's not really doing anything.
We're not seeing anything dynamic.
Now back in our editor,
or the editor of your choice,
you should have the webpack process still running
by running npm run bolt.
It should keep running
here in your terminal window.
And then
you can go to,
let's say the AppComponent es file
and now let's create a new property
in this TypeScript class.
A new property is simply created
by typing a name here,
like a variable,
but without var at the beginning.
So content, and then let's say,
Some content.
Assign a string as a value.
You can assign any value you want.
Now back in the AppComponent html file,
we want to output this new content.
And do you remember the slide
where I told you that
we have the content in our body here;
and the content in our template,
which we can connect via data binding?
Let's use one form of data binding:
string interpolation.
We've got four forms,
and you will see them all throughout this course,
but let's start with string interpolation,
which is the most common one, probably.
String interpolation works by using
double curly braces, opening and closing,
and in between here, you can output
any property or result of a method,
or anything else from your component class.
So, from within here.
I want to output my content,
so what I simply can write here is,
content.
And this will output my component content.
Now upon saving this,
the code will re-compile,
and if we then reload the application,
you see, some content, here.
This is how easy it is
to make our application dynamic
and to output things or content
from our component class
from our business logic, so to say, in our template.
Now you can maybe already imagine
how easy it will later on be
to also hook up a button here,
and change this content
and dynamically update everything,
without having to write complicated code
to manually select what to update, and so on.
This is what makes Angular2 so powerful.
But, that's just the beginning.
And, before diving deeper into these tiny examples,
let's go back to our overall application,
and work on that.
Let's start building this application.