In the end of the course,
I wanna have an application of where we are able
to login, log out and so on, and create messages
as well as edit or delete them.
Well, we're not going to write all them
this video, but let's start with the messages part.
I'll get rid of the hello world
and content figures so that the app component
HTML file is totally empty.
And then in here, I want to set up
some bootstrap styling.
Now, for this styling to work,
I will first create the outermost bootstrap
class and container and I use emit here
as a plugin which allows me to create
classes like this by hitting tab then.
And in here I want to have a row,
let's saw with col-md-8, and some offsetting
so this is all just some bootstrap styling.
The bootstrap css framework has nothing to do
with Angular 2, just to give this a nice grid
and position it nicely.
Now in here, I want to create such a message.
And of course later on we will fill this
with some life and make this more dynamic.
For now I'll hard code everything.
So here I want to have an article
which uses the bootstrap panel class
and their panel default, again just to
give this a nice bootstrap styling.
And if you want to learn more about
available bootstrap styles, visit getbootstrap.com
and here you can browse all available
components and things.
So in this article here, I'll now create
a panel body like this, where I want to
output the content of my message.
And below I'll have a footer, of class panel footer.
And here I want to output, let's say
some info about the author.
I'll assign a class author which is
a custom class I'll create.
And in here, a class config, which is also
a custom class.
And then I want to have two anchor tags
where I say edit and let's say delete.
Of course I will hook them up later on.
Now to all the output something,
let's go back to the app component file
and let's create a new message object here,
a new property.
Message, which is a JavaScript object,
and in here let's say we have a content
where we say a message and then we might have
an author which is Max.
Of course choose your favourite name and content.
And in the component then using string interpolation
as we saw before, we can output content.
Oops, the other way around.
Name it message and there content
and here the author.
So message author.
If I save this, I didn't do anything else
than before, I used string interpolation
and I also used some bootstrap classes.
In the running application if we reload,
you should see something like this.
It already looks nice, but I would like to have
a different styling.
I want to have the author here on the left
and the edit and delete button on the right.
Now I could achieve this with built-in
bootstrap classes, but I also want to show you
how we can apply styles to a component
in Angular 2 which can only apply to this component
and to no other part in the application.
We can do this by adding a new property
to our at component decorator here.
In here, what I can do is, I can add styles.
Which is just another view to configure
this component, and this takes an array.
In here, I can set up all the styles
I want to only apply to this component.
So if I style H1 tag here, you use
normal css styling, then you will only style
all H1 tags in this component,
and in no other component in the application.
Angular 2 will make sure that they
only get applied to elements in
the template of this component,
which is a very powerful feature.
Now in this styles array you create
a multi-line string because we have to
pass a string here.
I use back ticks which allows me to do just that.
You write over multiple lines here
while still having a string and
not getting any errors.
I will paste in some prepared styles,
which basically just turned these elements
to block elements, and then will
position them as I want them to be positioned.
With this styling, if I now save this
so that everything recompiles and then
I reload my application,
well once it finished recompiling here.
You see now it is evenly positioned
or it is positioned the way I want it
to be positioned, and the important takeaway is
if we now would use the author class
in any other place of the application,
and you can try this out,
you will see that it won't get these styles
because these are now limited to
the scope of this component.