So our application now looks like this.
Much better already.
We're getting closer to the goal of creating
a messenger here or to creating an app
where we can create messages.
Now, the content is still very static, though.
Yes, we dynamically outputted in the template,
but we're not able to change it, are we?
Well, we'll make this really dynamic later on,
but let's already improve this a little bit.
Let's learn about another way of data binding in Angular 2,
two-way data binding.
Right now, I'm using string interpolation to output data.
Now it would be great if you could also dynamically set it.
So let's add a simple input field up here.
It doesn't have too much styling,
just a simple input like that.
And now I want to hook up this input
or whatever we type here to the content of this message
so that we ourselves can change the content of this message.
Nothing easier than that.
Angular 2 offers us nice syntax
for this form of data binding.
We use square brackets,
and then inside of these square brackets, parentheses,
and then inside of here, ngModel.
Now, this might look strange, what it basically allows us
to do is, it allows us to bind this input here,
to any property we zip up between the quotation marks here.
So don't use curly braces here,
you only use it for string interpolation.
Here, simply type the property to which you want to bind.
In my case, this is message content.
Now what this all does is, it tells Angular 2
whenever I type something in the input,
store it in message.content, and whenever a message.content
gets changed somewhere else, or at the beginning of this
application is simply initialised, all the output, it ask
the value in this input.
This is why it's called two-way data binding.
It works in both directions.
We can change it, and we can see it there.
It will also affect message.content wherever else we use it
in this application.
Now in order to use it,
we also have to add it to app.module
We specifically, we have to import another built-in module.
Right now, we're only importing the browser module,
which contains some basic things we need for a browser
application that we built with Angular 2.
Now, we also need the forms module because this happens
to be the built-in module, a module Angular 2 ships with,
which offers us access to this ngModel thing we're using.
So if I save this, and you also need to import this from
@angular/forms as you can see here,
so if I add this and then I save my application
to let it recompile,
if I then reload the application, you now see
we got this new input field,
which automatically also displays a message.
Keep in mind, nowhere am I using
string interpolation related to this input.
So this message we see here, clearly comes from
this ngModel here.
So now with that set up, watch the message below
in the panel if I start changing this.
Do you see this?
Now we're dynamically changing the content
through Angular 2's two-way data binding.
Now, of course, this is not really how the application
will work in the end.
We want to have a clean input field, which we can submit
upon clicking a button and not change it all the time
we type something here, also we will later on
have multiple messages.
But if we will all use this concept again,
and I want you to understand how the data works Angular 2,
and how we can make it flow from the template
to the component class, and back to the template,
like we're doing right now.