Now even though we're still early
in the application,
we already know where we'll kind of end up in the end.
We know it since we set up our models
in the MongoDB section in this course, message and user.
We'll have a message part where we can create,
edit and delete messages,
and we'll have the authorization or user part,
where we are able to create users,
sign up so to say, or sign in with users.
We should also reflect that on our front end.
It would be great to have some models there, too,
because we can't use our back-end models
in our Angular 2 application.
We can't access them here.
We will later on reach out to the back end
to fetch data and store data,
but we're not able to use the properties
of these models here to validate our front-end input
and so on, or not that easy, at least.
So to do this, I want to create these same models here
on the front end,
to basically have a blueprint to work with on the front end
so that I know a message will have these fields,
a user will have these fields,
and also some additional fields, as you will learn.
So let's create two new files in the app folder here.
A message.ts file, or let's name it message.model.ts,
and a user.model.ts file.
These types of files will hold some classes,
which simply define,
how a message and a user should look like,
so that when we use a message
like we do here in the AppComponent,
we have a clear blueprint and a message looks the same
throughout our application, no matter where we use it.
So how should a message look like?
Well, it should be a class which we export
so that we can use it outside of this file, too.
And I'll name it "Message" with a capital M.
And in here, I want to have a content,
which will be of type: string.
And this is how you assign a type with TypeScript,
the property name, then a colon, and then the string.
And now this property is limited to this type.
You can't use a different type now,
or you will get an error.
But it not only have a content of a message,
I also will have an author, or let's say username here,
the username of the person who created this message.
This will also be a string.
Now that would theoretically be all I need,
but my model should have two other things
which will make managing my messages later on easier.
Later on, when I'm able to edit and delete my messages,
I will need to pass some information back to the server
when I click the delete button on the front end.
The info which I need to pass to the server is,
what was the ID of the message which got deleted?
Identifying the message by content is dangerous,
because if I have two messages with the same content,
I wouldn't know which one to delete.
Therefore, I later on also want
to store the ID of my message,
which will also be a string since MongoDB creates IDs
which are strings and not numbers.
And there's another thing.
I also want to store the user ID.
I shouldn't have duplicated usernames,
but it is possible because I will not control that,
I will only make sure that I have unique email addresses.
So I might have two users
with the same username creating a message.
Now, if I want to know if a user is able
to delete a message,
I want to check if he was the one who created it.
Now using a username is dangerous
because it's not unique, as I just explained.
So I also want to store the user ID
of the person who created a message,
so that I know if I should show the delete button or not.
And I come back to this later on.
But this will be the four fields I want to use
on my front end with the logic I just explained.
Now, to be able to initialise this,
I'll also add a constructor,
that's the default constructor,
the TypeScript class it ship with,
or which we can also use in all types of classes,
and here I want to be able to pass my content,
my username, so basically the same fields as before.
And I'll show a quicker way of setting this up in a second.
So this is my messages model.
Here of course I need to assign this.content to content,
this.username to username, and so on.
So let me quickly do this.
With this setup, I'm able to create messages,
and also able to then have a unique blueprint
how a message should look like
in my whole front-end application.
Now how should the user model look like?
Let's have a look at it.
Of course it'll also be exported class User,
and in here now I'll use a quick array
of setting up all these fields.
I can use a shortcut TypeScript offers me,
where I can directly set up properties
and assign the values in the constructor.
So do the same as here in the message model,
but with only one line of code instead of 10.
So here in my user model,
let's think about what fields should a user have.
Well, here I want to stick to the fields I set up
on the back end, so in my models file,
we see a user has a first name, a last name,
a password and an email.
The messages are something I'll not store
in my user model on the front end,
because I will fetch that differently as you will learn.
So in the user model here,
I want to have an email which should be of type: string.
Now this would be the approach we used before.
It's getting passed as an argument to the constructor.
If I want to tell TypeScript, "Hey,
"this should also be a property of this class
"and please assign the value automatically,"
then I simply add public or private in the beginning
to make it a public or private property.
And now I have the same as if I would have written,
public email or omit public since it is the default,
email: string, and then in here,
this string, this.email equals, oops, equals email,
like this.
So I can omit all of that,
and by simply placing it in the constructor here
as an argument with public in front of it,
I get the same result.
Now I do the same for the password,
which should be a string,
and I'll split it up over multiple lines
since this will get a bit longer.
I also want to have my firstName, which will be a string,
and I will also have my lastName, which will be a string,
like this.
Now there's one important thing.
When I create users or when I use users,
I will not always have all four fields.
I will only use the first and last name
when I create a user in this application,
not really if I only sign in with a user later on.
Therefore, I will make first and lastName optional
by adding a question mark.
This now means, you can pass these arguments,
but you don't have to.
The properties will then just be undefined.
Because for signing in, I only need the email and password,
and I don't want to force the user
to enter more info than I need.
This is why I make these fields optional.
With that, we added these models to the front end,
and that now gives us a clear blueprint,
which we can use to make our application more structured,
and make sure we're using everything we need to use,
or we're working in a consistent way.
The same is true of my message model.
Message ID and user ID should be optional.
I won't always have that.
So let me make it optional here,
and of course also in the constructor,
so that I'm not required to pass them.
And with that, I set up a nice, basic setup,
which gives me the blueprints I'll work with
throughout the application,
to be able to work with messages and users.