Now as we can see our app folder is
already getting pretty crowded and it's a good practise
to structure your project.
You want to create sub-folders to keep your project clean
and keep the possibility to quickly navigate and see
what is located where and so on.
Now how do you structure Angular2 project?
It's a good practise to structure it by feature.
So I will not create a folder named models
and then a folder named components, like this.
This is not how you should structure it.
This will quickly get it unmaintainable
and hard to understand once it grows.
Instead structure it by feature.
So here we'll have a messages feature
and we'll also have a off feature,
so user related stuff.
With that I can move my messages model to the
messages folder and the user model to the off folder.
I'll keep the other files in the app folder
but these will be the only files I have there pretty much.
All other components and so on, which I'll soon create,
will go into sub-folders too.
So here in the app folder, in the root folder there,
I only want to have files which are related to the
start up of the application, really to the root application.
All other things will go into sub-folders.