Now speaking of structuring the application
in my app component HTML file in this template
I get my message.
Right now that's all the content my application has
but this will change in the next videos,
and I will create multiple features and things
and also the message part can be split up
into multiple components if you look at it like this.
I at least see a message component here.
This article, this would be a great component.
So let's go to the messages folder
and create a new component there.
Here I want to create a message component
and I will store in a message.component TS file.
Now why I do name this file like this?
Because in angular two it's a good convention
to have the name of what's inside there as the first thing
in the name, in the file name, and then the second part
in the file name, component in this case here,
should describe what's in the file.
So the feature is a message
but the thing in this file is a component.
So with that I save this and now it will go to my app
component and copy all that code here including the input,
which I'll delete in a second anyways, into my message
component, though not in the message component TS file
but instead let's create a new html file,
message component html.
So we get the types group file for the business lodging
so to say and the html file for template.
I'll get rid of the input
and now I have my message in there.
Now of course my message component TS
file certainly needs to grow a little bit.
That's not all I want to have here.
Instead here I want to export a class which I'll name
message component like that and then make, let's make this
a component, and you learned how to make it a component.
We add the at component decorator like this.
Make sure to import it from at angular core.
Here we need to pass a JavaScript object configuring
this component.
I want to have a selector and now here this is important.
How do you choose a good selector name?
The selector works like a CSS selector,
so it could use hashtag something to select any element
which has an ID of something, like you select via CSS.
But typically you use the element style, so, but to select
the element like this or simply here, looking like that.
Something of course isn't a built
in element so I created my own one with that.
However you wanna make sure that
you have a unique selector here.
You don't accidentally want to overwrite something.
So if I were to choose H1 well I would override
all H1 elements, certainly not what I want.
Or if I would choose something else which a third party
package I use might also use that would also be bad.
So prefix it with something which makes it unique.
That could be app or my.
Now here I will use app and then message
and this allows me to use app message to insert
this component into my code.
Of course, I also need to point to my template URL,
and here write dot slash to make this a relative path
and then point to message component html.
With this set up I get my basic component
and now the thing left is to hook it up in my app
component which remember is my route component.
I will add all other components to my app component,
not to the index hps file, in which you won't find them
there because it only knows how to start this app component.
Remember, we're telling it here in the boot strap array.
So instead we need to add it here in the app component now.
So here I simply enter app message which is the selector
adjusts it up to render this new component in this route
component which will hold my entire application.
Though there's one thing missing.
If I do it like this, it would not work,
because angular two would still not
be aware of the message component.
By default it doesn't scan all your files for selectors
which is great because that would
really be a performance hit.
Instead we have to make it aware of our new component,
and we just do so in the app module file.
Remember that I told you that here we would register
everything which makes up our application?
The message component is one of these
things which make up our application.
So we have to edit here in the declarations array
which is the place where you add all new components
or directives or pipes you want to use.
Here I will add the message component
and you also need to add the import to the messages
slash message dot component file.
Without a file extension, that's important,
you always create these imports without a file extension.
With this in place let's save this,
and this should trigger the rendering of the application,
and then if we go over to the application and reload it
you now see the message again but the input field is gone,
and all the content of course.
And all of these buttons are back on the left.
I'll work on the contents soon
but let's first edit the styling.
The styling is missing because
it's set up here in the app component here.
I explained it belongs to the component where we set it up
and even though message component is a child component
of app component, that are a lot of components,
because we set it up here in the app component template.
It still is contained to the app component.
It's not working this way that it
would travel down the child route.
Note, it still only belongs to the app component,
so if we want to move this styling over to the message
component, I have to cut it here and insert it here,
and with this if I reload the application after rendering,
after re-rendering you see now that it moved over there.
So the styling is back,
but of course the content is still missing.
Now we could fix this by simply copying this message
property over to the message component
but I don't want to do this.
I'll show you a different way and with that the last forms
of data binding in the next videos.