We learned about string interpolation
to out put data with these curly braces,
and two-way data data binding with
these squared brackets and parentheses.
Now, maybe you wondered where these squared
brackets and parentheses were coming from.
Well, they are coming from property and event binding,
which are the last two forms of
data binding Angular 2 offers us.
Property binding looks like this.
We bind to a property, and that could be
a property of a default HTML element,
like the value property on a input,
or it could be the property on our own component,
as you will learn in the next videos.
So we bind to the property and enclose it
in squared brackets to tell Angular 2,
"Hey, we want to bind to this property."
And then between the quotation marks,
we have expression, resolving two a value,
which we want to pass to this property.
This could be a string, because
maybe we want to pass a string.
This could be a number, or this could be a method
call returning something which we want to pass.
So if we want to bind to the value of a property,
then we would pass the value or the string
which you want to bind in the quotation marks.
Event binding is the opposite.
Here we use parentheses and we enclose
the event to which to which you want to bind.
Click, for example.
And in the expression, or between
the quotation marks, we have the expression,
which gets executed whenever this event occurs.
This can be a method call, but it could also be
a short assignment directly between the quotation marks,
something like ="true".
So, to what can we bind?
As I said, to DOM properties.
So, HTML elements, properties of HTML elements,
like value, hidden, and much more.
To directive properties.
We will see directives in action soon,
but directives are simply just instructions in the document.
They are a feature of Angular 2
which allow to manipulate the document,
and they may have properties to which you bind.
You will see this throughout the course.
And to component properties. Components are directives,
but with a template, as you learned.
And we can also bind to properties of components.
This will be shown in the next video.
The same is true for event binding.
We can bind to native or User/DOM events
like click, mouseover, and so on.
We can bind to our own events in directives,
or our own events in components.
And you will see all of that in the next videos.
Now, the expressions or the syntax you see up here
is how you use the bindings in the parent component.
So let's say, in the app component,
for the message component we just created.
How would that look like in the child
component, which is the receiving end?
Or in the case of the event binding, the outputting end?
Well, there you use, for property binding,
this syntax here, with @Input, and then the propertyName.
So @Input makes this property bindable from outside.
You also got this alternative input,
or this alternative syntax, excuse me,
where you set it up in the component decorator
with inputs and then an array of all inputs
which you want to make bindable.
You can also pass an alias,
as you see as an argument to @Input.
And this is a method or a feature which
allows you to use a different name
outside of this component than inside.
So, if you have propertyName inside
of the component to which you want to bind,
then outside of it, you can use Alias.
You won't see this on action,
if you were confused right now.
So, you could use the above syntax
from outside by binding to propertyName.
Or, if we use the alias "Alias" between squared brackets.
And for event binding, it's pretty much the same
but with @Output and then the name of the event.
And we use it with the parentheses.
Now, that's the theory. If it's not 100% clear,
let's see it in action in the next videos.