The problem we do have is
that we want to use the message.content and message.author
here in the MessageComponent,
but we don't have that property
here in the MessageComponent TypeScript file.
We do have it in the AppComponent, instead.
So now, we could, of course, copy it,
but let me show you how to use property binding
to pass it as an argument to this component,
which we're using in our AppComponent.
We can do this by going back to the MessageComponent
TypeScript file and setting up a new property here.
Let's also name it message, like it is named
in the AppComponent, but that is optional.
You can use any name you want.
Now, here, let's make it of type Message.
If you remember, this is the model we created a while ago.
So, assign Message here, and then add the import
to Message from ./message.model,
which is the file here, which we placed in the same folder.
This is a simple type assignment
which now makes sure that all messages we use here
have to follow the structure laid out in this model.
So, they have to have a username and content,
and, optionally, also have messageId and userId.
Also, these types here have to match.
So, with that, Message should be, let's say,
undefined at the beginning.
So let's not assign a value.
What I want to make, though, is,
I want to make it assignable from outside.
So I will add @Input here
from @angular/core.
So, make sure to add this import at the top, too.
And don't forget the parentheses.
Now, what this will do is, it allows me,
in my app component HTML file,
where I use my component here, the app-message component,
to pass an argument by adding square brackets,
then message, which is the name of the property set up here,
and then, whichever value I want to pass.
Now, the value I want to pass is
the message property of my AppComponent.
This one here.
Now, right now, this is not adhering to my message model,
so I will also assign my message model here.
Also add the import to ./messages/message.model.
Now, I will use the constructor of my message model here.
And here, I will pass a message, and then my author.
Remember, the other arguments are optional.
I don't need to set them up.
So, with that, this is my new message property
in the AppComponent, and I'm passing
this message property as an argument here,
between the quotation marks, to the message,
and these names match, but they don't have to match,
to the message property in my MessageComponent.
And here, I could use the alias I was talking about
to, for example, name this InputMessage,
and then I could use this alias here
between the square brackets.
Not only could, I would now have to use it.
But I'll revert this and go back to the non-alias version.
So, let me quickly remove it here.
Now, with this in place, if I save this
and let it recompile, I can reload the application,
and now, we see the content again.
We don't see the author, because
it's now no longer an author, but instead, username.
So if I change this here in my message.component.html file
and recompile again, and reload again,
we now see the same as before,
but the key difference is, the message
is now passed dynamically from outside.
And this is a huge and very important feature
Angular 2 offers you, which allows you
to really make your application dynamic
and communicate between your components,
which is, of course, very important,
because you often need to do that.