Let's also see the opposite in action.
We pass data into our message component,
now let's create a custom event to pass it
from the message component back to the app component.
Let's say we want to make this edit button work.
We want to be able to click it
and upon clicking it,
we won't bring up an input field yet,
but we want to change it
to a static new content for example.
So we want to hook up the edit button here.
And we want to listen to the click event
which we do by using parentheses, click, parentheses.
And then whatever code you want to execute
upon a click event between the quotation marks.
You have a couple of other events available, too.
Basically all the default DOM events
you have on an element.
And you can find them out by simply visiting
the references you find in the Internet on them,
or simply print such an element to the JavaScript Console
and inspect it there.
Use all events which are normally named On,
click and so on, without the On
and then just while the other part
click, mouse over, whatever,
with a lower-case starting letter.
With that, I hooked up this link to the click listener,
and then here let's say I want to execute onEdit.
Now this will execute the onEdit method
in my message component tied to the file
in this class to be precise,
which of course doesn't exist.
So let me quickly create the onEdit method.
With that I can now log,
or that's a log, let's alert.
It worked, just to see if this, well, works.
So after saving this and reloading the application,
if we click the Edit button,
we see it worked.
So we hooked up this Edit button to the event.
The next step, of course, is to now pass this event
onto the app component.
Now we can't listen to events in these child components
in our app component,
and that is good because we certainly don't want
to get all the events which occur there,
but we can explicitly create an event which we pass there.
You learned about this in these slides before.
At output is the key here.
This all needs to be imported from @angular/core
and then you need parentheses
just like we're using at input.
You could assign an alias which you use
outside of this component, but I will not.
And then choose any event name you want,
I'll name it editClicked.
Now here's an important part,
this is not just a normal property.
It is an EventEmitter,
which is an object Angular2 offers you.
So let's create a new EventEmitter here,
which is basically an object which,
as the name sounds,
it allows us to create or emit events,
and also listen to them.
So this also has to be imported from @angular/core
and this new EventEmitter is a generic type.
If you don't know what generics are,
basically generics are a feature TypeScript offers us,
they also exist in other languages,
which allow you to create classes,
like EventEmitter here,
which can use multiple types.
The EventEmitter doesn't care which type of data
you pass or use in the event.
But it would be nice to tell it
at the point of time you create it.
So therefore here, I know I will simply pass a string,
so I will do this
by using a lower-than and a greater-than sign,
and in between,
the type of data I will use in this EventEmitter string.
If you don't know which data you will use,
you could use any, by the way.
So with that I can now in the onEdit method,
use my editClick property,
which is this EventEmitter in the end,
and then call the emit method,
which means emit a new event.
And here as an argument,
I can pass any data I want to pass.
You don't have to but you can.
And here I want to pass a new value.
This is the new string I want to assign
as a message content.
Of course, choose the value you want to use.
Now this emits my own event,
it also makes it listenable from outside by adding @Output.
The last step is to listen to it.
So in the app component which is the parent component,
here I will add a new thing to my app-message selector.
To this element I created.
I will listen to my own event.
So here I use parentheses again,
and then editClicked which is the event name I chose here
and then whatever code I want to execute.
So like before with just click, the built-in event,
now I'm listening to my own event,
but I do the same thing with it.
I execute some code once it appears.
And here I could listen
or I could create a new method to which I want to execute,
but I could also simply say
message.content equals and now what?
I want it to equal the content I pass through the event.
So this a new value string.
Now Angular2 gives you a generic way
to access the value passed through a custom event.
Dollar-sign event,
this object here,
this built-in object which gets available
or is made available when you listen to events,
always holds the value you pass.
That's just something you have to keep in mind, $event.
So with this I am assigning the value I pass
through the event to my message.content field
while of this message property I create here.
With that, if I save it,
and then reload my application,
let's see what happens if I click Edit.
You see that?
We changed this to a new value here.
Let's see it again.
Bam. This is how you sent up your own event,
how you use it to pass data,
and how you listen to it.
And now a very powerful feature
to be able to not only pass data
from a parent to a child component,
but also do it the other way around.
From the child to the parent component,
through a custom event.