Thus far, I explained
the idea behind components.
I explained how we can use data binding,
the different forms of data binding.
I also mentioned directives,
but we haven't really digged into them.
Let's do that now.
What are directives?
Directives are instructions in the code,
like here, ngif.
These instructions are encountered by Angular 2
at run time, and when it finds them,
it knows what to do because we have to
register all directives, therefore Angular 2
knows what to do when it finds a directive.
For example here, with ngif, the instruction
would be, that's that built in directive,
as a side note,
"Only attach this HTML element and all
its children to the DOM if condition (between the
quotation marks here) is met."
This allows us to conditionally attach
or detach content to the DOM.
That's, by the way, important.
It's not hiding and showing,
it's attaching or detaching.
This alters instruction.
My-component, as we used it before,
here the instruction is,
"Insert MyComponent
here", and this of course, as before, includes
not only the template but also the business logic,
in the typescript class.
So components are directives with a View, the template,
but the key thing to take away is
that directives are such instructions
which, no matter if we have the component
or a simple directive like ngif here,
which allow us to change things on the DOM,
which make our application dynamic.
All directives, no matter if it's a component
or a normal directive, use 'selectors'
to let Angular 2 know which parts of the HTML code
represent in the instruction.
After all, ngif is added like an attribute
to Section, so how does Angular 2 know
the difference between Hidden, which is a default
HTML attribute, and this ngif thing?
Well, we tell it about these selectors.
You saw this for Components where we
registered them in the declarations area
and at Module.
And these selectors work like CSS selectors,
so we use MyComponent for example, typically
for components, but you could also use #MyID
to select any element which has an ideal of MyID.
I also showed this before.
That's the theory behind directives.
We attach them to the DOM to make
a part of the DOM dynamic and to change
it at run time.
Now let's see some examples for such directives
and see how they work.