Angular 2 ships with a couple of
built-in directives,
and there we have kind of two kinds of directives,
attribute directives which are attached like
normal HTML attributes,
and structural directives which are also attached
like this but change the structure of the DOM
and not just the element on which they sit.
ngIf would be such a structural directive,
because it really adds or removes code to the DOM,
and not just change some styling.
We saw this on the slide before,
and you will see it throughout this course.
Let me quickly also show you how a attribute directive
would look like.
On this article, I could use a built-in attribute
directive named ngStyle, like this.
Though you need to pass an argument to that,
to a property, so I will use square brackets
for property binding.
Here, I can pass, or I have to pass, a JavaScript object
which now describes which styles I want to change
on this article, depending on which conditions,
or with which values.
So here if I want to change the background colour,
I can do this by writing backgroundColor,
camel case here, no dash in-between.
If you want to use the normal CSS name with the dash,
you have to enclose it in quotation marks, like this.
So both syntaxes work.
Here I'll use the camel case syntax, like that.
And then divided by a colon, so it has the value
for this key value pair, the value for this style.
So for the background colour, I could set this to red,
and if I now saved this, and then reload the application,
you see it has a red background.
Now of course, this could have been achieved
with normal styles attribute.
The cool thing here is, I can also bind to a property
named colour, which I then create in my component class here,
colour, and I can set this to red.
And now you will see the same result,
but now it's already a bit more dynamic.
I can even improve this by combining it with event binding.
So let's say I have my mouseenter listener here,
to listen to whenever I hover over this element,
and only if I hover over it, or at the point
once I hover over it, then I want to set colour
equal to green, like that.
So colour is this property I'm using here,
and which I set up here in the component,
keep this in mind.
So I'm changing it if I hover over the style.
So if I reload this, it's still red,
but if I hover over it, it becomes green.
It doesn't become red if I leave with the mouse,
because I haven't took up a respective event,
but this shows you how you can use ngStyle
to really, well, make it dynamic,
and more than that, it shows you how you use directives
to change parts of the DOM, depending on some external
conditions like events, or whatever.
So I'm removing all that code
because I just wanted to show that.
We will use more directives in the next videos, though.