The last video we saw
an attribute directive,
which changed the element on which it was placed,
style in this case.
Now I want to show
a structural directive,
which changes the structure of the DOM.
It's really time to get
more than just one message.
Now I could get an additional message
by simply duplicating this line.
If I save this and reload my application,
now we get two messages.
But that is the worst way to do it
because it's not dynamic at all.
What if we want
to dynamically add new messages?
We can't go back and code
and add them manually here.
So let's quickly remove that.
Instead, what I want to do is,
here in my message property app component,
I want to rename this to Messages
and make it of type message array,
like this.
So, now this should be an array of messages.
Like so.
And here, let's say I'll add a second message.
So, something else, also by Max.
Now I've got two messages,
and I want to output them
with my message component.
I don't want to manually pass them.
So, like, message with index zero ends on.
I could do this,
but that's not how I want to do that.
Instead, here I want to loop
through all my messages,
and output my app message component,
this one here,
as often as I need to.
To do so, I will simply add a new directive
to my app message selector here.
To this component.
This new directive is a structural directive.
We saw ngIf on the slide to conditionally attach
or detach this component.
Another one is ngFor,
which means loop through a certain condition
as often as needed,
and duplicate this component or this element
on which this ngFor is placed,
and all child elements, as a side note,
as often as needed.
So here, I want to loop through all my messages.
I can say let to create a local variable
which I can use here in the template.
Message of messages.
This is the syntax
of a normal for-of in Java Script
or Type Script, and I use it here in ngFor.
This creates this local message variable,
which I can use in my template.
Like here, when I pass it to message still,
to this property by name.
This message here now no longer refers
to a property in app.component.
I don't have message;
I only have messages.
But instead it refers to this local variable
I've created here.
And this will be the message
of the current iteration I'm at.
So, here I'm looping through all my messages,
and for each loop iteration,
I'm reassigning this message variable
and I'm passing it to the component
which also gets created per iteration.
With this simple change,
if I save this and go back to the application
and reload, you now also see two messages,
but with different content
and created dynamically.
And if add a third message,
like this,
simply naming it, "3rd Message,"
you will see only one reload away,
well, after recompiling at least,
you see different message.
This is the power of ngFor,
which is a built in structural directive,
named such because we change
the structure of the DOM.
As a side note,
this is why we have the star at the beginning.
This is kind of telling Angular 2
that this is a structural directive.
So, ngFor and ngIf, together with ngSwitch,
are the build-in structural directives
which use this star.
These are all the build-in structural directive
Angular 2 ships with, but as you see,
looping through and conditionally showing,
really is covering most of the use cases
where you need to change the DOM.