Our application is taking shape.
We already output multiple messages.
We're not far away from creating them on our own,
but before implementing the logic
to create them on our own, I want to restructure it,
or add new components which we'll soon need.
I'll add two new files to my messages folder.
I'll add a message-input.component
which is later on, responsible for creating new messages
or editing existing ones.
And the second file I'll add should hold my list
of messages.
Right now this list is held here,
in my app component where I loop through the messages.
But remember we'll soon also have the authentication part
which then also needs to be somehow contained
in my app component.
So the list of messages is not really something
the app component should be responsible for.
Instead I should have a new file, a new component for this,
the message-list.component here in the messages folder
of course, like this.
Let's start with the message list component.
Here I'll again create a new class MessageListComponent
named like this which follows the naming convention
of describing what we have in this file.
I don't have anything in the class itself,
but I will add the component selector again
or component decorator, excuse me.
Also add the import and then here,
I need to pass something as an argument,
the Chalice script object, with my selector,
where I want to have app-message-list
to follow this naming convention of my selectors.
Of course you may choose whichever selector you want to use,
and then here, I'll use an inline template
which means I'm not using an external file,
but instead I want to store the template in this file.
I can do this by using backticks here
to write a multi-line string,
and since it is a short template,
I will choose to write my HTML code in here
and not use an external file.
Here I want to create a div with a class
of .col-md-8, bootstrap class it is,
also give it some centering so,
really nothing we haven't seen before.
And here my ID doesn't like this.
And then in here, I want to loop from my messages,
so I will copy the code from my app component
where I insert my own message,
and I will now simply add it here
in the MessageListComponent.
Of course this also means that for now,
I will copy my messages' array from my app component.
I can remove the import of the message class therefore,
to my MessageListComponent
where I now need to add this message import
from
./message.model
So this is my MessageListComponent,
and I will now use this list
in my app component HTML file here
where I will replace this div since I added the column class
as my self and import app-message-list here.
Like that.
So that's the new component I created
and which I'll now also have to register in my app module,
so match it, MessageListComponent
and also add this import.
With this, if I save this and then go back
to the application,
we should see the same as before, but now it's restructured.
Again because later on, I will use other things
like authentication in the app component,
and therefore I want to make the message part here,
the feature here responsible for itself,
with its own components.
Now for the message-input-component,
I'll do pretty much the same.
I'll create a new class, MessageInputComponent
in this file I just created,
then add the component decorator again
which needs to be imported from @Angular/core
and pass the Chalice script object.
Let's set up a selector named app-message-input
I think you're seeing which naming convention I'm following.
And then here we can also use a template URL again
since this will be a little bit of a longer template.
I want to point to message-input.component.html
Let's also create this external file
message-input.component.html like this.
And now how should this look like?
Here I also want to have my bootstrap classes
for a grid to position it in the middle like before.
Of course you can always adjust this to your needs.
And then here let's create a form group,
all the bootstrap with a label
for the content of the message.
So Content and then of course the input
with an ID of content and a class of form-control
which the bootstrap class TypeText is okay.
And this should hold my input,
and then I will have a button to submit it,
so here I want to have classes button and button primary,
all the bootstrap classes.
Type should be submit
and I'll name it Save to save my message.
With that I'm able to show it at least.
So I can now register this in the app module,
the MessageInputComponent that is.
Like this.
Also add the import again.
Don't forget this.
And then in my app component, I can simply duplicate this,
add another row, and here have app-message-input.
With this in place, if I now reload the application
one more time, we see this new input component,
and maybe let's throw in a horizontal line here
as a divider like this.
So now we get this set up.
Now the last thing I wanna do for now,
is I want to pass the value, the user inputs here,
to the console for now.
I'll soon also hook it up to my array to really add it.
For now let's just do this.
So here I want to hook up a click listener on this button,
and I want to execute onSave here,
so onSave in my TypeScript class.
Now how do I get the value passed into the input here
to my TypeScript class?
I could use two-way data binding for this,
and I will do so soon, or I will use a form to be precise,
but here I will show a different approach.
We can assign a local reference
to any HTML element in our template
by using a hashtag and then the name of the reference.
Let's name it input, but it's totally up to you.
This will store a reference to this input
which we then can use everywhere in our template.
So in the onSave method, I could pass input
to pass the reference to this input element,
or I could directly pass input value.
Remember, value's a done property available
on input elements, so can easily access this like this.
This passes the value of this input
to the onSave method whenever I click it.
So here in the TypeScript class, I can expect this value
which will be of type string,
and I can simply log it to the console like this.
So if I now save this and let it recompile
and reload my application.
Let's open up the Chalice script console here,
and let's enter something and hit save.
You see something over there,
can increase this in size here.
And this is how easy we can hook this up,
and again, as a next step,
we will make sure that we really fetched this value
and then pass it on to a kind of a storage
so that we not only save it here
in parenthesis to the console,
but add a new message to our array.