It would be nice to be able to
get the value we enter into the input components
so this new message,
entity array of messages we already got.
For this, we will use services and dependency injection
and before showing this in action,
let me explain what this actually is.
Let's consider our application
where we have a couple of components:
component one, two and three.
And each of these components will have, lets say,
a method and a property or a variable here.
Now, as you can see, for all three components
this is the same.
We use the same method, with the same variable.
So we do have exactly the same code.
Now that is of course duplicate code,
which is hard to keep in sync
if this depends on each other.
It's also hard to maintain because
if we change it in one place,
we need to change it in three places.
For such a case, we have this concept called
services in latitude.
Which allows us to outsource certain tasks, data
whatever, into a single class,
which we then can use in multiple places of our application,
in multiple components, let's say.
So in such a service,
we store this method A with its variable
and then we are able to inject the service
into the components where we need it.
All these components do have access to the service then,
and we can also choose if we want to provide it
on a per component level,
which would give us free instances of the service class.
So three different instances with
three different variables, so the data will be different.
Or, if we want to provide it on the application level
with only one instance,
which means every component has access to it,
but the data is shared.
We're going to use such a service to get our new content,
or new message from one component to the other
and to store all our content,
all our messages, in such a central service,
which holds it as our data repository.
Well, lets see this in action in the next videos.