Back in the project,
I wanna create such a new service.
It's going to be a service used
in my messages feature here.
So I'm going to create this file
in this messages folder, and a fitting name
would be message.service.ts since
this will be a service for my messages.
Now how does such a service look like?
It's a normal class, which we export
to make it usable outside of this file too.
And I'm not going to name it just service.
I'm going to name it message service,
since it will hold my message related things.
Now in this service, a very important thing
which I wanna have is my array of messages.
So this will be of type message,
which needs to be imported from ./message.model
so my own male model here, of type message array.
And it will be an empty array let's say for now.
So this is my central messages array
which I will soon use to store and manage
all my messages in my front end application.
Now in order to be able to use this array,
I want to create a at message method here,
which allows me to add a new message
to this property or to this central array.
And here I expect to get a message as an argument.
Of course this should be of type message.
And then I can simply use my messages array
to push this new message on it.
You can, by the way, make this a private property
which is not accessible from outside.
As the next step I also want to be able to
get my messages here, so let's add
a get messages method to this class
which simply returns my messages array here
so that I have access to the central array.
And I want to add one other method.
Adding and getting messages is great,
we'll soon also add an edit method,
but for now I want to implement
a delete message method, which allows me to
pass a message to this method here.
And then here I want to take my messages array
and splice it and remove one element
with the splice method.
I want to start at the index of the message
and passing as an argument.
I'm getting this index with the index.of method
on my messages array.
And then I want to splice exactly one element,
so remove this one element from this array.
This will alter this array and remove
that element I want to remove.
With this, this is the functionality,
I want to outsource in a separate file
in this message service.
I can then use this message service
and other components to, in one component,
add a message, in another component, get messages.
I will extend this service in the next videos,
but for now let's hook up this
at message functionality here.