For the time being,
I'll add console log here so that we can see
the messages array after we added a new message.
I want to you use it in my MessageInputComponent,
though, where I have this onSave method.
Here it would be great if I could access
my message service and pass the value,
or a new message based on this value,
to this message service and store
it in the message array there.
Now, to do so, I need to inject it here,
as I explained on the slides.
The Angular 2 framework ships with
its own dependency injector, which is a tool
in the background which allows us to provide
certain instances of certain objects in places
in the application where we need to have them.
So we're not going to instantiate this service
on our own with the new keyword, like this.
This is not how we'll do it.
We will let Angular 2 handle this
and get your readily instantiated instance
directly served to our component here.
How does this work?
We add a constructor to this class here,
and in this constructor, we set up
an argument we expect to get.
Let's all just store it in a private
property named messageService.
And now here's the important part:
I assign a type to this.
Type should be MessageService.
Also, import this from ./message.service.
Now, who's creator our message input component?
That is Angular 2.
So, when Angular 2 is creating it,
it will execute the constructor,
and there it will see that we
expect to get this MessageService.
Now, since Angular 2 is doing all that,
it kind of needs a way to be able to pass
this instance of type MessageService to
this MessageInputConponent when it creates it.
In order for Angular 2 to be able
to create this MessageService instance,
we kind of need to tell it how to do that.
But telling it is really simple.
We do so by adding a new property to the
object we passed to the component decorator.
And this is named providers.
This is an array of blueprints we want to tell Angular 2
or we want to get Angular 2 to know for this component.
Here, I'm telling Angular 2 "MessageService."
I'm passing this passing this type as an argument
or as an element in this providers array.
By doing this, Angular 2 is able
to create an instance of this MessageService
and pass it to this constructor,
where it then will be stored in this
private messageService property.
With this setup here,
we're using Angular 2's dependency injector,
which is doing all the rest in the background for us,
creating this new MessageService instance,
passing it to us, and so on.
And then we can use it here in this component,
and only here, not in any other component.
That's important. We only injected
it here in the constructor.
You will find this concept of dependency injection
in other languages, too, as a side note.
So, here I can then access my messageService,
and call addMessage to pass a new message.
Though, I first need to create such a new message,
so I will store it in a message constant, new Message.
I therefore need to import my message from ./message.model.
And here, I want to pass the value as the content,
and then let's say Max as the offer.
And other fields are optional anyways.
With that, I can pass this newly created message
as an argument to the addMessage method,
which should store it in this array.
Now, let's save this and see this in action.
If I open up the console here, reload the application.
Clear the console and type "Something!" again.
If I hit save, you see an array,
which holds this message we just created.
messageId and useIds, of course,
undefined because I didn't pass it.
If I add "Something 2!," you now see
this array holds two messages.
So, the storing of messages in this central
array in this service does work.
And this is how we use such a service
to centralised certain things, to use it
as a data storage, for example.
Of course, storing the data is nice,
but it would be even more useful if you could
not only store it there but also retrieve it there
after and output in our list of messages here.
So, let's work on this next.