We already unchecked
the message service and the message input component.
Now in order to get this list of messages,
the logical place to alt unchecked would be
the master list component here,
where we have the array of messages.
So let's do that, let's add a constructor
here too, where I then also set up
a message service property and tell Angular 2
that this should be of type message service.
Which also needs to be imported here
at the top, of course.
Remember that alone won't do the trick.
We also have to add the providers array here
to provide the message service like this.
With that, we get access to the message service
here too, and we could call this get messages,
by the way, method here to get all the messages.
Now in the message list component,
we could do this in the constructor,
but a good practise is to use the ngOninit
life cycle hook for well, anything else
which is beyond very basic initializations.
The ngOninit life cycle hook is one of
the life cycle hooks Angular 2 reaches
when creating such a component.
It will reach several life cycles,
and you can learn more about this
in dedicated Angular 2 courses.
But a very important hook is the
Oninit life cycle hook, which is executed
once the component has been initialised by Angular 2.
Remember it's doing this in the background
with this add component decorator,
we give Angular 2 the chance to initialise
such a component.
So in order to implement this life cycle hook method,
I implement an interface which is called Oninit,
and which needs to be imported from at Angular core.
What this interface does is it
requires me to implement the method called
ngOninit in this class, otherwise it will get an error.
Now with this interface, I'm telling Angular 2
since it requires me to implement this method,
that I do have this method.
Which makes it safe for Angular 2 to
execute this method once it reaches
the Oninit life cycle phase.
It won't execute it by default
because I might not have this method,
but if I do have it, and I indicate this with
again, with the implement hash optics interface,
it will run this method automatically.
So in this method which is called,
after the component has been initialised,
after the properties have been initialised,
I can simply say this.messages equals
this.messageService.getMessages,
which will give me this array.
Now here's an important note.
I'm assigning this messages,
which I now can simply clear here,
to this array I'm having in my message service.
Keep in mind arrays and objects in JavaScript
are reference types which means
if I assign this array from the service
to the array in this component
as I'm doing here, this is one and the same object.
These are not two different objects,
I'm not creating a copy here.
I'm simply copying the pointer which
points to the same place in memory.
So this messages and this component
points to the same array as I have here
in the message service.
Which is great because this means that
whenever I add a method from some other place
in the application, it is added to this array
which happens to be the same as
in the message list component.
Which means the list will automatically get updated.
So once you see this automatic updating,
keep this in mind that this is happening
because we're using the same messages array here
due to how reference types work in JavaScript.
Enough of the talking so I hooked this up,
so with that if I save this, what we should see
upon reloading this application is
that initially this is now empty.
We don't have any messages anymore.
Which makes sense because I deleted it here.
I'm fetching it from the message service
which is empty at the beginning.
So let's add a new message here.
And after I click save, we should see it
up here down there.
Well, nothing is happening.
Why is that?
Well, I'm going to have a look at this
in the next video.