Remember in the last video,
we had the problem that upon clicking Save,
the messages don't get added here,
though as we can see in the Console log,
we clearly are creating them.
They are getting added to this array.
In the last video, I explained that the array
we use in the message list component gets assigned
the same array we used in the service,
so it should automatically update.
Why is this not happening?
Well, let's go back to the video where I showed
the slides about dependency injection.
there I also explained that we can inject
or that we can provide such a service on a
per component basis, or a per application basis.
Actually, there's even a bit more to it.
The Angular 2 dependency injector,
which we're using here, is a hierarchical injector,
which means it can be set up in a way to give us
one instance of this message service for all
our components, or only for some,
or one instance per component.
Right now, we're in the one instance per component mode,
which explains why we're not seeing the messages.
The message service we're using in the
message list component simply is a different one
than the one in the message input component.
Angular 2 creates two instances of the service.
This might be the behaviour we want,
but here it is not.
Instead, you want to use the same instance.
Now since the injector is hierarchical,
we can simply remove the provider set up here
in the message input component,
and also in the message list component.
So after removing it in both components,
let's go to the app component,
which holds the inputted list component,
and let's add it here.
Here in the app component, let's add the provider's array
MessageService.
Also add the import, of course.
What this will do is, it will create one single instance
of this MessageService for the app component
and, and this is important, all its shell components.
So for all the components we use in the app component,
namely, the inputted list.
So now the inputted list component will share
the same instance of the service,
which should now lead to the desired behaviour
that if we update this array in this instance,
it is updated in the other component as well.
So if I save this,
and then we reload this application here.
Let's clear the console,
and try this again.
Now you can see the new message
and it gets added because now we set this up in a way
that this now works in the desired way,
and we're using the same instance of the service
with the same messages array for both the input
and the list component.