Our application really developed nicely.
We are now able to set up our own messages here
and save them here.
Deleting and editing does not really work,
but we will get this to work, too.
Before doing so, let's have a look at the input component
again though.
It works that if we click here, we add it,
but what doesn't work is it doesn't clear this input here.
Also it would allow us to submit an empty field.
And both is not really what I want.
So we can enhance this by using in our feature
Angular 2 offers us, forms.
Angular 2 makes the creation and management
of forms very easy,
and indeed it offers two approaches to do so,
the template driven approach and the date driven,
or reactive approach.
I will show you both, but for this form,
I wanna start with the template driven approach.
So let's work on that.
The template driven approach is named
template driven approach because it uses
this template to create the form.
Basically, we create the form
just like you always create forms.
Add, a form element here,
let's simply delete the action because we're not going
to submit this directly to the server,
Angular 2 will handle this form.
And then let's copy all that code
and paste it in there into the form.
Now with that, we quickly created the form in HTML,
in the template.
And Angular 2 is clever enough to automatically detect
this form.
It detects the form element here,
and derives that we want to use a form here,
and automatically constructs the form in the background.
What do I mean with constructs the form?
Well, Angular 2 manages the form for us,
and for this, it tracks the validity of the form,
the current value, and much more.
All of that is stored in a form JavaScript object
Angular 2 creates for us automatically.
And this is what I mean with that.
It creates this object for us and stores it,
simply because it detects this form element.
We can override this behaviour as you will learn later,
but for now, let's take advantage of it.
This form here is a very simple form,
but while Angular 2 does detect the form element,
it does not detect the inputs for us.
It certainly could do that, but you might have a form
where you don't want to register all the inputs
as form inputs.
Or maybe you have a custom component which holds your input,
so it doesn't do that.
You have to tell Angular 2 which parts
of the form are actually inputs you want to register.
This is very simple to do though.
Let me remove this local reference.
I'm not going to use this approach anymore.
Instead in order to tell Angular 2 that this input here,
just going to restructure it to make it easier to read,
that this input here should be a control
as it is called of that form.
I simply add ngModel to it, like this.
Do you recognise this?
We used it before though with squared brackets
and parenthesis.
Without that, all it does is,
it tells Angular 2, hey this input
on which ngModel is placed, should be registered
as a control of the form which was automatically derived
by Angular 2.
Now for that to work, it is important
that you have the form's module added
to the import's array in the app module though.
We already do have that, but I just want to highlight this.
This is important.
So with this, what I can do now is add another thing here,
a normal attribute, the name attribute.
And I'll give this a name of content.
This is a normal HTML attribute,
has nothing to do with Angular 2
though Angular 2 will automatically detect it
to store this value of this input on a control.
It gives this name which we assign here.
With that we're storing our content.
But it would be nice to be able to now do something
when we hit the submit button.
We do have a click listener here,
but this is not how you actually handle the form submissions
so let's delete it.
Instead, Angular 2 gives us a new directive
which exposes an event we can use here.
It's called ngSubmit and it should be enclosed
in parenthesis since it is an event here.
There we could execute onSubmit,
and therefore let's rename this onSave method to onSubmit.
Now as you see we no longer pass the value
of our form like this.
Now we could use two-way binding
to get access to the contents stored
in the property automatically,
but I don't want to do that.
I don't want to update a property on every keystroke.
I only want to pass this
when we actually hit the submit button.
So how do I pass the form Angular 2 creates for us
to this onSubmit method here?
We can use a nice little trick
or simple approach Angular 2 offers us here.
I can assign a local reference to this form,
as before with the hashtag and then any name of your choice.
Here is simply f.
This would give us access to this form HTML element,
but I want to get access to the form Angular 2 created
in the background.
I can get this access by assigning equal and then ngForm.
With this command I'm basically telling Angular 2
don't give me access to this form HTML element.
Instead give me access to the JavaScript object
you, Angular 2, created for me.
And then I can pass this local reference
or this form to the onSubmit method
and here in my component,
I know that I will get the form as an argument,
which is of type ngForm which needs
to be imported from @angular/forms,
and then in here, I can simply,
console.log
and I will comment out the outer lines for now.
Let's see what happens if I now reload the application,
open up the console and type something here and hit save.
You now see we indeed get an object
of type ngForm submitted, and this is the form
Angular 2 created in the background for us.
Now definitely feel free to play around with it
and have a look which fields Angular 2 created there.
You will see the controls which is basically
an object holding all the controls Angular 2 knows.
Here, that's only the content control.
Again this is the name I assigned in the template,
here with this attribute.
And then you can see on this content control,
you get more fields and so on.
A very important field on the overall form
is this value field here which holds
an object representing the value of the form,
again with the content control, the name we set up,
and then the value we entered.
Now since we got this value field here,
it's very easy to go back to the type script code,
comment that in again, remove the console log,
and here simply take form.content as a value,
form.value.content, excuse me.
This will populate the content of this newly created message
with the value entered into the content input field
in our form.
And with that, we're using the template driven approach
to now submit this.
And we can enhance this a bit more
by now after all of this has been done,
calling form and then resetForm, like that.
So if I just save this, let's see the new application here.
I will reload this and add something,
and if I click save, you see we create it,
but now the form is reset thereafter,
which means it now is empty again,
the input is empty again.
It means more than that though.
In such a form, remember I can still submit
an empty field, and I don't want that.
I can go in my template
and add the HTML5 value data required.
This is not Angular 2.
This is HTML5.
But Angular 2 will recognise it
and now knows this input is required,
which means that now if I save this
and I reload this one more time,
and I type into there, you now see it has a red border
because it is empty.
It is invalid.
Where does this red border come from?
Well let's inspect this element.
Here you can see this input got a couple
of new things attached to it by Angular 2.
And very important is this part here
in the classes, in the CSS classes.
We get form-control which is the bootstrap class,
but we also get ng-pristine, ng-invalid, and ng-touched.
These three classes are added by Angular 2,
and they represent the state of this input.
They tell us that it is pristine
which means we haven't entered anything.
It is invalid because it is empty
even though we said that it is required,
so it should not be empty.
And it is touched because I clicked into it.
If I reload the application and inspect this,
you see now it's also invalid, but it's ng-untouched
because I haven't clicked into it.
And where's the red border coming from?
Well that's a style I set up in my public style sheets,
style CSS file down here.
Any input which has ng-invalid and ng-touched
gets the red border because I don't want
to put the red border around inputs
which are invalid but haven't been touched yet.
The user had no chance of making them valid yet.
This is what leads to the red border
and what now means that if I click there
and hit submit, I get this built-in error,
but once I enter something, I am able to submit,
and thereafter the form resets
and it's not bordered by red because the classes
are also reset.
So this is again untouched.
With that we're using the template driven approach
to manage the creation of new messages,
a huge step in developing this message's functionality.