It's nice that the messaging part
is developing well but we also have
this auth part and we haven't really worked on that.
Right now our whole app component only represents
the messages part.
I want to change this.
I now also want to start working on the authentication part
and more than that I also want
to implement routing, which means I want
to be able to switch between my messages part
and my authentication part.
So in one part I want to be able
to still create and see my messages
but in the other part I want to be able
to sign up or sign in a user.
Well for that I need routing.
I want to be able to load different pages
depending on different links on which I clicked.
To do so, I will add yet another component
to my messages feature file here for the folder.
The messages component dot TS.
So I already have a message component
which represents a single message.
This now should represent my whole messages feature,
this messages part here.
So here I will export my messages component
and of course you already guessed it,
I will add my component decorator to this
which needs to be imported from @AngularCore like always.
Here I'll pass my auth check and we'll set up the selector.
Let's name it App Messages.
I also want to set up the template
and you could use an external file.
I'm going to use an inline template again
like this with back ticks.
And in this template I want to have
all the code I have here in my app component HTML file.
Because again, I want to have this messages component
to be the responsible part for my messages feature.
So with this I created my separate app messages component
and now I could include it like this here
but I don't want to do that
because I want to use routing.
I still need to register it in my module here.
So here it's time to now add my messages component
also at the import, so that we're able
to use it in routing later on.
Before adding routing, let me also add
a component to the auth file.
To the auth folder.
Authentication dot component dot TS will be the file name
and in here I'll also export a class
named Authentication Component.
Here I'll also assign a decorator component like this.
Imported from @AngularCore as always
and let's give it a selector of app authentication.
The template will grow later on.
For now all I will do here
is I will simply output an H1 tag
where I say authentication to know
that we successfully got there.
I also won't include this is my app component template
but again I also need to add it
to my app module to make Angular2 aware
of this component so that I can use it
in routing later on.
Also add the import.
Now I finally also want to create a header
and I will store this in the app folder.
Though I could create a subfolder
named Shared or something like this.
Here the header component should,
well you might have expected it,
hold my header.
So in here I'll also export this class,
Header Component at Component Decorator
with your shallow grouped object passed here
and this should get a selector of App Header
and then again a template.
I'm going to use an in line template here too.
You might outsource it if you prefer that of course
and there a header with class row.
And then a Nav element with the classes Col MD Eight
and then Col MD offset to elect
the four Bootstrap grid classes to style it nicely
and in here let's give this
an ordered list with the class Nav, Nav Pills.
This is just Pills Navigation look Bootstrap offers us.
You can find it on Get Bootstrap dot com of course
if you want to learn more about that.
Oops.
And in here let's create two list items
with anchor text to have my links.
I want to have a messenger link
and let's say an authentication link.
I will remove the href element
because I will replace this later on,
but for now I will leave it like this
and register this header component
which now, until now only has a default Bootstrap styling
to the app module, also add the import.
This allows me in my app component HTML file
to include the app header like that.
So if I save this and reload the application
we now see this header with the two pills.
No pill is active right now
and while the routing of course doesn't work.
So we clearly can improve this a bit more.