In order to set up routing,
I will create a new file in the app folder
and name it "app.routing.ts"
Angular 2 ships with a built-in router.
This router is very powerful,
but we need to tell it which routes our application has,
of course.
Telling it is very simple, though.
We do it in this file.
Here I want to create a constant
which I name APP_ROUTES, this name is up to you,
which is of type: Routes.
This is a type provided by the @angular router package.
This type expects us to provide an array of routes,
where each route is represented by a Javascript object,
like this.
And each route then has a path,
which is the part we see in the URL after the slash.
So something like "/auth", for example,
or "/messages".
Let's indeed use this.
Let's create a 'messages' path
to load our messages component.
To tell Angular 2 to load this component,
I add another property to this object
which is named "component,"
and where I point to my messages component like this.
Also imported from ./messages/messages.component.
With this, I set up a route,
but Angular 2 isn't aware of it yet.
We will add it soon.
I will duplicate this to also provide an auth route,
where I load my authentication component,
and also add this import.
And finally, I also want to handle the case
that the user simply visits this route here, / nothing.
To do this, I will duplicate the first route,
and set the path to nothing,
and then here I want to redirect
to '/messages'.
This will lead to this route always resolving
in a redirection to,
and now this is important, '/messages' means,
always use your domain and then append '/messages' directly.
If I would have just 'messages',
it would always append 'messages'
to the end of the existing path,
which could be localhost/user,
and I don't want to go to localhost/user/messages,
but I always want to go to localhost/messages,
which is why I use an absolute path here.
I also need to add another property here,
which is called pathMatch,
and I will set this to 'full'.
Why do I need this?
The Angular 2 router works in a way
that by default, it tries to match any part
of the path with the path you set up here.
Now the problem with the empty path is,
every path includes this.
Even if you have /messages,
you have this invisible empty part
between the domain and your path thereafter.
So the empty path is always present.
Therefore, if we don't add pathMatch: 'full',
which overrides the default behaviour,
Angular 2 would always redirect to 'messages',
even if we visit /auth.
With pathMatch: 'full', we tell Angular 2,
"only react to this path if this is the full path."
So not if it is included here,
but if there is nothing else, then this path.
With that, we get the desired behaviour
that we only redirect to /messages
if you visit the root page, so localhost/ nothing,
and not any other route.
Well, with that, the routes are set up,
though Angular 2 still isn't aware of them.
To make it aware,
we use the built-in RouterModule Angular 2 ships with,
which needs to import it from @angular/router,
and there we can register new routes
with the forRoot method.
And here we pass our routes.
This registers our routes
in the Angular 2 RouterModule for our application.
Now the last step is to import this RouterModule
in the AppModule,
though if I were to import RouterModule like this,
it would not work,
because that would mean the RouterModule
without our custom routes.
So we need to re-export this modified RouterModule here,
therefore I will export a constant named 'routing'
which I assign to RouterModule.forRoot and then our routes.
Therefore now in the imports array in our AppModule,
I can simply import routing from ./app.routing,
so also add this import path here.
With this, I make this module,
this RouterModule with our custom routes,
available in this application,
I register it here,
and Angular 2 is now aware of our routes.
We can already see this in action,
though we first need to give Angular 2 a place
to render these routes.
It's nice that we set up that we want
to load the MessagesComponent in this case,
and the AuthenticationComponent in this case,
but where should we load it?
In order to give Angular 2 a place,
I will now add a horizontal line
in the AppComponent HTML file,
and add a new built-in directive here, &lt;router-outlet&gt;.
It looks like a component,
but it simply is a directive telling Angular 2,
"Here is the place where you should load
"the router loaded components."
So this will be the place
where these components will be rendered.
So let's save this, and then reload the application,
and now you see I instantly get redirected to /messages,
which is great.
And if I click on /auth, or enter /auth here,
I go there.
Of course, these links don't work though,
because, well, we haven't hooked them up.
Let's do this next.