In order to hook up these links
to our existing routes, we're going to use
another built-in directive.
This directive uses property binding,
because we need to pass an argument,
and it's named routerLink, in square brackets
because of property binding.
routerLink expects to get an array where each element
represents a segment in our path in the URL.
So if we would have something like /messages/1
then we would have messages, and the second element
would be 1.
And then it would navigate you out of main/messages/1.
Well here we only have messages, but I want to go there
absolutely, so add a leading slash.
Again for the same reason I explained before,
to force Angular 2 to always load localhost/messages
and not appended to the end of the existing path.
Now with that, I can simply copy this
and also append it down here.
But here, of course, I want to go to /auth.
With that, if I reload this application again,
now you can see, this is hooked up,
but you see the styling is a bit off.
I'm not talking about the authentication part here
jumping around.
That's simply because we haven't added any bootstrap grid
to this component yet, since it is very incomplete.
We will work on this later.
But it would be nice to see which route is active.
So let's add this.
Since I'm using bootstrap, I can mark a route as active
by simply adding the CSS class named active
to the list item which holds the link.
If I do this and reload,
you now see Messenger is active.
But of course, it stays active,
even if I go to Authentication,
because I hard-coded this here.
It would be nice if we could conditionally attach
this CSS class.
And it turns out, with Angular 2 we can.
We can add another directive here, which is named
routerLinkActive, or actually it belongs to the
routerLink directive here.
routerLink, or Angular 2 routing in general, is able to
find this directive, and whatever I pass as a name
between the quotation marks here, gets assigned to
this list item as a CSS class whenever a link
on this list item, or nested in this list item,
like it is the case here, gets active.
So here, I don't then want to apply the active class,
and I do the same for the auth link here.
Now this means the active class only gets applied
if the nested link is the active one.
Very, very convenient,
and very powerful.
It's only two directives used here,
and it give us very flexible routing,
and very flexible links.
So with this in place, if I now reload,
you see Authentication is active,
but if I click on Messenger, now that is active.
And with that, we got our routing set up.
Of course, it's next time to improve this authentication
part here a bit, before we then finally can leave
the front end world for a second,
and hook up our Messenger to the back end,
to really save our messages there
and, well, get our back end back into the party.