Before doing so, before adding the
authentication part to finish this section here,
I want to highlight something else.
If I click on these links, you'll see
we clearly change the URL up here.
If I now reload by hitting enter, it still works.
This works because I configured this
seed project in a specific way.
By default, it would not work.
Because if I hit enter here, we send a new request
to the server, and the server has no /auth route.
Let's have a look in the routes file.
We only have slash nothing.
So, why don't we get a 404 error?
Why is Angular 2 able to pick up
before the server throws a 404 error?
Because I configured the server in such a way
and you have to do the same in your custom setup.
Your server should not return 404 errors.
Instead, if it encounters a route it doesn't know,
like here, /auth, which is perfectly normal
for a single-page application
where routes are registered in JavaScript.
In such a case, and there's a setup
in the app.js file here in the root project folder,
in such a case you see down here
that I catch any 404 errors.
So, whenever we reach this point here where we seem
to not have found any fitting routes, in such a case,
I also want to return the index page,
which, of course, holds our Angular 2 application,
starts our Angular 2 application,
and therefore, then, knows how to handle this route.
If I would throw a 404 error here,
we would get that before Angular 2 has a chance
to take over.
So, whatever your server is configured in a way
that in case of a 404 error,
it returns your index.html,
index.hbs, whatever file, and gives Angular 2 a chance
to take over.