With that out of the way,
let's work on the Authentication section next.
Here I want to create a couple of components to work with
which I will extend in the next modules,
but where I want to start working on right now.
We got our authentication component,
but specifically I want to have components
for signing a user up, in, and logging him out.
So I'll need a sign up component.
I'll also need a sign in component
and I'll also need a log out component, like this.
Let's work on the log out component first.
It's the easiest one.
Here I'll export a class named Log out Component
and, you already guessed it,
of course I'm going to attach my component decorator
which needs to be imported from @angular/core.
I will give this a selector of let's say app log out,
whatever you like.
Here I'll also create a inline template,
so no external file and in here all I want to have
is I want to have my bootstrap classes
to again centre this nicely like before.
In this div here I want to have a button
with a class of button button danger
which says log out and which upon clicking it
fires a click event on log out
which I will fill with some logic later on.
I will set it up now, though.
So this will be fired.
It doesn't do anything right now, though.
Now I will add it to my app module here,
the logout component,
I'll also add the import here,
but what I won't do is
I will not add it to my authentication component.
Why? Because after setting up my next components,
sign in and sign up,
I will add child routing here,
which means I want to have some sub-routes
for my authentication related routes
so that I later on have routes
like auth/logout, auth/signup and so on.
So I want to load these components,
these nest components here conditionally
and not hard code them in here.
It's different for the messages area
where I simply structure them all on one page.
But for authentication, I want to have multiple pages.
To see this in action,
I will quickly set up my other two components,
sign up component here
and then, thereafter, sign in.
Both are, of course, created by adding
the component decorator and imported as always.
Then they should get a selector
of let's say app sign up
and then a template URL here,
I'm going to use a external file again,
sign up component HTML,
which I'm going to create.
I'll also create such a file
for the sign in component,
So sign up and thereafter sign in component HTML.
Because I will basically just copy the code
from the sign up component
into my sign in component typescript file,
of course, change the selector,
change the template, sign in,
and change the name of the component here.
Also register all these components
here in the app module,
so sign up component and sign in component.
With that, I have created all these components
and I will simply say sign up here
in the sign up template,
this will change later of course,
and sign in in the sign in template,
and on the log out template, remember,
we have this button.
Again, I will adjust the content later on.
For now, let's keep it simple.
Next, I want to set up this child routing
so that I can load one of these three components,
log out, sign up, sign in, when needed.