I will start by creating the links.
We already learned how to do so.
I will do it in the authentication component,
which is the parent component for
this whole authentication feature.
In here, I want to have a header
with a clause of row and spacing, which is a custom clause,
which, well, you guess it, adds some spacing so that
it doesn't sit directly on top of other elements.
And then, there, a nav with the well-known
col-md-8 column width here and the offset to centre it,
and then inside of this nav,
I want to have unordered list with nav nav-tabs.
Remember in the main header here, we used nav-pills,
which is a Bootstrap class to get this pills look here.
Now, I want to have this tabs look to give us multiple tabs.
And this is the CSS class I have to use,
again, provided by Bootstrap.
In there, it's time to set up some list items
with nested links, and I will get rid of the ref attribute,
because I will soon add a routerLink again.
Here, I want to have a tab for signing up,
for sign-in, and for logout of course.
So, what this should give me is, when I save this
and reload the auth page, we get the three tabs here.
Of course, they don't work,
and it doesn't look too beautiful
because we don't see anything else,
but that is what I'm going to work next
when I set up my routes and load them.
Now, you already know we need a place
to load them with the routerOutlet.
So, let's add another row here with some spacing,
and in here, add the router-outlet directive.
Now, you might say, "We already used router-outlet
"in the app component here.
"Now, I'm using it again in the authentication component.
"How does Angular2 know what to render where?"
It's very simple.
Routes set up in the app routing file in our root router
here will get loaded, on the highest possible level here,
will get loaded in the top-most routerOutlet,
which sits in our app component here, in the template
of our app component.
Nested routes, as I will create them in a second,
will be loaded in the component where I nested them.
But to make this a bit clearer,
let's start creating these routes so
that we can see what I mean.
I will create a new file
in the auth folder named auth.routes.ts.
Here, I will again create a constant named,
let's say, AUTH_ROUTES, which is of type Routes,
which needs to be imported from @angular/router.
This is an array of routes and you'll already notice
from the app routing file, this one here.
This array is the same.
So, in here, I again define some JavaScript objects,
setting up some nested routes,
but right now Angular2 doesn't know that
they are nested, of course.
I set them up in the same way as before.
The important thing about the path here is,
this path is now to be seen relative from /auth,
because I will soon set them up
to be child routes of the auth route.
So, all paths I enter now are auth/ and then this path.
So, here I want to have a signup path,
which in the end will be auth/signup,
because I will add it as a child route.
This is important to keep in mind.
So here, this will be the signup path,
and I want to load the signup component in this case,
which needs to be imported in this file.
I will duplicate this twice to also have a signin
and a logout route here where I have my signin component,
which needs to be imported at the top,
and my logout component which also needs to be imported.
These are my three child routes.
I also will set up a redirection here for the empty path,
which, again, is not really empty.
It's /auth/ nothing, in which case I don't want
to load a component, but let's say I want
to redirect to signup, and now here's important.
Not /signup, this would load localhost/signup,
which doesn't exist.
Instead, I want to append it to the currently active path,
which is /auth at this point, because /auth/ nothing.
And then I want to append /signup
to go to the second route here.
Of course, I also need to set up pathMatch full
to not get the not get the issue
of always getting redirected,
because there is always a empty path somewhere in the path.
So, these are my routes, and now you could think I
again use RouterModule and then forRoot.
But, this is actually not the case.
I don't to create a new routerModule, I already have one.
I want to add these routes to the existing routes
as child routes for this route.
Wow, that were a lot of routes.
To do so, I will simply export this constant here, export.
And then, in my main routing file, I want
to add them as child routes to this route,
so that Angular2 then knows they should be appended
to this path and loaded in this component,
which happens to be the component
where I have my routerOutlet.
To do this, I can add a new built-in
property named children.
This takes an array of routes and, guess what,
this is exactly what I set up in the auth.routes file,
an array of routes.
So, I can simply add AUTH_ROUTES, also at the import here,
as a value for this property,
and this registers these routes here
as child routes for my /auth path here.
And this is also the explanation why Angular2
will load them in my authentication component, here,
because this is simply the component
which gets loaded here, which now has the child routes.
Of course, the missing piece is to now hook up these links,
which is easy, again, with routerLink,
and then here an array where I want to navigate to signup.
Not /signup, because I don't want to go to localhost/signup.
I want to go to auth/signup.
If I now copy this to my other two links here,
signin and logout, and then also add
the routerLinkActive directive here
to style the active link like we did on our main header.
If I save this and then reload my application,
you now see the signup route is selected by default,
and if I switch you can see I can navigate
to all these routes.
The styling is, of course, off for a signup and signin
because I haven't added my Bootstrap grid classes,
but you see the routing works great.
I can still go to the messenger and back
to the authentication, where I now have these tabs
to be used, so that is great.
The missing part before we then finally start adding
some backend functionality is to set up the signup
and signin form, and for that, I'm going
to show you a different approach
of creating forms in Angular2.