Let's start with this Signup component here.
Here I will remove this h1 tag and instead add
my well-known Bootstrap classes here to centre it
and so on, you already know these.
And here I want to create a form.
Again, remove the action.
Angular 2.0 will handle this.
Right now Angular 2.0 will automatically again detect
this form and create one for me.
I could use this approach.
There's nothing wrong with that, but I want to show
the other approach, the data-driven approach
or reactive approach.
This approach means that we create the form ourselves
so this programmatic form, this JavaScript object,
we created ourselves and then we tell Angular
to assign it to this form.
So we would do it the other way around.
We don't let Angular 2.0 do it for us
and just auto-detect everything.
Instead we create it on our own and then tell Angular 2.0,
"Don't detect it, use our form."
Well, before doing so, still we have to create it
here in HTML because we want it to display
something to the user.
So we should create a form group here
in which we have a label for let's say
the first name of the user.
First name because when a user registers,
remember we have these fields.
We have first name, last name, password, and email
so we should fetch them in the form.
So back in the form let's add the input
for the ID firstName with a class of form-control,
Bootstrap class again to give it some nice styling.
I don't need to add the name attribute
because we're going to do this differently
with this new approach I'm showing you.
And with that I can simply duplicate this three times
to also set up the last name here, lastName.
And then here we want to have the mail address
so let's name this email.
Could also be of type email, but that's optional.
And then here we want to have the password.
Let's also name this password here
and it should be of type password of course.
This is my Signup form and I also want
to be able to submit it so let's add a button,
button primary.
Whoops, primary with type of submit
and then submit as the text.
This is the HTML form as before,
but now I want to create it programmatically
and not let Angular 2.0 detect it here.
Creating it programmatically might sound difficult,
but it is not.
It is really easy actually.
First, I will create a property.
Let's name it myForm, but you may chose any name you want.
This will hold the form we create.
It will be of type FormGroup.
This needs to be imported from @angular/forms.
So a form in Angular 2.0 is simply just a group
of basically controls in a form.
Next, we could use two different approaches
to create the form.
We can create it with all the individual elements
or we could use a tool named Form Builder.
I will use the first approach and create
all controls by myself.
It's not really that different from Form Builder,
just a little bit more explicit and that's why I chose it.
You may of course look up some Angular 2.0 courses
or tutorials to also learn about the Form Builder.
Therefore, I want to implement the OnInit hook here
to create this form.
Again, this is a great place to do so
because it's a bit of a more heavy thing
and I don't want to do that in the constructor.
Don't forget to import OnInit here at the top
and then implement the ngOnInit method
such that when this component is created,
the form is created as well.
So here I will assign this myForm and now I want
to create myForm.
So myForm is a FormGroup so let's create
a new FormGroup like that.
This FormGroup takes a JavaScript object,
which describes it and here we register our controls.
Remember before the template-driven approach
when it printed the form to the console?
It had tonnes of fields and all these fields
are still created and managed by Angular 2.0 automatically.
All I have to do myself here is tell it
which controls does my form have.
So this is exactly what I'm passing here,
an object containing my controls where the key
is always the name of the control and the value
is how I configured the control.
So I will have a firstName control for example
and the value will be a new FormControl now.
This also needs to be imported from @angular/forms.
And here, as you can see, we can pass multiple arguments.
The first one is the initial state, so basically
the value with which this control is initialised.
We could display some default value,
but I will keep this to an empty string
so that the input is empty at the beginning.
We could also pass null here.
Then, you can attach validators you want to use.
Remember in the template-driven approach
here in the message input component,
I added this required thing to tell Angular 2.0
that this should not be empty.
We can do the same here.
I can add Validators to use the built-in collection
of validators and all this is imported from @angular/forms
and then required and now this field is required
and may not be empty anymore.
With that I set up my first control.
Now I'm copying this to also set up my lastName here.
I'll copy one more time to set up my email
and one more time to set up my password.
Now of course you could also add additional validators
and I will do this for the email.
Here I want to validate that it actually
is a valid email address, but I also
want to make sure it's not empty
so I want to add two validators.
Now you don't add them as multiple arguments like this.
Instead you will simply add an array of validators
as the second argument now.
So the first validator I want to use
is the required validator and that's important
again for the other validators up her too.
Don't execute it, don't add parenthesis.
It should only be a reference to the function,
which Angular 2.0 will execute when it checks
the validity of this control.
And the second validator is also built in one,
which is the pattern validator.
Here I do execute it and pass an argument
and this argument should be a string
containing a regular expression describing the pattern
this input should match.
So here I clearly want to match it to a valid email address
and I copied this regular expression.
You may chose any regular expression that fits your needs.
It's not really a regular expression of course.
It looks very complicated.
In the end, this should make sure
that we enter a valid email address.
Though I will say right away, I chose a decently short one.
It doesn't cover all cases.
There are better email validators out there,
which are just very, very long
and which I didn't want to use here.
So with that I'm now applying these two validators
to my email control and both functions will be executed
whenever Angular 2.0 checks the validity of this control,
which it does upon every keystroke.
So this creates my own form and that is all.
The remaining step is I need to tell Angular 2.0,
"Please use this form in this HTML code
"and don't use the one you created automatically."
Doing so is also very easy.
On the form itself, I pass a directive
which uses property defining formGroup.
Here I point to the form I want to use, myForm,
and this tells Angular 2.0, "Don't use your own form,
"use mine and use this one specifically."
I also set up ngSubmit now to call onSubmit
whenever we submit the form.
Note I don't need to pass the form as an argument here.
I already do have access in my class here.
So here if I enter or if I add onSubmit,
I can already console.log
because I registered it here as a property in my class.
This is one of the advantages of the data-driven approach.
I do have very easy access to it.
I can fine tune it when I create it and much more.
So this sets up the overall form,
but I still need to tell Angular 2.0
which input here refers to which control in myForm.
It doesn't try to match this automatically
because you might use different names here
than you use here or in my case,
I didn't set up the name attribute at all.
So in order to tell Angular 2.0 which input
belongs to which control here, I simply add
another directive here, formControlName,
and set this equal to the control name
you set up in your object.
So here I use firstName as a control name.
Therefore, since I want to match this input
with this control, I pass firstName here.
Notice we don't use property binding here
because this is not a directive or a property
where we pass a value in.
It's a directive which Angular 2.0 analyses
when analysing this whole form and then it simply takes
the value of this quotation here as a control name to match.
This is all.
This synchronises this input with this control.
Now I'm going to quickly repeat this
for all the other inputs here to also match them.
Done.
So I added the formControlName directive
to all inputs and matched them with the controls
in my custom created form here.
Now in order to make this work, I need to change
one thing in my app module.
For a template-driven approach, in two-way binding
I needed to add FormsModule.
For this new approach, the reactive forms approach,
I need to add ReactiveFormsModule here.
So make sure to add this and to also add the import
from @angular/forms.
With this, if I now saved this
and then reload the application
and go to Signup, you see this new form.
Now let's see what gets logged to the console
if I enter something here.
Notice that it is red if I don't fill in
a valid email address and now hit Submit.
You see I now logged my FormGroup,
which has the same fields as before
which has a value which now has my key value pairs
I set up programmatically.
This is how you use the data-driven or reactive approach,
which gives you more control over your form
and allows you to create it in code.
You can now even fine tune this a bit more.
Go back to the Signup component here
and let's say I want to disable this button
as long as the whole form is not valid.
So I can simply add a property binding
to the disabled on property off this button element
and I want to disable it as long
as myForm.valid is not true.
Valid is one of the fields Angular 2.0 manages for us
where it takes the validity of all inputs together
and only turns it to true if all inputs are valid.
So with this, if I reload this application or this page,
you see the button is now not clickable.
I have to fill in valid values into all fields
and now it becomes clickable again
and as soon as I make one field invalid, it isn't.
This is how I can set up this form.
As a final step, I simply want to add a functionality
to reset the form whenever I do submit it.
So here I will call this.myForm.reset like this.
So to showcase this a last time,
if I now enter something here and hit Submit,
it is reset thereafter and with that,
we've got the Signup form finished.