We're almost there.
I will now copy all that code here,
in my
class body
to my signin component,
since it will also use this approach of creating a form.
Of course, you should then also
copy all these form-related imports here
into the signin component,
so that this is all enabled again.
And, of course, we also need to synchronise this.
So I'm simply copying
the template of the signup form,
though here I only need email and passwords.
So, I will remove the inputs
for first and last name,
and then of course all that means
that in my signin component TypeScript class,
I will remove these controls here too.
So now I do have a lighter version
of the signup form here in the signin component,
which means that if I reload the application
I now get the signin component here.
Still has the same functionality as before,
but now only for mail and password.
With this we got our application
or frontend almost finished.
We've got our authentication section here
with Signup, Signin, and Logout,
which we can switch with child routing.
Get our Messenger, where we can
add new routes.
The one thing I want to fix, or add now
before moving on to the next module,
where you've finally connected to Node.js;
so bring these two pieces together,
is these two buttons.
Deleting doesn't work,
and reloads it actually.
And the same is true for editing,
which does work,
though it only replaces it with some static text,
but then also reloads the page.
I will leave the static text for editing,
but I want to hook up the delete button,
and I also want to remove this unnecessary reloading,
or this annoying reloading.
Back in the message-component.html file,
the reloading is triggered by these references here.
Because now with routing in place,
this simply triggers a reload.
So by removing it, I get rid of this annoying feature,
or function.
I also want to hook up the delete button.
So let's execute onDelete here.
Of course, this new method should now be added here.
And remember, we already do have the delete method
in the messages-service here.
So therefore, I can simply
inject this messageService here too,
in the message component.
So messageService should get injected here too.
Make sure to add the import at the top here.
And with this message now available,
note is it's the same instance
as in the input and list component,
since I provided in this messages component
which holds them all.
So since it is the same instance,
I can simply call this.messageService.deleteMessage,
and here, I pass this.message.
So the message which I get
passed into this component from outside;
which is the currently loaded one.
So, with that,
if I reload my application again
and add a new message,
you see editing doesn't reload,
and deleting, well, deletes it.
This is the finished front end.
Now let's move on to the Node.js section
and add the backend so that the messages
are stored on the server,
are really edited,
and are really fetched
from the server.
So, time to move on.