In this course, and in probably any real application,
we not only want to send data to the server
to then do nothing there.
We want to store it in a database,
we want to be able to retrieve it from a database.
As a database, in this course we will use MongoDB,
which is a very popular choice for Angular2
and Node.js as applications.
You're not limited to MongoDB,
you may chose any database of your choice, or preference.
But again, in this course, I will go with MongoDB.
Now for developing, we will all need to set it up
on our local machines so that we can test it
and work with it.
How do we set it up?
Well, first we need to download MongoDB and extract it.
And then we also need to move a folder.
I will walk you though these steps.
Thereafter, we need to launch our MongoDB server.
This is important to be able to
perform database operations and here it's always important
to then keep this server running because you will only
be able to connect to it and to perform database operations
if the server is running.
So if you throughout the course,
gets some error when starting your node server,
and the errors says something about MongoDB,
maybe your MongoDB server is not running,
and therefore Node.js is not able to connect to it.
Finally, we also need to launch a client.
So we have the MongoDB server,
to be able to, well, interact with it.
But the client is where we issue commands like,
save something, get something.
We got a shelled client installed with MongoDB,
when we do instal it,
but we also typically will not use that,
most of the time the client will be
our Node.js application connecting to the server.
In this module, I will walk you through all these steps,
setting up MongoDB, setting up Node.js to use it,
and then how to interact with MongoDB.
So let's get started with the set up in the next video.