You wanna head over to mongodb.com
which is the official webpage of MongoDB.
And here, download is the link we wanna use.
Now on the download centre, make sure
to use the right version, which would be
the community server for the testing purposes here.
Then your operating system, and then the version
you wanna use, the default version should be fine.
Thereafter, you may download this
and depending on your operating system,
you can also follow through the
installation instructions here to understand
how to use that download.
On Windows, it should be installer.
On OS X it stays package.
So let's simply download it here.
You don't need to register there,
it will start automatically.
And after this download finished, I'll be back.
I'm in the downloads folder where I downloaded this.
On any operating system you should be able
to double-click on it, and on Windows
it should start an installer.
In Mac it will give you this folder.
Now this folder already has everything you need
in the bin folder, you have multiple executables
you can run through the terminal.
I will show you how to do that in a second.
Which allow you to start your Mongo server
with this executable or your client
with this executable.
You may now move this whole folder
and rename to any place on your machine
where you wanna store it and where you
later on also wanna access it.
Now to successfully set up your environment
to use MongoDB, then make sure to
go to this quick start guide.
It should automatically redirect
to the one for your operating system.
You may choose the right version
otherwise here on the left.
And make sure to follow these steps here.
Now we already did instal it.
The important part for us is to now
configure it correctly.
You may add this path variable here,
but you don't need to do that.
I will show you how to use without this
extra step here.
But important is that you create
this data directory here.
So make sure to definitely follow
this step here to set up this directory
which will be the directory holding
the actual data later on.
The directory we downloaded holds the
server and the code we need to
execute our server, but in this data directory
which should create with these easy steps here,
the data will be stored thereafter.
So make sure to execute the steps
one and two there regarding running MongoDB.
I'll come back to this in the next video.