We installed MongoDB
in the last video, and make sure
you also set up your data directory
as described in the official docs.
After doing that, on Mac on Linux,
navigate into this MongoDB folder
you downloaded, extracted, and then moved
somewhere in the terminal.
On Windows you may just go there
in the Windows explorer.
Then in this folder, you should have
this bin folder or directly in
the MongoDB folder which was installed
through the Windows Installer,
you should have executables named
Mongo D and Mongo, for example.
On Mac and Linux, you have to go into
the bin folder in MongoDB, in the MongoDB
folder to get there, and then we're running
dot slash mongod, you will start
the MongoDB server.
This starts the server and keep it running,
don't close it as long as you're
working on your project because
if you close it, you're of course
not able to access it anymore,
and any tries if you exit it will
crash your application.
So just keep MongoDB running, and if you've got
any problems running this, head back
to the official documentation.
This quick start guide is really great,
and it should give you detailed instructions
for your operating system on how to
set it up correctly and run it
both on Windows, as described here,
or OS X, as I already showed you
here in this video.
Now with that server running,
we're able to work with it and to
write some data to it.