Before connecting Node.js, I want to show you
the other thing which was installed with MongoDB.
I'll open up a new terminal and note,
keep the server running,
and I'll also navigate into the bin folder,
or on Windows again choose the right executable,
the name is just Mongo,
so ./mongo when executed from the command line,
simply clicking on mongo.exe on Window,
on Windows
Mongo, not mongod, that was the server,
mongo is now the client, the shell client to be precise.
This is a client which allows us to connect
to our MongoDB server through the terminal.
We will rarely do this,
most of the time Node.js will do that for us,
but from time to time you will see me jump
into the shell client to have a look at the data
in the database and get a quick view of what's stored there.
The general usage is that you can type use
and then the name of your database
to access a specific database,
you may have multiple databases on your Mongo server.
The one I'll use through this course is called node-angular,
I'll also set this up in my Node.js application later on.
So we've used node-angular inside of this
and then with show collections you can show all collections,
MongoDB don't has tables, it has collections of data,
you have, you see I already have two collections,
it's probably empty for you,
I do have them because I already worked with it.
You can then access a collection by typing db, for database,
the currently selected one, then the name of the collection,
for example messages,
and then find, like a method here,
to show all messages in there.
Again, this probably won't work for you,
but you will see me do this throughout the course
so I want to show it right now.
This is the general usage,
and that is all I'm interested in right now.
I won't dive super deep into that
because you will learn it through the course.
We will use MongoDB a lot there
and you will learn how we can access it
and how we can work with the data.
Not something I want to do in the shell here,
just wanted to introduce the shell
so that you are aware of how to start and use it
if you see me use it throughout this course.