So we got our MongoDB server set up,
and we could work with just MongoDB and Node.js.
MongoDB ships its own client we can use in Node.js.
Remember a client is what connects
to the MongoDB server so we could
download the Mongo Node client from the
Mongo webpage and get started with that,
but if you were to use this client,
we would have to write all the excess
and all the query logic on our own.
We also wouldn't have features like
using models against which we could verify some data
or something like that.
So what we will use is a different client
not the default one.
The one I'll use is called Mongoose.
Mongoose is more than just a Mongo client.
It is a package which also allows us
to define schemas, models.
So for example, a user should have
a first name which is a string,
a last name which is a string.
You can set up such a configuration,
and then you can use this schemas blueprint
to create objects based on that model
and directly on this object you created,
you can then execute database methods
like save or delete so you don't have
to write the queries on your own.
You also get this extra validation
if the data you create actually fits
the model you set up, and this is
why Mongoose is so great.