So back in our Node.js application,
or in our project here, I wanna instal Mongoose.
It's a third-party package, and we would have to
instal the default MongoDB driver,
too, if you wanted to use that,
but I want to use Mongoose, so what I will need
to instal is the Mongoose package.
I do this by running npm instal,
and then, minus minus save to save it
as a production dependency in the package.json file
to create an entry there.
Whoops, Mongoose is the name.
This will pull down Mongoose, and instal it
in our project so that we can use it.
With the installation finished here,
again, ignore any warnings you might get,
with that finished, you see in the package.json,
Mongoose was added here.
So now, we're good to use Mongoose.
How do we use it, then?
The first step is, we need to connect our app to Mongoose.
We do this in the app.js files,
so in every request, we wanna connect to the database.
Here, I will create a new variable named mongoose,
and that will require the Mongoose package.
So I'm basically pointing to this
Mongoose package we just installed.
Now, in order to connect to it on each request,
I can now execute mongoose.connect, like this.
With this connect function, we will establish a connexion,
but of course, we need to tell it
where the Mongoose server lives.
We do so by specifying the path here.
Now, the path is something we can figure out
by having a look at our running Mongo server.
When starting it up, you see some general
information about the path up here.
You see that the port is 27017.
And the path instance that is running on our machine,
localhost, so the domain is localhost.
So here, we connect to localhost 27017,
and then, you add a slash and the name
of the database you wanna use.
You can add a database you haven't created yet,
because it will be created for you on the fly.
So, node-angular is the one I will use
throughout this project, and you may specify it like this.
It should work.
With that, we're connecting to our MongoDB server
through our Node.js application using this Mongoose package.
Now, Mongoose is there for more than just connecting us,
you will learn, but this is the first basic step
to later be able to actually perform database operations.