Now I already explained that one
of the biggest advantages of mongoose is the fact
that we can create models.
And we can use these models to create objects based
on them in our code,
and we can then use these objects
to directly access the database,
and behind the scenes mongoose will create
the appropriate collections for our models
and manage our data there.
So we don't have to write our queries.
We can use this very intuitive database access
of using our data in the Node.js code
in the Chalice script code.
And calling functions like save
to also save a copy to the database.
You will see this is very intuitive.
And I will create two models which we will use
throughout this course because in this course,
which kind of application are we going to build?
We're going to build application where we have messages
and users who can create messages,
who can sign up, sign in.
So we wanna be able store both messages and users,
so I will create a message and a user model.
For that I'll create a new folder
in the root project folder which I'll name models.
This is a service side folder too.
Angular 2 doesn't care about our models here,
but our back-it does.
In there, I will create a new file, message.js
which will later on hold my message model.
I'll also create a second file, user.js
for, you guessed it, the user model.
How do we create such a model with mongoose?
Let's start with the message model.
The first step is to import mongoose in this file too
because just because we import it in the app js file here,
here,
doesn't mean that it is available in our files too.
We need to import it into every file where we want
to use it.
So with that I got access to mongoose.
And then I will create another variable
which I'll call Schema.
This will use this mongoose package I just imported,
and use the Schema object in there.
Schema is basically a helper object
which allows me to create the blueprint of my models.
With this schema, I can now create a new schema
with a lower case S.
This will be my own schema I set up
for the message model which I'll use,
and I can create a new Schema with a new keyword
and this Schema object I imported or I fetched
from my mongoose package up here.
Now this schema constructor here expects
to get a Chalice script object as an argument,
and in this object, we define how our user model,
excuse me, our message model, should look like.
What could our message look like?
I want to keep it simple, so the message should have
a content and it should hold a reference
to the user who created the message.
So we're going to have two fields, content and user.
Now here they keys are the names of these fields,
or the names of our properties,
and these will be stored in the Mongo Database
as field names too.
As a value, I pass and shelve the script object,
defining how this field should look like,
how it is configured.
So the content, lets say, should be of type String.
Type is a property mongoose understands
to define which type of value should be stored
in this field.
And I will add another key mongoose understands, required.
Required set to true basically means
this field may never be empty.
We should always have a content.
Now for the user, I will set this to another type.
The type here is Schema.Types
to access all the types mongoose knows,
and then ObjectId.
We can't use just ObjectId.
The shortcut works for string but not for this Id
or for this type.
What is the ObjectId type?
This is basically the internal type mongoose uses
to store the Ids of the different objects we store
in the database.
Each object we store automatically gets an Id,
even though we don't set up an Id field here in our schema.
And this Id automatically created by mongoose
and stored in the database is of type ObjectId.
Behind the scenes or in the end,
it's a string, but it is managed differently,
since it is also created on its own.
So this is kind of an internal thing mongoose does for us.
I also want to set up something else,
but I'll come back to this after creating this user Schema.
Now we have the blueprint, but we want the model.
We can't instantiate this blueprint.
We can't create a new message based on that blueprint.
We need a model to do so.
So what I now do is I want to export something
in this file with module.exports
and this something is the actual model,
for that I'll use mongoose.
And then the model method.
This method expects two arguments,
the first one, the name of this model,
I'll name it message.
We will then be able to create a new message
with new Message later on, just like that.
So this is what this message here does.
It also determines the name of the collection
mongoose will create automatically for us in the database.
Mongoose will always take this name we define here
and use it as a collection name
but lowercase and in a plural form, so messages.
So this collection will be created automatically
for us as soon as we start writing data to the database.
And the second argument we need to pass here of course
is the schema we want to use for this model.
With that our message model is set up.
Let's work on the user model next.
I will copy the code from the message models,
since a lot of it is equal.
Of course the fields will very.
How should a user look like?
Let's say a user should have a first name and a last name,
a password, and probably an email.
And we also want to have some messages.
Remember on the message schema we had the user reference?
On the user schema, we want to have this messages reference.
Message yes because one user might have multiple messages,
whereas each message can only be created by one user.
This is why the fields are named differently.
So let's start setting them up.
First name should be of type String
and should be required.
We will get validation errors or errors
if we try to write data to the database
which doesn't satisfy these conditions as a side note.
The last name should have the same setup,
so shall have the password.
We don't need to set up anything special for the password.
In the end it will be stored as a string,
and it should be required.
We'll worry about encryption
in later stages of the course.
Now the email is different.
It is of type string.
It is required, but I also want it to be unique,
so let's pass unique.
Now, unique even though it is a property recognised
by mongoose, it's not validated automatically.
So unique can be set up here, but we would still be able
to pass multiple times this key
or this email to the database without getting an error.
To prevent this I'll add in our package
instal it with npm install--save,
and then mongoose-unique-validator
is the name of the package we wanna use.
This third-party package now allows us
to make sure that we get this extra validation,
however in order to get it, we need to take our schema
and use the plugin method which mongoose offers us.
This allows us to add a new plug into the schema,
and the plugin I wanna use is the mongooseUniqueValidator.
So let's also import it, mongooseUniqueValidator,
choose any name you want.
Validator, like this.
And of course I need to require
the mongoose-unique-validator here.
With that I can simply pass it here as an argument
to the plugin.
And now, remove the parenthesis here though.
They will be passed to reference.
With that we got the extra validation
if fields marked as unique are indeed unique
in the database.
Back to the configuration, we're still missing
the messages here.
Messages first of all is an array.
We indicate this with square brackets
telling mongoose that this is an array,
that these are multiple messages.
Then we set up the type.
Here again the type is Schema.Types.ObjectId
Remember messages will only be an array
of strings in the end, an array of Ids.
But with ObjectId we're taking care
that mongoose works with it correctly
as it handles these Ids automatically
in the background for us.
We're almost done.
Missing piece of course is to rename this to User down here,
so this model should be named User.
Again as with message this will automatically create
a collection named users.
And we haven't really told mongoose
that messages here refers to this message model,
and user here refers to this user model.
We told it that this will actually hold some Id,
and it's obviously not the Id of the user model itself here
in the user schema because that will be stored
in a separate field.
But we haven't told mongoose the Id of what will be stored
in this messages array then.
We do so by adding another configuration property here,
ref.
Ref tells mongoose this field here has a connexion
or holds a connexion to another model you know
or I created here.
We then pass as a string the name of this model, Message
since I want to refer to this message model,
and therefore here in the message model
or the message schema I should say,
we also set up a ref pointing to user, so to our user model.
Now behind the scenes mongoose is aware of this connexion
and is able to perform some nice operations here
we'll see throughout this course
when we want to access this relation and want to use it.