In the last lecture, we set up our Mongoose models.
Time to use them and to really understand what Mongoose does
behind the scenes.
So we got a message in the user model,
and we already got this node HBS view, where we are able
to submit a message.
I'll change this to email because I want to create
a user model as it is to a more complex one,
and I changed the name to email here too,
for the input field.
I would get rid of this message output up here,
don't need it anymore.
And for now, this will be the view I'm able to submit.
Now in my app.js file, I will update this message here
to no longer get a message in the URL and to no longer
pass one to the view
because I don't output it there anymore.
To be precise, I can also get rid of this route,
simply use my root route and render node here,
so that we don't have to type /message all the time.
So this is my get route, loading this node HBS view.
Now when we hit submit there,
we wanna submit to just "slash", let's say,
so here, I would also update this action to just
target/ there for reaching this /post route here.
And then here, I want to create a new email first,
or extract the email from the request,
so I will start the variable and we can extract it
on this request body, as we learned before,
because this is how we submit it.
It is stored in the input field named email,
and therefore we can access this email property
on the body of our request.
With that, I wanna store it in the new user model
or a new user object based on our user model.
To do so, I first need to add an import,
the import to the user model we created.
So here, I'll point to my models folder,
and then the user file.
Without the file extension,
this will be added automatically.
We don't need to specify .js there, it actually would lead
to an error if we did so.
This will import the user model since we do exported here.
With that, we got access to this user model,
and I can now call new user using this variable,
which uses this exported user model.
Now, of course, if I were to store this
in a var other than users, I would have to call
new users here, but user makes more sense
because it is onc user we create.
Now to the constructor, we pass a java script object,
where we configure this model we want to create,
or where we configure this object we want to create
based on this model, I should say.
So here, we know that we will have a first name
because this is how we set it up here, we get a first name,
a last name, a password, and an email and the messages,
of course, but these aren't required, so I don't have
to pass them, and I won't here because we don't have
any messages yet, we will do so later in the course, though.
So here, I got the first name.
I'll set it to Max because this is my name.
Choose whatever name you like.
I get the last name, I'll set it Schwartz,
part of my last name.
And I get a password, we're not encrypting it here.
We will do so later in the course, of course,
but for now, I'll name it whereas store super-secret
as a password, which obviously isn't.
And then the email should be the email I extract
from the request body, of course, I could've extracted it
right here, just want to make this
as structured as possible.
With this, I created my user here, an object based
on my model, and I passed my data to this user object
to, well, set it up as the model requires me to set it up.
Now comes the part which I mentioned earlier.
It's super easy to now save this to the database.
All we have to do is run it user save, that's all.
This will tell Mongoose to store this user object
in the user's collection, it will create a collection
automatically if we don't have it yet in the database.
In which database?
In the one we configured here in our root app.js file.
We can pass a callback here, which is executed
after this saving has been done where we can listen
for errors because as arguments, Mongoose will give us
an error or the result of this operation,
and we will use this callback throughout the course
to handle errors.
For now let's keep it simple and just call save.
Now in the end, of course, we want to redirect
to just "slash" and no longer append a message here
because that won't work anymore.
With that, let's restart the server because we changed
a lot of service that cued,
and let's head over to the application,
at localhost3000 now.
I'll store a database or an email to the database
by entering it here and hitting submit,
and now, did it work?
We can't tell because we're not fetching it yet,
we only stored something there.
Well, I showed you earlier how we can tell.
Let's go back to terminal and start this mongo client
on Windows without the terminal simply executable,
and in there, we should use node angular
since this is the database we used.
And then we got some collections, you saw that earlier,
we can access the user collection by typing db.users
and then find will show us all the users in this collection
and here we indeed see this new user as a single object
Max Schwarz super-secret and email,
this looks really like the user we just created and it is.
You see, the messages are always empty
because we didn't pass one, and you see it has this
underscore id field, which we didn't create,
which Mongoose creates automatically.
I mentioned this earlier.
Mongoose does this 4S, and it uses this object id type here,
though in the database in the end, this will be just
a string, so we see it a bit different here.
It's a special kind of string, so to say, holding the idea
off this object, this unit idea, of course.
This is how we can store data in the database,
and I think this is really convenient,
and this is the reason why I use Mongoose
because it's so easy to set this up and to get validation
to see if this is right and to store data in the database.
Now in next lecture, let's all go fetch some data.