In last lecture, we saved data to the database.
Time to now get it back and show in our review.
To do so, I'll go to the get route,
which is the route rendering our page,
and here, I now wanna access my database and get something.
Now, when we created a user, we created a new user
with the new user command here with the constructor.
How do we retrieve data from the database?
It's very simple.
We use this user variable we created
up here, which holds our user model,
and on this model, we can directly perform a couple
of actions, and you can check out the mongoose documentation
for a full list of available actions.
You will see a lot throughout this course, though.
One of them is find one to, as the name suggests,
give us back one result, the first one typically.
We can also pass, where we have to pass an argument
to define which result you want to get back,
but if I pass an empty object, it will simply give me
the first one in the database.
Then, the important part comes.
We specify a callback here.
This is important.
We do not get the user by calling user find one
and storing it in a variable
because this is a asynchronous task.
This will reach out to the database,
and it may take a couple of seconds, so it will call
this callback we pass as a second argument, once it is done.
This callback will then, by mongoose,
receive either the error, this can be null
if no error occurred, otherwise we do have an error
in this error variable here in this argument,
or the document it retrieved.
You may rename these arguments to whatever you like.
I'll keep the two names I chose here.
So we can now check if we got an error during the retrieval,
in which case we could send
a response where it will simply send some text,
not even render a view for this case here,
simply say error here.
If we haven't got an error, and important,
have the return keyword here, otherwise code execution,
would continue even though you already sent the response.
This is not what you want.
So if we don't get into the if block,
if we don't have an error, then I want to render my response
only once we are finished.
So not outside of this callback, this is important,
we would render the view before this task here finished
to do it inside of the callback.
Here, I wanna render my node, HBS file,
and pass an argument email, which holds my document,
so this email we created or we fetched here.
With that, let's return to node HBS,
and here I wanna output this email,
so again, with double curly braces to use handle bars,
we can output email, and again, this is just a name
I set up as the name for this property here,
and this should give us this single email.
Now, let's restart the server
since we made some changes here,
and then reload this page.
Looks good, we're fetching the full object here,
though I only wanted to get the email.
So in order to do that, I can access doc,
and then simply email, since this is the name of this field
since you configured it to be like this in this user model,
or in this schema for the model, to be precise.
With that, if I restart the server again and reload again,
now we're only outputting the email we created
and this is how we can access it in the database.
This is generally how we can fetch data
from the database, key takeaway here:
use any method to fetch data directly on the model,
and then use it in this callback,
including the rendering of responses.
If you execute any code outside of this callback here,
you won't have access to the data fetched
because it is not there yet.
This is important to understand here,
and, as all the other things, you will see this a lot
throughout this course.