In one of the last lectures,
you saw me encode data in the URL
and send data with a post request.
Let's better understand which ways
of accessing data we have, and we will
use them all throughout this course.
On the request, we typically have
a header and a content type,
and the same is true for the response.
We've also got a body, which might hold our data.
Now, on a request, we might access
a URL, which looks like this.
Let's have a look at what we do have
inside of this data, or how we can
attach some data to that request.
Well, what we don't see in the URL is,
with a post request, for example,
we can store data in the body,
which is also part of the request.
The body is not visible in the URL,
but is something which is sent behind the scenes.
And we already retrieved data from the body
in the post request we handled two lectures ago.
We also got things we can see in the URL,
like the request params here.
Remember we already also used params
to retrieve data from the URL.
And then we get this part which we haven't seen yet,
after the question mark here.
This is the request query,
or the so-called query parameters.
We can attach them to any request.
They always come in the end, and the difference
to the request params is, they're not encoded
in a specific place in the URL,
so, five here, if that were some ID,
could only go after /user, because
we hard-encoded with this colon in the URL.
Question mark anything equals anything
always comes on the end, and allows us
to pass some additional data, kind of
optional data, to each request.
In this course, you will see when we use that
and how we use it to extract some data
which might be present, but we're not sure if it is,
and which also should be attached
to multiple requests, and therefore,
isn't hard-coded into the URL.
Regarding data formats we can use,
the typical format we will use in this course is JSON.
JSON is a very lightweight format.
It's basically a JavaScript object
as a string, if you wanna put it like that,
and therefore, it's able to encode
a lot of data with a very little
amount of characters, keeping it small.
And, since we used Node.js anyway,
it's easy to be parsed.
We used JavaScript objects all over the place,
so why not send our data as one?
You could also send plain text, or a file,
or, of course, URL encoded data,
And for example of you, HTML code.
But we won't do this in a Angular 2 and Node.js
application, here we will stick to JSON
to exchange data behind the scenes
because always keep that in mind,
we will never send a request and
get back a response which leads to
a reload of the page.
We won't send HTML code from the server
besides that initial loading of our index hps file.